Chapter 807: Entering the Valley

After hearing the Ghost Spirit Sect Master mention the ancient teleportation formations, a few cultivators rejoiced at his words while others remained skeptical. After all, few truly knew of the internal situation of Devilfall Valley.

“To put everyone’s hearts at ease, I will have Quanzi and Elder Zhong go across first. We will have everyone else cross afterwards.” Wang Tiansheng finished, and waved his arm towards Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan.

The silver-masked Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan walked towards the center of the spell formation and stood next to the mid Nascent Soul old man.

Soon after Wang Tiansheng gave the command, the cultivators simultaneously pointed the flags down, shooting an arm-thick rainbow beam of light towards various points of the spell formation. Suddenly, the entire spell formation began to hum and the spirit stones around it began to brightly shine.

This scene stirred the nearby cultivators, but Wang Tiansheng paid them little notice. Wang Tiangu then brought eight Core Formation cultivators with him towards the spell formation.

In that moment, the other cultivators clearly saw that while the spell formation may appear enormous, it seemed to only be able to teleport three people at a time. As a result, the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators had to be teleported in batches.

Seeing that the Ghost Spirit Sect had rushed to take the first step, the other cultivators grew tempted to follow them. However, cultivators were often cunning and cautious. For a time, no one dared to step forward and clearly wished to see others make an attempt first. After all, the Ghost Spirit Sect’s reputation wasn’t very great and the slightest mistake could lead to certain death.

Han Li stood up on the mound, taking in a better view of the scene.

Wang Tiansheng coldly laughed upon seeing the cultivators responses and he raised his arms towards the sky. The sky above him began to stir and the valley’s surroundings gradually became quieter.

Despite the awkward atmosphere, the Moulan began to move. Over ten Moulan spell warriors silently walked towards the huge formation behind the scholarly man surnamed Zhong and the woman surnamed Le.

A trace of black Qi flickered across Wang Tiansheng’s face after seeing this, but soon disappeared. As for the taciturn Wei Wuya, he calmly faced Elder Zhong and looked at him.

Before the Moulan spell warriors made their way into the spell formation, Elder Zhong flung his sleeve, shooting over ten streaks of azure light from his sleeve into the sky.

Wang Tiansheng then expressionlessly waved his hand and caught the lights, only to reveal tensome medallions.

Although Wang Tiansheng didn’t participate in the battle at the border, he already knew of the Divine Sage’s identity. As such, he took a breath and slowly said, “Good. The quantity will suffice. Please go in.”

Elder Zhongn nodded and several spell warriors moved from behind him, entering the spell formation. Suddenly, the Ghost Spirit Sect disciples floating in the air activated the formation and sent the Moulan into the valley in groups of three.

When Elder Zhong walked into the spell formation, he glanced at Wei Wuya and casually said, “If the target location of this transportation formation is random, then it’d be best if your sect’s disciples don’t encounter us.”

Showing no fear, Wei Wuya faced the Moulan Divine Sage and replied, “How could something so convenient happen in this world? If something like that truly happens, it can only be by the wills of the Heavens.”

“The will of Heavens? Hehe, then so be it!” Divine Sage Zhong coldly chuckled and disappeared with white light alongside two of his juniors.

After that was said, Wang Tiansheng glanced at the empty spell formation with a trace of a scowl.

When the others saw that the Moulan were able to safely use the transportation formation, they couldn’t help but lose their composure. Many cultivators began to take out their Devilfall Medallions and walk towards the transportation formation.

Over the span of a few minutes, the transportation formation flickered with light many times, sending over three hundred people into Devilfall Valley, about a fourth of the total number of Devilfall Medallions. As for the high-grade spirit stone at the spell formation’s center, it had already begun to dim; its spiritual power appeared nearly exhausted.

Han Li indifferently watched all of this as he stood on top of the mound and made note of all the cultivators who entered the valley.

Suddenly, Han Li’s gaze shifted to six green-robed cultivators that approached the spell formation. The one leading them was the Controlling Spirit Sect’s Grand Elder, Dongmen Tu. Han Li didn’t have a particularly good impression of. Although they had never engaged each other in a direct confrontation, Han Li felt that he should be careful around this person considering his involvement in dealing with the Moulan spy, Gu Shuangpu. But with his vastly powerful abilities, Han Li didn’t need to pay too much attention to him.

At that moment, the five green-robed cultivators escorting Dongmen Tu simultaneously turned their heads in the direction of Han Li. At the same time, Han Li’s assimilated second Nascent Soul suddenly began to intensely stir. Were it not for Han Li’s quick reaction to immediately concentrate and forcefully dominate it with his spiritual sense, he feared it would’ve manifested on its own.

At that same moment, Han Li used his spiritual sense to carefully observe the five green-robed cultivators. “Elemental Spirit Nascents!” These early Nascent Soul cultivators gave off a strange impression similar to his second Nascent Soul. As a result, he couldn’t help but squint at them, not knowing where they came from.

Of course, Dongmen Tu also noticed his escorts acting strangely and he hurriedly turned his gaze to Han Li, happening to exchange glances with him.

A trace of astonishment appeared on Dongmen Tu’s face, but he soon turned his head around as if nothing had happened and walked into the spell formation. As for Wang Tiangu, he appeared greatly shocked upon seeing that Dongmen Tu was being accompanied by five other Nascent Soul cultivators.

As for Wei Wuya, he closely examined several of the green-robed cultivators and wore a pensive expression.

Staring at these five cultivators, Wang Tiansheng asked with a deep tone, “Brother Dongmen, these Fellow Daoists are quite unfamiliar. Could you introduce them to me?”

In his cunning, Dongmen Tu casually responded, “I’ll be happy to once the matter with Devilfall Valley is concluded.”

Wang Tiansheng inwardly cursed him, but he knew that Dongmen Tu wouldn’t tell the truth. Unwilling to let this drag on, he gave the order to his disciples to teleport the six Nascent Soul cultivators in two groups. In the instant that Dongmen Tu was teleported, he unconsciously glanced at Han Li with a malicious expression.

Although his action was well hidden, Han Li had clearly seen it with his spiritual sense. It appeared that Dongmen Tu was able to sense the Spirit Nascent inside his body. This would prove troublesome. With the Elemental Spirit Nascents following him, he had suddenly become a fearsome foe. It was a pity that the Wood Spirit Nascent still wasn’t fully assimilated. It seemed that Han Li would have to be much more careful after he entered the valley.

Soon after Dongmen Tu was teleported, another group of three appeared behind them. Han Li wore a wry smile upon seeing them. They were Senior Martial Brother Cheng and two other Nascent Soul cultivators that were nearing the end of their lifespan.

Han Li sighed and watched the three teleport into the valley. Afterward, his attention shifted to the high-grade spirit stone that sat at the center of the spell formation. It had already grown mostly lightless.

Han Li’s gaze flickered and without any further hesitation, he soared into the sky and flew over in a streak of azure light. He soon descended in front of the spell formation and tossed his Devilfall Medallion towards Wang Tiansheng.

Wei Wuya’s figure blurred and he appeared a hundred meters away from Han Li. “Fellow Daoist Han, you’ve also arrived. With your young age, your prospects are limitless. There should be no need for you brave such danger.”

Han Li calmly replied, “Many thanks for your kindness Brother Wei, but there is a reason I must enter Devilfall Valley.”

Wei Wuya frowned and stared at Han Li’s expression for a moment more before his expression grew sullen. “Since Fellow Daoist Han has decided, I won’t speak of the matter further. I just hope that our goals differ.” With that said, Wei Wuya blurred and reappeared back in his original position.

After seeing Wei Wuya speak to this youth with such a serious tone, how could Wang Tiansheng not know who Han Li was? With a calm expression, he examined Han Li with shock filling his heart.

He had heard of Han Li many years ago when Wang Chan had suffered a massive loss which allowed Han Li to escape back when they both only possessed Foundation Establishment stage cultivations. After the passage of time, he had reappeared in the Heavenly South Continent as a Nascent Soul cultivator. Additionally, the youth had once again developed a deep hatred towards Ghost Spirit Sect and escaped their grasp once more.

Several years had passed since the incident at the Moulan Plains, while his reputation soared and he displayed abilities that left other cultivators in awe, raising him to become an existence on par with the Three Great Heavenly South cultivators. When Wang Tiansheng heard about this, the matter was far from good, and he took Han Li’s name to heart. Now that Han Li had arrived before them, he wished to figure out who this person was.

Unfortunately for him, Han Li was already standing at the center of the spell formation with his eyes shut and a neutral expression, leaving no openings for anybody else to approach him.

This caused Wang Tiansheng’s heart to tremble and he was touched with a faint sense of trepidation. Regardless, he was able to wave his hand with a relaxed posture and the disciples in the air activated the formation, sending Han Li off in a series of hums.

After a chain of teleportations, Han Li felt a wave of uneasiness but he eventually recovered his bearings and began to examine his surroundings.

He found himself near a mostly collapsed stone cliff and was surrounded by overgrown grass that reached half a person tall. In the distance, he saw a chain of short, unbroken hills. There wasn’t a person to be seen. However, this wasn’t strange in the least as Devilfall Valley spanned hundreds of thousands of kilometers. If two people weren’t teleported together, it would be incredibly difficult to find them. When Han Li turned around to look around about him, he couldn’t help but wear an astonished expression.

Chapter 812: The Ancient Python

Lu Weiying finished his incantation and pointed to the spell flag. Trembling, the flag suddenly unfolded, shining with a blinding light. Gusts of wind repeatedly blew around it like a storm, eventually gathering enough force to condense into ten or so white wind dragons, all rushing towards the mist with overbearing momentum.

As for Marquis Nanlong’s huge golden sword, it shot out with a hum and began to revolve above the mist. It seemed Marquis Nanlong was planning to wait for the mist to disperse before striking at the ancient beast with a thunderous blow the moment it appeared.

Han Li silently flung out his sleeve, summoning a small bell that flashed with silver light and flew off into the distance in a flash of light.

The wind dragons seemed to race each other as they struck headfirst into the mist. The grey mist roiled for a spell before being torn apart by a tornado from within.

However, the dispersion of the mist only lasted for a moment before a strange hiss filled the air and a muffled boom resounded through the mist. A huge snake tail swatted one of the wind dragons from the mist and dispersed the tornado.

Then with two more thuds, the snake tail easily smashed into two more wind dragons and threw them from the mist.

When Lu Weiying saw this, he was shocked and immediately grasped his hands in a strange incantation gesture, uttering, “Explode!” The remaining wind dragons suddenly flashed with white light and ruptured.

The explosive winds devastated the mist, scattering most of it with ferocious gales and revealing the monster within.

The snake was currently coiled up and appeared to be the size of a mountain. With its body now revealed, Marquis Nanlong’s golden sword took the opportunity to silently strike at it.

As this occurred, Han Li shot a spell seal at the silver bell. In a brilliant flash of light, the bell suddenly grew three meters tall. With a clear ring, a silver wave suddenly rushed out from the shining bell and moved to engulf the huge python in a joint attack with the huge golden sword.

The python was slow to react and simply lowered its head into its coiled cody in response to the attacks, remaining still.

Marquis Nanlong was overjoyed by the sight of this, and poured even more spiritual power into his sword, slightly enlarging it. But before the golden sword could strike, a layer of green light suddenly enveloped the python’s body without warning.

A huge boom sounded out as golden and green lights intertwined, but soon the green light overwhelmed the golden sword and repelled it. As that happened, the three cultivators were shocked.

Immediately after the golden sword was repelled, the silver soundwave struck the python’s barrier but was scattered without effort. The two successive attacks seemed to have awakened it as it slowly withdrew its head to look at Han Li and the others.

By this time, the grey mist had already cleanly scattered and the huge python had revealed itself before them.

The python’s body was as black as iron, over twenty hundred meters long and was exceptionally thick with black palm-sized scales covering it. Its faint green serpent eyes held an ominous glint.

Han Li felt his heart tremble upon seeing the python’s body. Just as he thought to recall his silver bell, the huge python suddenly extended itself in a blur and the silver bell that was a hundred meters away from it disappeared without a trace.

Before Han Li realized what had happened, Marquis Nanlong’s huge golden sword also disappeared from the sky with another blur from the python.

At that moment, Han Li had already processed what had happened: the huge python had extended itself with fantastical speed, swallowing both treasures in the blink of an eye. It had happened so fast that they were unable to even react.

Han Li grimaced. The python was giant, but its movements were still amazingly fast.

When Marquis Nanlong saw that the sword was swallowed, his alarm was soon replaced with joy as he had spent over a hundred years tempering his linked magic treasure. ‘The huge snake’s exterior defenses may be formidable, but since it has taken the initiative to swallow the sword into its stomach, isn’t it seeking its own death?’

With that thought, Marquis Nanlong hastily commanded the golden flying sword to display its full might within the python’s stomach and directly cleave through the beast. But in that short time, his expression froze.

Although his magic treasure was still connected to his spiritual sense, it was restrained within the huge python’s stomach and didn’t budge in the slightest. In that moment, he couldn’t help but grow nervous. After all, if his magic treasure suffered any damage, his consciousness would be heavily damaged as well.

“Fellow Daoists, my flying sword has been restrained. This python is no ordinary beast. Be careful.” With that said, Marquis Nanlong solemnly sighed and he raised his hand. A dark green ring flew off from his finger and floated in front of him. The ring pulsed with light and was faintly inscribed with various talisman characters.

Lu Weiying was alarmed to discover that their magic treasures had failed and he hastily attempted to recall his spell flag. Then with a wave of his hand, he released several talismans into the air that soon burst with white light, transforming into tens of blinding white fireballs that floated in front of him.

Han Li astonishedly glanced at the white fireballs and felt some familiarity towards them, but now was not the time to think on the matter. He then turned his head around and slapped his storage pouch, summoning six streaks of white light around him.

Three wolves, two flame oxen, and a green snake appeared in front of him. They were the six puppets that he had acquired from Daoist Heavencrystal at the grand trade meet. After he’d acquired them, he had yet to truly use them. Now that he was facing this formidable ancient python, it seemed to be a good opportunity to test their strength.

Marquis Nanlong and Lu Weiying saw Han Li’s puppets and momentarily revealed a trace of surprise.

The three were all vastly experienced cultivators. With a solemn exchange of glances, they all executed their various abilities in a joint attack against the python. However, an ominous glint began to condense within the python’s eyes as it stared at the three cultivators. It raised its head and spat out a mouthful of liquid towards them, filling the air with a fishy scent.

In their alarm, the three hastily raised light barriers around them and held their breaths. In the next moment, they discovered that while the fishy scent was putrid, it wasn’t poisonous. Regardless, it had still caused them to hesitate.

In that momentary delay, the huge python had widely opened its mouth and began to suddenly inhale, expanding its body.

In the blink of an eye, the entirety of the stone and earth in front of the python was sucked into its mouth. The three cultivators were caught off guard and felt a huge force pulling on them. They were rendered completely immobile as they resisted being sucked into python’s mouth.

Han Li’s six puppets were brought to the python's mouth in the blink of an eye, offering no resistance against the attractive force.

A trace of surprise appeared on Han Li’s face, but his heart remained calm. Azure light flashed from his body, causing him to grow incredibly heavy as he sank into the ground. Then with a mental command, the six puppets that had been brought to the python’s side began to attack. The red oxens’ horns began to flash with red light and shot four beams of light into the python’s gaping mouth.

Just as the python confidently believed that it could suck Han Li and the others into its stomach, it was struck at its exposed tongue.

Red light flashed and a series of thuds soon followed as the huge python groaned and closed its mouth. Although the extent of the damage to its tongue took was uncertain, it had stopped breathing in for the time being.

During that momentary pause, Han Li regained control of the three white wolf puppets. Their bodies brightly glowed with white light and regained their bearing on the ground using claws glowing with several inches of light. The wolves then brandished their vicious fangs before blurring from sight, flying towards the beast in streaks of light.

Clangs sounded out as the wolves struck the python’s head. For some unknown reason, the green light hadn’t appeared when the wolves struck, but the wolves shining claws and incisive fangs still weren’t able to harm the black scales; they were only able to leave behind white marks.

Then, two of the wolves immediately blurred and split up, shooting towards the huge python’s eyes. The eyes appeared bare and without the protection of its scales.

With a quick purple blur, two muffled thuds sounded out. The two white wolves were scattered with a lightning-fast flick of the python’s tongue and were sent flying.

The building-sized head of the python tilted to the side and began to close its mouth on the white wolf puppets. But just as it attempted to swallow them, the green snake puppet suddenly grew to forty meters in size and pounced at it. Additionally, the two red oxen shot out another attack from their horns.

Provoked by the puppets’ strikes, the huge python roared and it quickly swayed its head, spouting a black mist from its nostrils. In the blink of an eye, its entire head disappeared from view.

As for two of the white wolf puppets, they had taken this opportunity to run away. But suddenly, two figures shot out from the black mist and held down the two white wolves. They were two snake heads that appeared completely identical to the first.

This had all happened in the blink of an eye. By the time the cultivators realized what had happened, the black Qi had disappeared to reveal the python’s true form.

“This is a....”

“Three-headed Ebony Snake!”

“How is this possible!”

The three shouted with disbelief.

They were now facing a three-headed python that was furiously glaring at them. The center python head was hissing with its tongue flicking as the other two heads were chomping down on two of the wolf puppets.

Then, the still air rippled as the word “explode” was uttered. With two huge booms, the puppets in the snakes’ jaws suddenly shined with blinding white light.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Boring

PR: Lannis

Chapter 816: The Valley Depths

At the bottom of a steep three-kilometer tall cliff, there was a small cave that the party had just emerged from not long ago. After glancing at everything in front of him, Han Li couldn’t help but wear a peculiar expression and mutter, “This is the valley depths?”

Marquis Nanlong and Lu Weiying stood side by side as they gazed at the scene before them, both wearing odd expressions. There was a huge mountain range before them with countless mountains of varying sizes that stretched as far as the eye could see. Additionally, the world that surrounded them had areas glowing with rainbow light, both in the sky and on the earth.

The areas of rainbow light varied in size, with some reaching several kilometers in size and covering the sky, while others were only about a meter wide and shined weakly, but in any case, all of them were extremely beautiful. What caused Han Li and his party members to be astonished were not the clouds of light, but the chaotic nature of the spiritual Qi around them. Regardless of the attribute, the Qi mingled together and gave people a feeling of immense unease as if the very world would lash out at them with a single wrong move.

Marquis Nanlong sighed after collecting his thoughts and said, “This is definitely where the ancient cultivators fought. The worldly spiritual Qi is thoroughly destroyed here and as a result, it will have an influence on all of our techniques.”

Han Li wryly smiled and pointed to the sky, saying, “That is only a secondary concern. That’s what is going to be most troublesome.”

About a kilometer above them in the sky, there was a group of over ten foot-long arcs of white light floating there. Marquis Nanlong and Lu Weiying were greatly startled when they clearly saw what they were.

Lu Weiying shouted in astonishment, “How can there be so many spatial tears? And how can they wander?”

Marquis Nanlong’s expression also grew unsightly.

After noticing Marquis Nanlong’s change in expression, Han Li chuckled and said, “This should be expected. Since this was the battleground of ancient cultivators, there should be more spatial tears here compared to the outside. Why else would so many Nascent Soul cultivators have entered only to never return? We can only rely on Master Cang Kun’s map regarding the path forward or else...”

“Brother Han’s words do make sense. We definitely can’t take any risks and tread off the recorded path. Else, we may encounter some invisible spatial tears there. However, there is still much to fear from the wandering spatial tears, but so long as we pay attention to them, they shouldn’t pose much danger.” After saying this, Marquis Nanlong regained his composure.

Lu Weiying tensely frowned as he stared at another area filled with spatial tears. He pensively mentioned, “However, the number of these spatial tears is over ten times greater than that on the outside. Your words only apply if the invisible spatial tears don’t wander as well. If the invisible spatial tears roam and scatter like the visible ones, then Master Cang Kun’s map might not be safe.”

When Han Li heard this, he was stunned and turned his head. Blue light brightly shined from his eyes as he glanced at an area over three hundred meters away, watching a vague arc of light motionlessly floating there. He only calmed down after watching it for a while.

But then, just as he pondered about whether or not he should leak this information to his party members, Marquis Nanlong hesitantly spoke as if misunderstanding Han Li’s pondering for worry, “There is no need for you Fellow Daoists to be worried. Master Cang Kun mentioned that the invisible spatial tears don’t move in his records.”

Lu Weiying’s spirits roused and he suspiciously asked, “Is Brother Nanlong certain? How did Master Cang Kun learn about it?”

Marquis Nanlong looked at the two and calmly said, “Brother Lu should realize that in the past, Master Cang Kun had suffered from grave injuries. What should come into question was how he was able to safely leave Devilfall Valley. By relying on a technique that he had cultivated, he was able to sense the locations of spatial tears before leaving the valley. How else could he have left with such grave injuries?”

Having heard this, Lu Weiying felt a wave of relief, “There are such techniques in this world? In that case, it wasn’t due to luck that Master Cang Kun was able to escape from Devilfall Valley.”

Han Li’s expression stirred as well and he sighed with relief. Marquis Nanlong’s worries faded away upon seeing this as he had feared that his party members would be intent on retreating. He was particularly worried about Han Li who he found immensely difficult to read. Since Han Li would be the main force in the fight against the Ancient Flame Toad, he needed to convince him to move forward.

With a stern expression, Marquis Nanlong then said, “Let’s go. According to what the records said, we cannot fly too quickly so it will be about a day of travel until we arrive at the Ancient Flame Toad’s nest. Be careful on the way there.”

Han Li faintly smiled and said, “Fellow Daoist Nanlong should be worried about taking care of himself, Fellow Daoist Lu and I will look after ourselves.”

Lu Weiying nodded in agreement.

Satisfied, Marquis Nanlong said, “Then let us set off. We’ve wasted enough time as it is.” He then got his bearings and wrapped himself in a ball of light before slowly flying off.

Han Li and Lu Weiying glanced at each other and also took to the air. They closely followed after Marquis Nanlong without taking even a step off his track as any deviation could lead them into a spatial tear or an ancient restriction. As such, the party was painstakingly careful.

The path taken along the way was incredibly strange. There were times it would go straight and others where it would move in a complete circle. But regardless of the path, they would stop every two hours and make sure of their location before continuing forward. Additionally, Marquis Nanlong didn’t look at any jade slips on the way. It was clear he had already memorized the path.

Han Li maintained a neutral appearance, but on the way, he was memorizing every step of the path back. As such, if there were any unexpected developments, he would have a path to flee for his life. He reckoned that Lu Weiying was most likely doing the same. After all, cultivators who had mastered the basic elemental cultivation arts gained a perfect memory. This made remembering some directions an effortless task.

Their flight continued for almost an entire day and hadn’t encountered any danger. Han Li felt at ease, believing that the Marquis had acquired the genuine route Master Cang Kun had used when travelling through the valley depths.

As Han Li continued memorizing the path while following Marquis Nanlong, he diligently scanned his surroundings with his spiritual sense. He reckoned they had passed by at least four areas that were guarded with formidable restrictions along the way. There were also a few areas that seemed amiss but he wasn’t able to determine whether they were spell formations or abnormalities produced from spiritual Qi fluctuations.

Han Li was quite curious about these areas as he knew that they were likely to contain treasures left behind by ancient cultivators. Although he felt eager to explore these areas, he restrained himself.

Han Li possessed some understanding of certain ancient cultivator restrictions, but he also knew that they were incredibly formidable, and only the spatial tears posed a greater danger than the restrictions. Even with his Brightsight Spirit Eyes being able to see through, there was still a significant chance of him provoking a profound restriction.

Currently, common ancient treasures no longer tempted him. Having entered the valley, so long as he acquired the core of the Ancient Flame Toad, the remnant treasures of the ancient cultivator, the Spirit Kindle Fruit, and the Tailstar Silver, he would reap massive gains.

With the potentials benefits and drawbacks considered, Han Li abandoned any intention of doing anything dangerous. Then, his gaze was drawn over to Lu Weiying since he currently wore a sullen expression and occasionally glanced into the distance.

Han Li inwardly sighed. It seemed that if the old man couldn’t acquire the items he wanted from the ancient cultivator remains, he would most likely search the valley depths. It wasn’t a matter of greed, but rather desperation. Han Li knew that if his lifespan had also reached its end, he would take the risk. After all, if he succeeded, his life would be prolonged and his cultivation would advance.

As Han Li considered this, he couldn’t help but show a trace of sorrow.

At that moment, Marquis Nanlong ceased flying and looked to the area in front of him, his expression wavering. Han Li frowned at the sight of this and faintly felt a sense of dread. He glanced around him and immediately stared at Marquis Nanlong’s back in silence.

Below them was a small mountain over three hundred meters tall and entirely unremarkable. Ahead of them was an extremely tall mountain range.

Marquis Nanlong had clearly said that it would take a day of travel to reach the nest of the Ancient Flame Toad, but they hadn’t flown that long so it was clear this wasn’t their objective.

Lu Weiying was puzzled by this sudden stop and asked with a surprised expression, “Brother Nanlong, what happened? Why aren’t we moving forward?”

When Marquis Nanlong heard this, he slowly turned around to look at his party members. He bitterly smiled and said, “It seems we’ve encountered a problem. We might need to brave a bit of danger.”

Lu Weiying’s expression blanked and he bewilderedly said, “Brother Nanlong, what do you mean?”

Han Li stroked his nose but remained silent. However, he wore a curious expression.

“Fellow Daoists, do you see the two mountains in the distance?” Marquis Nanlong pointed to two mountains that were surprisingly alike.

“Of course we do. Does this problem have something to do with them?” Lu Weiying astonishedly asked.

“Precisely.” Marquis Nanlong spoke with complete certainty.

Chapter 817: Ten Supreme Poisons

Lu Weiying noticed nothing out of ordinary about those two mountains and asked, “Is there something wrong with them?”

“From now on, we’re setting off to one of those two mountains. The point where they join together will be the Ancient Flame Toad's nest. However, there is a group of Soaring Purple-lined Scorpions that dwell on the left side of the mountain range. Although they only number in the tens, each one of them is ferocious. I fear that we will most likely alarm them. It will be quite troublesome.”

Lu Weiying shouted in alarm, “Soaring Purple-lined Scorpions? Those fearsome insects that eliminated all the cultivators of the Ocean Mist Sect in the State of Wangsui?”

Han Li felt a wave of shock when he heard the name ‘Soaring Purple-lined Scorpions’.

Marquis Nanlong sighed and said, “That’s right, it's those vicious insects. Additionally, this lot is much more fearsome than the swarm that emerged in the State of Wangsui. These have lived for tens of thousands of years and their bodies are entirely purple-black.”

Lu Weiying lost his composure and glared at Marquis Nanlong as he bluntly said, “Fellow Daoist Nanlong, please tell me you’re joking! How could we afford to provoke Purple-lined Scorpions? If there were only two or three of them, we could deal with them if we were careful, but there are over ten of them. Wouldn’t we be sending ourselves to our deaths if we approach them?”

Marquis Nanlong wore a helpless expression and explained, “There is one other path, but it is even more dangerous as it is filled with a large number of invisible spatial tears. It isn’t something that we can tread through. Since we can’t identify the location of the invisible tears, the Purple-lined Scorpions is definitely the safer option.”

Lu Weiying remained dumbfounded for a long while. Needless to say, Purple-lined Scorpions were preferable to spatial tears, especially invisible ones.

When Han Li heard of the invisible spatial tears, he looked into the distance and his gaze began to wander.

Han Li finally broke his silence and spoke with a wry smile, “It seemed Master Cang Kun had taken the path with the spatial tears. He should’ve been able to avoid them with his abilities.”

When Marquis Nanlong heard this, he bitterly smiled and said, “Brother Han is right. Without Master Cang Kun’s abilities, we have no way to safely avoid the spatial tears. In comparison, a battle with the Purple-lined Scorpions is far less dangerous.”

Lu Weiying strongly shook his head and said, “That won’t do. We definitely cannot fight the Purple-lined Scorpions. You only heard of what had happened in the State of Wangsui, but I personally took part in the Purple-lined Scorpion’s extermination as a representative of the Heavenpeak Sect. They are fearsome beyond your imagination. Provoking all of them at once is a death sentence.”

The old man’s fear towards the scorpions was beyond what Marquis Nanlong had anticipated. He originally believed that they would prevail over the scorpions despite a bit of challenge. Now, he wore an expression of hesitation.

At that moment, Han Li frowned and began to recall the information regarding the Purple-lined Scorpions from the exotic insect rankings.

Soaring Purple-lined Scorpions were ranked fourteenth, close to the Gold Devouring Beetles. If it weren’t for the small number of eggs that the scorpions laid and their limited numbers, their ranking would likely be above the Gold Devouring Beetles.

Although they didn’t have the same ability to devour everything like the Gold Devouring Beetles, their defenses were about the same and they couldn’t be harmed by ordinary magic treasures. Additionally, their speed was amazingly fast and they were incredibly venomous, earning them their high position on the exotic insect rankings. Not to mention that these Purple-lined Scorpions had resided in Devilfall Valley for countless years. They had already reached the peak form of maturation where their bodies turned purple-black.

However, it appeared Marquis Nanlong only knew a smidgen of how fearsome these insects were. Contrarily, Lu Weiying had witnessed their power before and paled at the very mention of them.

As Marquis Nanlong’s expression turned gloomy, Han Li coldly chuckled. Marquis Nanlong had only mentioned the Purple-lined Scorpions after they arrived this far. It seemed it wasn’t done out of any good intentions but to keep them from fleeing. Since they had traveled so long, they would both feel reluctant to return without having made any gains and would feel obliged to face the danger.

Han Li continued weighing his options as he considered the danger of dealing with the Purple-lined Scorpions versus what there was to gain. After all, he would have to reveal his abilities to see through spatial tears in order to take the other path. As it was his most crucial ability for guiding him through the valley, he wouldn’t tell it to others unless it was absolutely necessary.

While Han Li pondered with a lowered head, Lu Weiying stood in place with a gloomy expression, his fear betrayed from his eyes. Marquis Nanlong also glanced at the mountain with the Purple-lined Scorpions with a wavering expression.

For a time, the three floated in place without knowing whether to advance or retreat.

After a long silence, Han Li’s expression stirred and he lifted his head to reveal a slight smile. Although Marquis Nanlong and Lu Weiying appeared absentminded, they were closely paying attention to the actions of their companions and noticed Han Li’s movements.

Marquis Nanlong immediately turned his head to look at Han Li and asked, “What? Could it be that Brother Han has a good idea?” A trace of hope could be heard from his tone.

Lu Weiying also turned to look at Han Li with excitement. However, Han Li didn’t immediately reply. Instead, he grasped his storage pouch, taking out a small green bottle. He asked, “Have you two Fellow Daoists heard of the Ten Supreme Poisons?”

Startled, Lu Weiying said, “The Ten Supreme Poisons? I heard that they possessed an inconceivable toxicity. Even if cultivators like us were to make contact with those poisons, we could come to an immediate end. I have heard that Wei Wuya mainly cultivates venomous techniques, allowing him to utilize one of the Ten Supreme Poisons, Corpse Venom. When other cultivators fight him, they dare not get too close to him or they risk perishing without warning.“

Marquis Nanlong looked at the small bottle in Han Lil’s hand and quickly said, “However, I heard that a few of the Ten Supreme Poisons had other miraculous uses apart from their deadly applications. Could it be that Fellow Daoist Han has one of these poisons?”

Han Li raised the small bottle and explained, “It seems there is no need for me to say anything. As you’ve already guessed, this bottle contains one of the Ten Supreme Poisons, Jadedove. It is said that this poison is refined from the saliva of a demon bird with a jade beak.”

“Brother Han means to say...” A trace of happiness appeared on Lu Weiying’s face.

Han Li promptly answered, “The Purple-lined Scorpions may be durable, but so long as we use the poison to draw them away from the mountains, it will give us the opportunity to entirely avoid them.”

“How can we draw them away with the poison? Oh, hehe. I forgot that Fellow Daoist was skilled in puppet techniques. Smearing a few puppets with the poison should be enough to attract the scorpions.” At that moment Marquis Nanlong smiled.

Once that was said, Han Li’s expression remained unchanged as he mused, ‘Marquis Nanlong speaks of the matter quite easily and has pushed it completely onto me with only a few words. Especially since his Eternal Flight Orioles would do just as well. Last time, several of my puppets were destroyed in the fight against the huge python.’

Although Han Li felt somewhat dissatisfied, he calmly nodded. Because this was but a small matter, he wasn’t willing to have a falling out over it. After all, they were still only halfway to their objective, and the poison was originally one of the treasures left behind by Master Cang Kun after all.

With Han Li’s medicinal experience, he was able to recognize the poison with a single sniff and had immediately put it away. Now that he thought about it, it was quite possible that Master Cang Kun had left behind the poison in preparation to deal with the Purple-lined Scorpions.

However, it seemed excessively affectionate and out of character for Master Cang Kun to scheme every step for his descendants to acquire treasure. Having recalled Master Cang Kun’s ruins, he remembered the portrait of the three-headed six-armed demon beast, feeling that there was something mysterious about it. Since Marquis Nanlong had previously said that he was a descendant of Master Cang Kun, he should know something of it.

But regardless of whatever was amiss, Han Li was only concerned with acquiring the core of the Ancient Flame Toad. He wouldn’t involve himself in matters that didn’t concern him and risk attracting problems to himself.

As Han Li came to this conclusion, his hands continued to move. With a casual slap of his storage pouch, he summoned five streaks of light from his storage pouch, revealing themselves to be huge ape puppets.

Han Li promptly took out several small jade bottles and poured a drop of the Jadedove poison into each of them before properly sealing the bottles. He then gave them to the ape puppets to tightly grasp.

Then under the guidance of Marquis Nanlong, Han Li ordered his huge ape puppets to silently make their way to the left mountaintop.

After they made it part of the way, Han Li turned to his party and said, “Let us set out too. We can’t be too far away from the puppets. When the puppets attract the scorpions, we’ll have to move as quickly as possible across the mountain or we may miss our chance.”

Marquis Nanlong and Lu Weiying raised no objections and closely followed after the ape puppets alongside him.

Soon, the ape puppets arrived at the mountain peak with Han Li and the others a couple kilometers away in concealment. At that moment, the puppets used the entirety of their strength to crush the small bottles in their hands.

Suddenly, a putrid smell immediately spread through the mountain and the ape puppets flew off to one side of the mountain.

Chapter 828: Joining Together

As Divine Sage Zhong and Cultivator Lu were having their discussion, Han Li had already flown over fifty kilometers away. Nothing else occurred on his way and he arrived at the cave after another hour of flight.

When he arrived, he took out the Yin Yang Ring once more and entered the passageway with the treasure’s protection. He quickly passed through the passage and quickened his steps when he saw the light of the cave’s exit.

Soon, his surroundings brightened and he found himself back in front of a cliff leading to the outer valley.

Han Li raised his head to look at the dusky sky. Although it still gave him a feeling of unease, it was far better than the crimson light that covered the sky in the valley depths.

After sweeping his spiritual sense over the nearby area and discovering there were no cultivators or any other oddities, Han Li sighed with relief and turned his gaze to the wall around the cave entrance.

With a wave of his hand, an azure spell seal flew out and entered the stone wall without a trace. Soon after, Han Li silently formed another hand gesture as he began to slowly mutter an incantation while a strange scene followed.

The unremarkable stone wall suddenly began to glow with a layer of blue light before a swarm of Gold Devouring Beetles flocked out from the wall, each of them carrying various-sized pieces of silver crystal. A few pieces were as large as a fist while others were as small as a grain of sand. In the blink of an eye, the pieces of silver crystal delivered by the beetles had formed a pile in front of Han Li. They were the crystalized Tailstar Silver ore.

When the first pieces appeared, Han Li’s expression was calm, but excitement began to show when tens of these crystals dropped down.

“Youngster Han! The Tailstar Silver ore vein is far bigger than I imagined. It seems I will be able to research using this material in creating puppets.” Suddenly, the Monarch of Soul Divergence’s voice appeared in Han Li’s mind. He couldn’t help but betray his delight from his voice.

After the Gold Devouring Beetles had deposited the last of the Tailstar Silver crystal, Han Li looked at the small pile of shimmering silver and smiled. “That’s right. I also didn’t think the Tailstar Silver ore vein would contain this much. We’ve gathered quite the harvest!”

Han Li swung his sleeve over the ground and swept up the silver crystals into his storage pouch in an instant. Afterwards, he sharply whistled and the Gold Devouring Beetles revolved around him before rushing back into their storage pouch.

Once this was done, Han Li slapped his storage pouch and a translucent ball appeared in his palm. He then blew a mist of azure light onto the pearl and a bean-sized speck of light appeared within the ball.

Han Li stared at the pearl in his hand for a long while and slightly frowned before looking around him. After getting his bearings, his body glowed with azure light and he streaked through the sky.

Han Li wasn’t flying in a hurry and as he flew with the transparent ball in his hand, he would occasionally stop to look at it before adjusting his course and continuing on his way.

After flying for tens of kilometers, he arrived above a wilderness and yelped with surprise before coming to a sudden stop. His body blurred and he quickly descended. By the time he was a hundred meters above the wilderness, Han Li stopped and light flashed from his eyes.

He saw a male cultivator’s corpse split in half lying in the wilderness and the surroundings had already been stained dark red with the hardened blood. As for the cultivator’s magic treasure and storage pouch, they were nowhere to be seen.

Han Li glanced at the corpse for a moment and sighed, “It seems someone had attacked him.” After verifying that there were no spatial tears nearby, he knew there was only one possible conclusion.

Han Li didn’t linger there for long and quickly continued on his way. Although he believed that there were few things in the valley that posed a threat to him apart from the two late Nascent Soul cultivators, it would still prove dangerous if a group of cultivators were to surround and ambush him.

While this wasn’t likely, Han Li traveled with heightened wariness regardless. After half a day had passed, Han Li still hadn’t found any signs of an ambush. Rather, he came across two cultivators who had perished as a result of spatial tears. Han Li shook his head at the sight of their broken bodies.

Following the guidance of the transparent ball in his hand, he eventually arrived above a dense and verdant forest.

Han Li muttered to himself for a moment before gripping the transparent ball in his hand and exerting strength into it. In a flash of azure light, it shattered with a clear ring.

When the ball shattered into fragments, the speck of azure light that floated inside of it was freed. The speck of light floated in front of Han Li while waiting for further instruction. The bean-sized speck of light flickered before shooting off as soon as he pointed at it while he closely followed after it.

A moment later in the sky above the dense forest, the speck of light flickered and began to fly downwards. As Han Li descended after it, a glint shined within his eyes. When it arrived at the ground, the speck of light spun around a gigantic tree before disappearing into its trunk.

When Han Li saw this, he landed in front of the tree and the light around him faded away. He quickly sized up the tree before pressing his hand against it.

With a muffled bang, green light flashed from where he pressed his palm and an azure talisman floated from the tree. He swiftly grabbed the talisman between his finger and glanced at it with a smile before tossing it into the air.

Woosh . The talisman set itself on fire before streaking into the sky in a fiery red line.

This time, Han Li stood still for a moment and sat cross-legged on the ground before closing his eyes and restoring the magic power he had consumed on his way here.

Not long after, the streak of red light dropped down at an unremarkable corner of the forest. Then another streak of light emerged into the sky and flew towards Han Li’s location.

Before the streak of light arrived, Han Li slowly opened his eyes and watched as it approached.

The streak of light soon arrived. It flew once around Han Li as if verifying his identity and then swooped down. As soon as the streak touched the ground, the light instantly disappeared to reveal a white-robed woman who possessed an otherworldly beauty.

Han Li calmly looked at her and said, “Lady Violet Spirit! You arrived quite quickly!”

“Quickly? I’ve already been waiting here for several days. During that time, seven groups of cultivators have searched through this forest, and I grew more nervous each time it happened. I would’ve left soon if Brother Han didn’t arrive.” Violet Spirit’s pleasant voice seemed to contain a bit of annoyance as she walked towards him with graceful steps.

Han Li smiled and looked at Violet Spirit’s flawless face before continuing, “Lady Violet Spirit revealing her true appearance has come as a surprise to me. I had believed that it was easy for you to conceal.”

Violet Spirit pursed her lips and sweetly said, “When I entered the valley, I had used a treasure to conceal my true appearance. However, there seems to be a restriction in the valley that has rendered it ineffective. Without it to conceal my true appearance, I have no choice to but wear it. What? Could it be that my uncouth appearance is below Brother Han’s notice?”

“Fairy Violet Spirit must be joking.” With a wry chuckle, his expression suddenly became solemn as he said, “That’s enough joking around. Was this the first place you found that was marked?”

Violet Spirit withdrew her smile and answered, “That’s right. It should be genuine since the original mark was destroyed by the Ghost Spirit Sect. However, finding it should prove to be no problem.”

When Han Li heard her mention the Ghost Spirit Sect, he raised his brow and coldly smiled. “Since that’s the case, let’s just follow the Ghost Spirit Sect disciples. It should save us quite a bit of time.”

“As Brother Han commands! A month ago, I placed a tracker unique to the Exquisite Sound Sect onto the Ghost Spirit Sect disciple who gave me the information. The tracker isn’t something created from magic power but by a fragrance undetectable to others. While the range of this fragrance isn’t large and it disappears after two months, it should still be enough to track down the Ghost Spirit Sect disciple that I placed it on.”

“I will have to trouble Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit to lead the way. First, we will track down the Ghost Spirit Sect disciple and rush past the marks they placed before. This way, the Spirit Kindle Fruit will be ours.” Han Li nodded and then slowly stood up.

A silver-tailed squirrel suddenly shot out from the dense forest and flew into the sky. It then sniffed the air before flying off in a certain direction.

Soon after, two streaks of light flew in a circle before closely flying after it.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Boring

Chapter 840: A Startling Change

While the three cultivators were dealing with the Elder Devil Corpse, bright light began to wind around Han Li’s body and his surroundings turned dim and hazy. Countless specks of white light danced around in the air around him.

Han Li clasped his hands in an incantation gesture and spiritual light flowed without end around his body. A whirlwind of light rose from the ground and enveloped him in a gorgeous display.

Soon after, gales began to blow with ever greater force and frequency as time went by. As for the white light specks in the distance, they were swept up like moths to the flame. Not long after, the winds formed a huge pillar that reached into the sky, picking up stones and sand wherever it went as if possessed by a devil.

At that moment, Han Li’s incantation echoed through the fierce winds, causing the pillar of wind to tremble before dispersing thin, glowing clouds through the air.

The incantation was quickly spoken and the glowing clouds turned blue. Soon, the sound of rushing water filled the air and countless surging waves rose as far as the eye could see. Waves up to three hundred meters tall began to rise around him. As for Han Li, he was standing within a huge pillar of water and blue light shined from his incantation gesture, appearing as if he were a water god.

Suddenly, Han Li’s incantation gesture changed and the light became muddled.The huge waves of water disappeared in the blink of an eye as if they were an illusion and were replaced with waves of scarlet flame. Over ten, hundred-meter-long fire dragons emerged from them, each of them spitting fire from their mouths.

Then, the flames disappeared only to be replaced with a verdant sea of trees, then an endless desert, a world of ice, and many other worlds as Han Li willed them into existence. For the moment, he appeared to be a godlike existence.

Han Li appeared satisfied with what he had done and used his magic power to condense a three-kilometer-tall giant. He had it beat its chest before roaring at the sky. Afterwards, silver light began to streak from every corner of the horizon and surged towards the giant in a silver wave.

Blinding silver streaks filled the sky and the giant melted underneath the silver lights as if it were ice before a flame. But when this light covered Han Li, he immediately covered his eyes with his hands and miserably scream.

Following his scream, the silver lights in the sky scattered.

Han Li felt completely dazed, but he soon opened his eyes in alarm as both the silver light and the world around him had completely disappeared. He was sitting inside a secluded room, his body completely drenched in sweat.

Han Li took a deep breath and calmed himself, finally recalling that he was within a sealed room inside Devilfall Valley. Not long before, he had taken the Nature Origin Pill that he had refined and was enveloped in an illusory world made by the medicinal power erupting from the pill.

He blankly remained seated and didn’t immediately stand up. As he reflected upon his own experiences in the illusory world, his expression wavered from revelation one moment and confusion the next. He then touched his back and found his robes to be drenched.

Han Li bitterly smiled. The Nature Origin Pill was beyond miraculous for it to be capable of sinking his mind into a world of illusions in spite of his vast spiritual sense.

As for his time inside the illusion, he had become an entirely different person and experienced inconceivable events. He had grasped tremendous power with ease, capable of shifting mountains and seas or calling wind and rain.

But when Han Li recalled what he had done in the illusion, the incantations became incredibly vague and he couldn’t recall a single word that he spoken, but the sensation from wielding worldly spiritual power of that level was remembered with complete detail. He felt as if he had experienced it with his body and believed it would prove beneficial for him when breaking through to the next cultivation realm.

Han Li then closed his eyes once more and in place for half a day before opening his eyes with restored calm. Any trace of confusion had disappeared from his face. He stood up and raised his hand, striking the stone door in front of him with a spell seal. The door flickered with spirit light and slowly opened, allowing Han Li to calmly walk out.

As soon as he walked out, a white streak of light flew out from the stone wall and into his sleeve. It was Silvermoon in her fox form.

Han Li slowly walked towards the cave’s entrance and asked, “How long was I in seclusion? Did anything happen while I was in there?”

Silvermoon replied with a respectful tone, “Master was in seclusion for two days. During this time Violet Spirit had emerged, but she saw that the restrictions protecting your cave had yet to be removed and returned to her residence.”

Han Li indifferently said, “Given her lower cultivation, the Nature Origin PIll should’ve had a lesser effect on her. It is no wonder that she left seclusion earlier. Rather, I am more surprised that you don’t want to take one.”

Silvermoon’s helpless voice came his sleeve, “Master should know that I am quite a bit different from a human cultivator. I am a Silvermoon Wolf that is possessing the body of a demon fox. In addition to medicine pills used to advance cultivation, I don’t dare to negligently take any other types of cultivator medicine pills. Who knows what harm they could cause me? I would rather just spend more time cultivating than take that risk.”

After a moment of thought, Han Li frowned and nodded without speak further.

Of course, Han Li hadn’t wasted the remaining Spirit Kindle Fruits. He had chosen to consume them before taking the Nature Origin Pill. When their medicinal power dissolved into his body, he experienced a small but noticeable increase in cultivation. It truly deserved to be a spirit medicine rarely seen in this world.

When Han Li arrived near the exit of his cave residence, he found his puppets obediently guarding the gate. He took several steps forward and swept them into his storage pouch in a flash of white light.

At that moment, Han Li opened the stone gate of his cave residence with a magic technique and calmly walked out.

In the instant Han Li walked out, a streak of light shot out from one of the neighboring mountains.

When Han Li saw the light approaching, he calmly waved his hands around him, causing all the nearby formation flags and plates that were placed in the ground to fly into his hands one after another in streaks of azure light.

At that moment, the streak arrived in front of Han Li, revealing Violet Spirit’s figure. She sweetly smiled at Han Li as she floated in the air. Her gorgeous beauty soon unfolded as the light faded away around her face.

“Brother Han, you’ve finally emerged. I had believed it would’ve taken you another half day before you came out.”

Han Li smiled and said, “It seems Violet Spirit has experienced rather fine results after taking the Nature Origin Pill. You are only a few years away from ascending to mid Core Formation stage. Allow me to offer my congratulations ahead of time.”

Violet Spirit’s gaze flickered and she happily said, “Brother Han must be joking. The Nature Origin Pill only saved me several tens of years of bitter cultivation. However, Brother Han now has a good chance of reaching mid Nascent Soul stage after taking the pill. This is worthy of even greater congratulations.”

“Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit can’t have believed that the Nature Origin Pill has the same effect on a Core Formation cultivator as a Nascent Soul cultivator,” Han Li calmly said, “Although it was said that the pill is effective to everyone under the Deity Transformation stage, the lower the cultivation one possesses, the greater the effect. When Core Formation cultivators take the pill, there is no doubt that they will be able to ascend to the next level, but this isn’t guaranteed for a Nascent Soul cultivator.”

“Regardless of how it is said, the Nature Origin Pill is greatly useful towards ascending to the next level of cultivation. There is no need for Brother Han to be so modest. And give the aptitude Brother Han displayed after reaching the Nascent Soul stage in only two hundred years, he should only be a step away from entering mid Nascent Soul stage.”

‘Aptitude?’ When Han Li heard Violet Spirit say this, he couldn’t help but bitterly laugh. Although he didn’t correct her, he did shake his head in silence.

Violet Spirit pursed her lips in a smile and thought to say something more when a huge rumble sounded out in the distance. It appeared as if a fierce tremble shook the entire world. Han Li handled it well enough, but Violet Spirit was shaken by this and started to fall from the air.

She hastily stopped her fall with a burst of light and shouted in alarm, “What happened? What’s going on?”

Also shocked, Han Li turned his head in the direction of the source of this sound.

‘Yi! That is the area that the map indicated.’ Han Li’s heart stirred and he felt somewhat bewildered.

At that moment, a white line howled as it streaked over from the horizon, carrying booms in its wake. In the blink of an eye, the white light grew thicker and countless waves of white Qi suddenly appeared nearby.

As far as the eye could see, a boundless and unimaginably tall wave of white Qi engulfed the surrounding mountains as it made its way towards Han Li and Violet Spirit. In the blink of an eye, it was only about a kilometer away from them.

“Not good!” When Han Li saw this, his expression changed and he summoned the small blue shield with a shake of his sleeve. It revolved around him once before expanding into a huge shield in front of him.

He pointed at the huge shield and a layer of blue light was emitted from it, enveloping Han Li. Still feeling uneasy, he spat out a ball of blue icy flame and had it rupture thirty meters in front of him.

The blue flame radiantly glowed and crackled. The large icy ball of Qi rapidly expanded and in the blink of an eye, a twenty-meter-tall ice mountain appeared in front of Han Li.

As for Violet Spirit, she had also reacted with alarm and released an embroidered scarf that released a mist of light to protect her. When she saw that Han Li had condensed an ice mountain, she hastily flew to his side with delight. At that moment, the rushing wave of Qi arrived before them.

The entire sky grew dim while the violent sounds of the earth shattering burst around them. A huge tremble went through the ice mountain before them as tens of boulders smashed into it, each impact releasing a sharp clank. The sound was discomforting and made one’s heart stir.

Chapter 841: First Devil Sighting

When Violet Spirit saw the huge mountain of ice on the verge of breaking, she paled and unconsciously turned to look at Han Li.

At the moment, Han Li appeared unperturbed and without a trace of panic. When Violet Spirit saw this, her heart steadied, knowing that he most likely had further methods to protect himself.

But to Violet Spirit’s surprise, Han Li didn’t make further use of any magic treasures or techniques. Although the blue ice mountain trembled underneath the boulders and Qi wave, it held fast and showed no further signs of breaking.

In her delight, Violet Spirit discovered that the mountain of ice wasn’t condensed from ordinary glacial Qi and was far more hardy than one would expect.

After the time it took to finish a cup of tea, the astonishing white wave of Qi eventually finished rushing past them. It continued rumbling into the distance before finally disappearing from sight.

Violet Spirit sighed, summoning her embroidered scarf back into her hand from its mist form. She looked at Han Li and puzzlingly asked, “What is that? How could Devilfall Valley possess such a thing?”

Han Li’s eyes flickered and he muttered, “I’m not sure. However, there’s something strange about the spiritual Qi that appeared in the distance. It was extremely chaotic. Could such an astonishing wave of Qi have come from a spatial tear instead of a person? However, the wave of Qi was so fearsome that the valley’s restrictions weren’t able to stop it. Nascent Soul cultivators should be able to deal with it well enough, but if that wave reached the outer valley, those Core formation cultivators would almost certainly perish.”

When Violet Spirit heard Han Li, she frowned and also used her spiritual sense to look in the direction that the Qi wave had arrived from. She was only able to sense that the spiritual Qi was somewhat abnormal since her spiritual sense wasn’t able to reach that far.

“There is something amiss. Brother Han, could it be you plan on investigating the source of this?”

Han Li hesitated for a moment and spoke with a tone of certainty, “Why would I plan on investigating it? Regardless of whether the wave was artificially made or a coincidental explosion, I don’t want to look for trouble despite how curious I may be. Let’s return to the outer valley since we’ve already fulfilled our objective. With this strange occurrence, the Ghost Spirit Sect will most likely be too occupied to find us. It’s a good opportunity to leave without being noticed.”

Afterwards, he pointed to the shield in front of him and it quickly shrank before returning into his sleeve.

As for the ice mountain, Han Li pressed his hand against its walls and blue light suddenly shined. The mountain thawed in the blink of an eye and soon, a ball of blue flame was all that remained before it returned to his palm.

When Violet Spirit saw this, she wore an expression of alarm.

Han Li raised his palm and looked at the ball of blue flame with a trace of satisfaction. This new technique of using the ice flames was something he had developed from his experience in the world of illusion. Although this was the first time he had used it, it was done with skill and precision as if he had done this several times before, much to Han Li’s surprise.

This illustrated that the experiences within the world of illusion weren’t born from simple imagination; they were truly the understandings of heaven and earth from a higher realm. After this experience, Han Li had higher hopes for entering mid-Nascent Soul stage.

With a faint smile on his face, he turned to Violet Spirit and thought to say something when light suddenly shined from the horizon behind them to reveal two streaks of light.

A streak of yellow and a streak of white light trembled as they shot across the sky as if they were fleeing in Han Li’s direction.

“Yi!” When Han Li saw them with his spiritual sense, he yelped with surprise.

Violet Spirit stretched out her spiritual sense only to discover that the two streaks of light belonged to two Nascent Soul cultivators. As she wasn’t able to see anything further, she asked, “Brother Han, you know those two?”

“Of course I recognize them. I’ve had some dealings with them in the past!” Han Li frowned and stared at them with an odd expression.

One of the streaks of light contained a yellow-robed old man with a sallow face — Yellow Maple Valley’s Ancestor Linghu. As for the other streak of light, it contained a white-clothed woman with an icy expression, the grand elder of the Masked Moon Sect and Nangong Wan’s Senior Martial Sister.

Han Li was surprised that the two had also entered Devilfall Valley. It seems they had stolen into the valley at the very last moment.

The two wore expressions of fright and were fleeing as quickly as they could, but there was visible nothing behind them. Regardless, they continued to flee as if there was something in close pursuit, and they didn’t dare to slow down. Han Li found this truly strange as they weren’t weak individuals by any means.

Ancestor Linghu was a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator and Nangong Wan’s Senior Martial Sister possessed formidable treasures and techniques. It was hard to believe that the two had decided to frantically flee instead of standing their ground. Could it be that the Moulan Divine Sage Zhong was chasing them down?

With that thought, Han Li felt his heart tremble. His relationship with the Moulan spell warriors was anything but good. He had wrecked the plans of the Moulan Tribes several times and slain many high-grade Moulan spell warriors. If he were to come across Divine Sage Zhong, he feared that the Divine Sage would definitely go after him.

With that thought, Han Li didn’t delay and decided to take advantage of the fact that the two had yet to detect him and Violet Spirit. In a blur, he arrived at Violet Spirit’s side and held his hands in an incantation gesture. A layer of azure light then appeared above their heads and caused them to disappear from sight.

The two streaks of light passed the mountain Han Li where was concealed.

Han Li was able to see the deathly pale expression that Ancestor Linghu wore. Then, he glanced at a place three hundred meters behind them and narrowed his eyes.

“Where do you think you’re going? What? Don’t you want to be with your companion? Tch tch , your cultivation is quite high and your primal souls are exceptionally profound. They will make great offerings to this Lord. How could I possibly let you escape? This time, there will be no further surprises and you will obediently fall into my grasp.”

The voice howled with laughter and spoke with a tone of audacity. These words shook the world nearby, guaranteeing that all cultivators within five kilometers could hear it.

Afterwards, a line of black light strangely appeared where Han Li was staring.

The black line intermittently flickered, closing the distance toward the two fleeing cultivators with each reappearance. A short moment later, it was only two hundred meters away from them.

At that moment, a silhouette could be seen from within the black radiance. Although it appeared vague, Han Li hastily focused his attention on it. As a result of some sort of unknown technique, Han Li wasn’t able to see the figure’s cultivation with his spiritual sense. He was only able to see his vague figure. However, his figure appeared rather familiar to Han Li and after a moment of thought, Han Li recognized him, much to his shock.

‘Marquis Nanlong? How can he be here? And there seems to be something different about him.’ Han Li was shaken with bewilderment. Unknown to him, the person before him was the devil possessed Marquis Nanlong.

Although Han Li didn’t know that a devil soul had possessed his body and he was no longer the original Marquis Nanlong, the overwhelming devilish Qi emitted from his body and his audacity to pursue Ancestor Linghu and the Grand Elder of the Masked Moon Sect was clearly bizarre and out of character.

At that moment, Marquis Nanlong reappeared in his black light only a hundred meters away from the two. He eerily laughed and the black light surrounding him ruptured. A ball of pitch-black devilish Qi wrapped around him and he disappeared in a flicker of black.

When Ancestor Linghu and the white-clothed woman saw that Marquis Nanlong had disappeared, they were greatly alarmed and came to a sudden stop. They each took action, with one person taking out a pitch-black mirror and the other brandishing a jade scepter, both of them covering themselves in a barrier of light.

Then, a black light shined not far away from them. Pitch-black devilish Qi suddenly spurted forth and instantly enveloped an area of over thirty meters. Marquis Nanlong’s figure could be vaguely seen from within it.

“You clearly know that you aren’t my match. Don’t do something so foolish as to resist me!” Marquis Nanlong sinisterly smiled from within the black Qi and he casually waved his hand before a loud bang sounded out. A black hand suddenly appeared out of nowhere and struck the white-clothed woman. Afterwards, she was repelled over twenty meters away within the barrier that formed from the mirror before managing to steady herself.

Ancestor Linghu’s pale complexion grew even more unsightly after seeing this.

With a harsh tone, Ancestor Linghu yelled, “What are you? Not only have you possessed Fellow Daoist Nanlong’s body, but you dared to devour the primal soul of our fellow cultivator. Do you truly believe that there is no match for you within Devilfall Valley? There are several tens of Nascent Soul cultivators that have entered Devilfall Valley. No matter how powerful you are, you will find it difficult to escape death.”

Marquis Nanlong show no fear, only to respond with a sinister grin, “Several tens? Haha! Fantastic! I originally believed there were but a few humans in this valley. But there are actually so many Nascent Souls for me to devour, so I’d better finish up here and go and retrieve them. With so many Nascent Souls devoured, my soul power will mostly recover!”

Then with a huge bang, black Qi instantly ruptured and scattered. A silhouette clad in black Qi blurred as it shot towards Ancestor Linghu, leaving afterimages in his wake.

Chapter 854: An Alarming Surprise

As the flood dragon’s roar faded away, its image spiralled once more in the air before disappearing into Han Li’s back. Crimson light glowed behind him as the image of a three-inch-long crimson flood dragon began to roam across his body with a vivid lifelike nature.

Han Li’s body began to pulse with crimson light and thumb-sized sparkling crimson scales appeared all over him. Following a sharp pain from the top of his head, a small scarlet horn appeared, and his hands turned incredibly hard and his fingers became pointed and incisively sharp.

At first glance, Han Li’s new form appeared similar to that of the Elder Devil trapped in the sword formation. However, Han Li’s face remained human and the scales were only present on the rest of his body. As for the Elder Devil’s head, both of its heads appeared malevolent and had purple scales. Han Li’s use of the Spirit Subjugation Talisman had also boosted his true essence with the power of the flood dragon’s soul and raised his cultivation to the border between the early and mid Nascent Soul stages.

With his body glowing with both azure and red light, he grabbed the Blood Devil Sword with both his hands and poured the entirety of his magic power into it. The sword began to intensely tremble and violently pulsed with crimson light before expanding to three meters in length, filling the air with the putrid smell of blood. As for Han Li’s red horn, it glowed a brilliant crimson as a result of using the power of the flood dragon’s soul to its greatest extent.

With the minor Elder Devil trapped inside the sword formation, Han Li had resolved himself to prevent the main Elder Devil from rescuing his counterpart and fusing into one to bring forth an even greater adversary.

But with the main devil’s speed, it would arrive before the sword formation had closed on the minor devil and finished it off. Han Li’s only choice was be to personally slay the minor devil. Once this was done, he would flee, as there was no way he could withstand the might of the main Elder Devil.

Although there would be dire consequences from using the Blood Devil Sword, including great damage to his true essence, Han Li had already decided that he wouldn’t be involved in this battle much longer. With the minor devil slain, he would immediately flee and let the other cultivators deal with the stronger devil. Otherwise, he might experience permanent damage to his cultivation.

Given that he would have slain one of the devils by himself, the other cultivators surely wouldn’t have any complaints.

But at that moment, the Blood Devil Sword seemed to be insatiable. In the blink of an eye, it had already consumed a majority of what Han Li’s cultivation could offer. The sword’s crimson light continuously pulsed and now extended to over twenty meters in length and condensed an even more powerful aura, much to Han Li’s shock.

When the minor Elder Devil saw this, he rigidly stared at the light extending from the sword and a trace of fear appeared on his face. He wasn’t able to keep his calm and his ghost head harshly shouted, “Are you seeking your own death? For a human cultivator to use a sacred tool of our Holy Realm without regard - are you thinking of turning into a devil?”

Han Li coldly smiled and simply continued to pour spiritual power into the sword while ignoring him.

The devil grew furious as this. Knowing that Han Li intended on taking his life, his expression turned gloomy and his body began to glow with crimson light. With one of his hands acting as a blade, he severed one of his arms. The wound was as sleek as a mirror and didn’t leak even a drop of blood.

In the moment the arm was severed, he grabbed it with another arm and spat several mouthfuls of blood essence onto it as he muttered an ancient incantation. The severed arm immediately shined with crimson light and underwent a series of warping distortions before forming a sword that resembled the Blood Devil Sword.

The sword was made of sleek bone and was covered in pitch-black devilish Qi. With a single wave, threads of devilish Qi surged around it. The Elder Devil then brought the sword in front of him and began to pour the entirety of his body’s devilish Qi into the sword, causing it to surge with black light.

Han Li was somewhat surprised when he saw this, but killing intent quickly flooded his mind. Although he didn’t know the might of this grotesquely formed sword, he couldn’t afford to underestimate it in the slightest given its bizarre method of creation. He had to strike before the devil could make full use of the bone sword.

Having come to this conclusion, Han Li ceased pouring magic power into the Blood Devil Sword. Then with his hands holding onto the trembling hilt, he fiercely cut down towards the Elder Devil within the sword formation.

A crimson thirty-meter-long swordlight cleaved downward towards the Aureate Sword Formation.

Before the swordlight even arrived, the Elder Devil was submerged in the scent of blood released by the swordlight. The air around the sword formation began to tremble and space even began to distort as an indescribable vibration shook their surroundings.

The Elder Devil was overwhelmed with shock as this was clearly a display of the sword’s full power. If he remembered correctly, tools from the Holy Realm were only able to be used at half strength by humans. ‘Could it be that this increase in strength has something to do with his transformed state?’ Although the devil had experienced many battles against the ancient cultivators, he had never experienced something as inconceivable as the Spirit Subjugation Talisman.

But now that his life was at risk, the devil had no choice but to raise the partially charged bone sword to meet the incoming strike, both his heads loudly screaming. A black beam that was only half the size of the descending crimson light shot out from the bone sword to meet the oncoming streak of crimson radiance.

Crimson and black light overlapped as waves of Qi surged from the point of contact while a boom shook the nearby air.

Senior Martial Brother Cheng was blown back a dozen steps before being able to stabilize himself. As for Han Li, he drew support from his increased cultivation and merely blurred half a step back before steadying himself. The Elder Devil, however, was unaffected by the wave. He simply looked at the confrontation of sword light up above him with a nervous expression.

A scene that surprised both Han Li and the Devil Soul occurred. After the wave blew across them, a fist-sized jet-black ball strangely appeared in place of the overlapping swordlights. The ball quickly warped in shape and in the blink of an eye, it lengthened to fifteen meters long and a meter wide, stretching over the sword formation.

Before Han Li understood what was happening, a large expanse of rainbow light appeared from the pitch-black object.

Because of the rainbow light's lightning-fast appearance and its close proximity, the minor Elder Devil and Han Li were both enveloped by the rainbow light. Afterwards, a huge attractive force pulled them toward the black object. Senior Martial Brother Cheng fortunately managed to avoid it, having been blown back a dozen steps by the initial force.

‘Not good! It’s a spatial tear!’ Han Li realized what had happened and terror filled his mind as he attempted to break free of the rainbow light.

But when Han Li attempted to utilize his magic power, his expression blanched. All of the magic power in his body had completely disappeared.

Han Li broke out in a cold sweat at this discovery. Soon to be engulfed by the spatial tear, he beckoned to the Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords comprising the Aureate Sword Formation in a panic. The minor Elder Devil also found himself without any power to resist the spatial tear and revealed terror on both of his faces.

As the rainbow light pulled Han Li and the Elder Devil into the spatial tear, they weren’t able to offer the slightest resistance. Then a clear ring sounded out from the formation and over a hundred streaks of golden sword light shot off in meter-long gold-red streaks towards the spatial tear.

At that same moment, a violent and sharp explosion erupted from nearby as a ball of black devilish flame flickered and teleported into the vicinity of the spatial tear. Devilish flame surged and was promptly extinguished, revealing a towering figure reminiscent of a divine devil.

When the newly arrived Elder Devil saw that his counterpart was being dragged into the spatial tear, he felt both fury and alarm. As he floated nearby, not daring to enter the range of the spatial tear, he spotted the last of the Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords that were flying towards Han Li and instantly grabbed at the air in their direction. A huge devilish hand appeared above the flying swords and reached out to grab them.

The swords released a clear ring and immediately swerved, avoiding the hand and shooting straight towards the spatial tear. However, two of the swords were too slow and were grabbed by the devilish hand, rendering them immobile.

At that moment, a purple ball of flame shrieked from an unknown place and instantly flew into the spatial tear as well.

The giant Elder Devil was stunned and thought to do something else when the spatial tear blurred several times and quickly shrunk in size before disappearing without a trace.

All that remained nearby was Senior Martial Brother Cheng and the giant Elder Devil.

The Elder Devil glanced in the direction that the spatial tear disappeared from and his expression wavered. Then, he turned to look at Senior Martial Brother Cheng and a savage expression brimming with hostility appeared on his face.

Senior Martial Brother Cheng was alarmed and hastily used his yellow flying sword to protect himself as he slowly withdrew, screaming curses in his heart. He unconsciously glanced around him at that moment only to reveal an expression of delight at what he discovered.

Someone from amongst a group of green-robed cultivators spoke from three hundred meters away, “Yi! Isn’t this Fellow Daoist Cheng? What are you doing here? And what is this devilish monster?”

A green-robed old man glanced at the two-headed six-armed giant Elder Devil with shock. This old man was the Controlling Spirit Sect’s Grand Elder Dongmen Tu, and the three behind him were the Nascent Soul cultivators formed from Elemental Spirit Nascents.

“That’s right, I would like some answers as well!” A gloomy voice sounded out immediately after followed by a dozen black-robed cultivators appearing, the Ghost Spirit Sect Disciples. The speaker was the Ghost Spirit Sect’s Elder Zhong.

These two groups of cultivators saw that spatial tear disappear and all of them revealed an expression of shock.

Senior Martial Brother Cheng bitterly smiled and could only muster the strength to say, “It is too hard to explain. Let’s first deal with this monster first. Be extremely careful. This devil is immensely powerful. A moment of carelessness will result in death.”

Dongmen Tu and Elder Zhong glanced at one another with puzzled expressions. The cultivators following them then immediately surrounded the ten meter tall devil from a distance.

The Elder Devil’s two ghost heads slowly turned around to examine the human cultivators that surrounded him.

One of the faces sneered and emitted dense killing intent. As for the other face, it wore a mysterious smile containing a trace of derision.

Without saying a word, he raised his hands to the sky and summoned four huge, black blades of light into his hands. With a faint tremble, the huge blades released deafening shrieks.

When Senior Martial Brother Cheng saw this familiar scene, his expression grew unsightly.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Boring

Chapter 862: Feeding the Core

When Senior Martial Brother Cheng heard Lu Luo, he was stunned. He hastily examined Han Li’s inner Qi with his spiritual sense and saw that Han Li had truly entered mid Nascent Soul stage, much to his shock.

“I knew that with your quick wits, you would’ve quickly discovered it. I did indeed come across a fortunate encounter inside Devilfall Valley and bitterly cultivated to enter the next stage. As a result, I was able to enter mid Nascent Soul stage after such a short amount of time, something that even I hadn’t expected. But if I hadn’t known that you two were protecting Wan’er, I would’ve spent my many years trapped inside the pocket dimension with worry on my mind, preventing me from wholeheartedly cultivating. My progress is much in thanks to you two as well.”

Han Li then saluted the two and uttered his thanks.

“What is Junior Martial Brother saying? Since I am Sister Nangong’s sworn brother, it is only natural that I look after her. And it's not like we did much with regards to that. To our shame, she is still trapped in ice!”

“Junior Martial Brother Han reached mid-Nascent Soul stage in less than three hundred years of cultivation. Such an announcement would shake the entirety of the Heavenly South. Let alone late Nascent Soul stage, it is highly possible that Junior Martial Brother could reach the Deity Transformation stage!”

Lu Luo words were filled with admiration. There were only a sparse few characters in history that had progressed at the same speed as Han Li.

Speed on this level no longer had anything to do with cultivation aptitude and most likely came from luck and destiny.

Of course, Han Li simply responded with a few humble words before changing the topic and asking about what had happened after he disappeared in Devilfall Valley. The information he acquired straight from someone who witnessed the battle was far better than whatever was heard from rumors.

When the old man heard Han Li, he bitterly smiled.

After Han Li was swallowed by the spatial tear, the other Elder Devil was thrown into a fury. Just as Senior Martial Brother Cheng thought that his life was forfeit, the other cultivators had arrived.

Although the newly arrived cultivators had joined hands with Wei Wuya, they were still unable to deal with the two-headed four-armed Elder Devil. But just as these cultivators were about to be put in crisis, the Moulan had finally arrived.

With both sides joining hands, they trapped the devil. In the battle that followed, Spell Warrior Le summoned the Moulan Sacred Bird and they were able to grievously wound the devil. The Moulan Divine Sage Zhong was able to cut off one of the devil’s heads. But in the end, the Elder Devil managed to escape.

However, there were many Nascent Soul cultivators that perished in the battle. Nangong Wan’s Senior Martial Sister in particular suffered in the Elder Devil’s last struggle; he turned her body and Nascent Soul into ash with a ball of black devilflame. As for Ancestor Linghu, he ended up somewhat better. Although his body was destroyed, his Nascent Soul managed to survive.

But none were as unfortunate as the Ghost Spirit Sect Elder Zhong who had his Nascent Soul seized and devoured by the Elder Devil. As a result, all the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators that entered the valley perished, apart from a few Core Formation cultivators, much to the shock of everyone.

As for everything that happened afterwards, it was mostly as Huang Yuanming had mentioned. According to ancient records, devils couldn’t remain in the mortal realm for long, and none took the risk to chase it down. But against everyone’s expectations, the devil managed to persist in this world through some unknown method and went on a killing spree in the Heavenly South, killing cultivators and devouring their Nascent Souls. With fury and rage built up, a hunting party was launched.

When Han Li heard this, he frowned and said, “I’ve heard a few rumors with regards to the hunting party’s battle with the devil. But is it true that two of the Great cultivators and the Moulan Divine Sage weren’t able to slay the devil? Given your identities, you should know the truth of the matter.” With that said, Han Li’s expression turned heavy.

“We didn’t participate in the campaign against the devil, but according to the information that the alliance sent, the Elder Devil received grievous life-threatening injuries, but it still managed to escape through some strange secret technique. Master Sunreach and the others attempted to give chase to eradicate the devil, but they gave up the case at the border of the Moulan Plains out of fear of provoking the Soaring Tribes. However, many years passed without the devil being sighted in the Heavenly South. And given how calm the Moulan Plains are, if the devil hasn’t succumbed to its wounds, it should have crossed the Moulan Plains into the Great Jin.”

“The Great Jin Empire?” Han Li couldn’t help but reveal shock.

Senior Martial Brother Cheng and Lu Luo saw the surprise in Han Li’s words, but they tactfully dropped the subject. After all, Han Li current abilities and cultivation were beyond the two so they couldn’t help but feel a bit of admiration for him.

They chatted for a moment more before Han Li eventually mentioned how he found a cure for Nangong Wan in Devilfall Valley and wished to make an attempt to dissolve her curse.

The two were overjoyed when they heard this. If Nangong Wan recovered, the might of their Drifting Cloud Sect would increase once more. They hastily concluded their chat and personally guided Han Li to the restricted area.

Senior Martial Brother Cheng and Lu Luo stood at the entrance to the restricted area and personally kept watch, allowing Han Li to take care in dissolving the Soul Seal Curse. He uttered a quick word of thanks before approaching the stone gate.

Han Li glanced at the gate and saw that the restrictions hadn’t been further activated since the last time it had been opened. It appeared that Senior Martial Brother Cheng and Lu Luo had only used their spiritual sense to see how Nangong Wan was doing inside, much to Han Li’s satisfaction.

With his hand forming an incantation gesture, a series of spell seals flew out and struck the stone door, causing it to open with groans. Han Li then silently walked in with an odd expression, followed by the gate closing shut.

The room was exactly the same as in the past. It was completely clean because the restriction placed, and the moonlight stones embedded in the ceiling were as bright as ever. Nangong Wan’s child form was still sealed in the sparkling wall of ice with her eyes closed and a pale face.

With sadness across Han Li’s face, he took several steps towards the ice wall and stopped three meters away. Then, he stared at Nangong Wan’s deathly pale face and a complicated expression appeared on his face.

An unknown amount of time passed before he finally let out a long sigh. He then slapped his storage pouch and summoned a jade box into his hand.

He lightly tapped the top of the box with his other hand and it suddenly flung open, revealing a thumb-sized scarlet demon core that pulsed with red light. It appeared mysteriously alluring.

Han Li squinted his eyes as he examined the demon core before suddenly opening his mouth and spitting out an azure mist onto the demon core. Afterwards, he tossed the demon core and had it hover in the air towards the ice.

At that moment, he muttered a series of incantations and struck the ice wall with a spell seal. In a flash of blue light, the azure mist and the demon core phased into the thick ice and flew into Nangong Wan’s lips.

Han Li then pointed at Nangong Wan and she stiffly opened her mouth like a puppet, allowing the demon core to fly into her mouth. Suddenly, Nangong Wan’s deathly pale face began to shine with a faint layer of red light, but her eyes remained completely shut.

Han Li let out a deep breath, knowing that the matter couldn’t be rushed. Even if the demon core was truly effective, the curse wouldn’t be dissolved in a few short months. Han Li stayed there regardless and simply stood in front of the ice wall, staring at Nangong Wan in silence. For some unknown reason, the breathtaking memory of when he first saw Nangong Wan appeared in his mind.

Time slowly passed by as Han Li stood still without moving an inch.

After a long while, Han Li calmly walked out from the secluded room and sealed the restrictions once more.

Still guarding the cave on the outside, Senior Martial Brother and Lu Luo asked a few questions of concern, but Han Li simply forced a smile and said he would have to wait a few days and see whether or not the Soul Seal Curse was dissolved. Han Li then bid his farewell for the time being and flew back to his cave residence, tired from his rushed journey back to the Dreamcloud Mountains. In any case, there was always time for a proper discussion in the coming days.

As mentioned by his senior martial brothers, his cave residence had remained untouched under their strict order. As for his concubine, Mu Peiling, she just had continuously resided in the mountain neighboring his cave residence and was shown much consideration by his two senior martial brothers. She had now reached False Core stage and was only on the verge of Core Formation.

Han Li felt his heart stir at this news and recalled the details of the Copulative Essence Arts [1] .

Han Li had many medicines that could increase the odds of a successful Core Formation, and given her exceptional aptitude, she had a seventy percent likelihood of safely forming a core if he wholehearted assisted her.

However, he didn’t expect that he would encounter a chance to breakthrough the bottleneck to mid Nascent Soul stage without her in Devilfall Valley. He had originally planned on having Mu Peiling cultivate this technique for several tens of years before he would claim her vital yin, but that plan had fallen through. He could also use the Copulative Essence Arts to breakthrough the bottleneck to late Nascent Soul stage, but he would need a deeper mastery of the technique to use it, not to mention that the woman must also be at late Core Formation stage as well.

Under normal circumstances, it was possible that he wouldn’t be able to reach the peak of the Nascent Soul stage in even three hundred years. And during this time, he would have to properly nurture Mu Peiling as she cultivated the Copulative Essence arts. As the Copulative Essence Arts wasn’t anywhere close to being a top grade technique, she wouldn’t be able to reach late Core Formation stage in a short amount of time unless he provided her sufficient medicine pills.

With that thought, Han Li arrived in front of his cave residence. When he saw the sea of mist in front of it, he smiled and parted it with a wave of his sleeve before calmly walking inside.

[1]. First mentioned in Chapter 645: Copulative Essence Arts. A technique that allows a male cultivator to breakthrough a bottleneck through copulation with a Core Formation stage woman. Can only be used once.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Lannis

Chapter 876: Acquiring An Island

The others raised no objections to Devil Concord’s suggestion to move the discussion elsewhere, and the group headed towards Spirit Turtle Island.

Han Li asked Master Sunreach for a sealed room to spend the night meditating as they waited for the other two to retrieve the formation plate from the spell formation masters.

Then, on the morning of the next day, Han Li received a sound transmission talisman from Master Sunreach and promptly appeared at the main hall.

Han Li walked in with a raised brow, noticing that the three great cultivators were already seated and talking to one another. When Wei Wuya saw Han Li arrive, he called out to him and summoned a faint red jade slip on the table with a flip of his hand. “Fellow Daoist Han, please take a seat. This is the location that you must place the formation plate according to our research of the sealing formation.”

“Oh! Let me take a look.” With a wave, the jade slip shot into his hand and then he took a seat before immersing his spiritual sense into it.

A short moment later, Han Li’s face stirred and he withdrew his spiritual sense from the jade slip, wearing a gloomy expression on his face.

Han Li tossed the jade slip back on the table and raised his head, coldly saying, “Fellow Daoists, do you plan on having me go on a one-way journey to place the formation plate so deep into the abyss?”

Devil Concord calmly replied, “How can Fellow Daoist Han say that? Although the location for the formation plate is a bit deep, with the Divine Devilbane Lightning protecting you, it shouldn’t pose a problem.”

“Is that so?” Han Li glanced at Devil Concord and said with an angry tone, “Does Brother Concord believe my reserves of Divine Devilbane Lightning are infinite? Or do you simply wish for me to not return after I place down the formation plate?”

“You mean to say that you don’t have enough Divine Devilbane Lightning to last the trip back?” Wei Wuya asked with a frown. “From what I remember, Fellow Daoist Han controlled quite a large quantity of lightning during his battle with the Elder Devil. It shouldn’t pose much of a problem.”

“Could it be that you didn’t delve too far deep into the devilish Qi?” Han Li asked with an odd expression.

“Yi!” Wei Wuya yelped. “Fellow Daoist Han means to say...”

Devil Concord’s eyes flickered but he remained silent. As for Master Sunreach, he lowered his head in thought.

Han Li knitted his fingers together and held them at his chest before he explained with an indifferent tone, “At a certain depth it is clear to see that the devilish nature of the Qi becomes even stronger and it exhausts the Divine Devilbane Lightning at a greater speed. I’ve reached this conclusion after delving a kilometer deep into the abyss. Although I do possess a bit of Divine Devilbane Lightning, I will not be able to delve ten kilometers deep into the devilish Qi and make it back.”

Wei Wuya tensely frowned and turned to Master Sunreach, asking, “So it was like that? Brother Sunreach, you delved the deepest into the devilish Qi out of the three of us. Is this true?”

“It’s true,” Master Sunreach sighed and nodded in agreement. “When I delved deeper into the devilish Qi using my secret techniques, I felt my magic power drain at a faster rate. I originally believed that Han Li wouldn’t notice and was thinking about warning him.”

When Devil Concord heard this, his expression changed and he said, “In that case, our original plan to have a cultivator enter the devilish Qi depths with devil warding treasures would fail. Although they would be safe at the beginning, there is danger of becoming corrupted once they delve too deep.”

“That’s right,” Master Sunreach said with a wry smile, “That’s why I wasn’t very interested in that plan. But since Fellow Daoist Han was still missing at the time, I didn’t raise any objections as there were no other alternatives.”

Han Li observed their tone of voice and expressions with indifference, but he grew somewhat gloomy. He was unable to tell whether the three truly knew of it or if they decided to keep the matter hidden. Regardless, he wouldn’t easily agree to them.

Then, the room was filled with silence.

It was clear that it would be a death sentence to have someone place a formation plate this deep in the depths of the Devilish Qi. Telling Han Li to do it for a virtuous cause would be an even less likely matter.

Although the four present realized that half the Heavenly South would be affected by the release of the devilish Qi, none of them were interested in sacrificing themselves in preventing this as they already cultivated to such a high stage. If worst came to worst, they would flee from the Heavenly South altogether. They will be able to easily find a place for themselves in the world with their level of cultivation.

And apart from Han Li, there was no one else that could delve deep enough to place the formation plate, causing the three great cultivators to look at each other in dismay.

Then, Han Li’s eyes wandered for a moment before speaking with a relaxed voice, “I am also aware that this matter is quite serious and that you all find yourselves facing a dilemma. As such, I have an idea I wish to try.”

When Master Sunreach heard this, he hastily said, “What’s your idea? Please, tell us.”

Wei Wuya and Devil Concord felt this spirits roused and hastily turned to Han Li.

“It’s rather simple. I believe I am able to reach the designated location for the formation plate with the Divine Devilbane Lightning, but I will not have enough to safely return. As such, you will need to hand over the devil warding treasures you’ve gathered over to me so that I will last longer in the devilish Qi. However, since this method does pose quite a bit of danger to me...” With that said, Han Li paused as if hesitant to continue.

With joy on his face, Wei Wuya hastily said, “That will be no problem! So long as you can place down the formation plate, we’ll lend Fellow Daoist Han all of the devil warding treasures we’ve acquired.”

“Of course, we won’t have you brave this grave danger for nothing.” Master Sunreach suddenly smiled at Devil Concord and said, “Brother Concord, what do you say?”

Devil Concord was stunned when he heard this, but after some hesitation, he nodded. “Indeed, if you accomplish this, we plan on handing over one of these islands over to Fellow Daoist Han.”

“You would present one of the islands to me?” Han Li’s narrowed his eyes.

“That’s right,” Master Sunreach said with a friendly voice, “To tell the truth, we planned on dividing the islands between seven great sects, but a majority of those sects belonged to our three superpowers. There is one island that is difficult to divide. We originally planned on handing it over to Fellow Daoists Long Han and Feng Bing [1] , but it turned out that the two are in seclusion. As such we’ve decided to hand it over to a small unremarkable sect. Now that Fellow Daoist Han is here to brave the danger, we will hand over the island to your Drifting Cloud Sect. Surely no will raise any complaints over this.”

“Is that so?” Han Li said with amazement. After all, from what he heard, not only did the islands have outstanding spirit veins, but they also have several rich spirit stone mines and other rarities.

After some thought, Han Li then worriedly asked, “Since the seven islands were a section of the grand formation, won’t they sink back into the ocean when the formation is restored?”

“Don’t worry,” Wei Wuya answered, “The method we’re using to restore the formation differs from the original used to create the sealing formation. Naturally, we won’t waste the islands by having them sink back into the ocean. And the cultivators occupying the islands will also be duty bound to look after the sealing formation.”

After muttering to himself, Han Li replied, “Since you three have made such heavy promises, I’ll have to give it a try, but after this matter is settled, I don't wish to be further involved in this.”

Wei Wuya heartily laughed and agreed, “Placing the formation plate is already considered a great service. Leave the rest to us.”

Although Master Sunreach and Devil Concord both had different ideas originally, they grew at ease for the time being.

At that moment, Wei Wuya took out a white circular object from his storage pouch and handed it over to Han Li.

Han Li took a glance at it. It was a palm-sized formation plate that was meticulously carved from white jade. It flickered with spiritual light and was engraved with several complex talisman characters.

Han Li’s hand glowed with azure light for a moment, transferring it into his storage pouch in the blink of an eye.

“Alright, now everything is ready except for one last thing,” Wei Wuya said with a pleased expression, “When does Brother Han plan on taking action?”

“Naturally, the quicker the better,” Han Li grimly answered, “I already rested the night and restored the magic power I earlier consumed. If you Fellow Daoists have the devil warding treasures on hand, I will place the formation plate right away. Who knows what could happen to the devilish Qi if we delay?”

The three great cultivators raised no objections to Han Li’s suggestion. As for the devil warding treasures they managed to difficulty acquire, they all carried them on hand and each took them out, giving them all to Han Li: a jade scepter with a flood dragon head, a fire-red trigram mirror, a set of sparkling gold armor and a small black flag.

Han Li promptly tested the efficacy of the four treasures and found that they were exceptional. Three of the treasures were Yang flame treasures and would prove very useful in dealing with the devilish Qi. As for the black flag, it was a famous Devil Dao treasure. According to Devil Concord, the flag was originally used to ghostly Yin winds, but it is also capable of absorbing devilish Qi. Han Li looked at the flag with doubt and fiddled with it before finally placing it in his storage pouch, much to the shock of Devil Concord.

After Han Li put away the treasures, the cultivators left Master Sunreach’s cave residence and head out in the direction of the giant whirlpool. Four hours later, Han Li appeared alone at the bottom of the whirlpool.

When Han Li looked at the devilish Qi below the light barrier, he silently made a fist and thunder rang out, instantly covering his body in several dense arcs of golden lightning, weaving a net of lightning around his light barrier.

As Han Li looked at the golden lightning, his mouth twitched, forming a trace of ridicule.

Despite how cunning the three great cultivators were, they couldn’t have imagined that he originally possessed seventy-two flying swords created from Gold Lightning Bamboo. According to his estimates, he would have enough to make two trips and still have enough to spare. This task didn’t pose the slightest danger to him at all.

On one hand, he had done this to haggle over the rewards as Master Sunreach had previously informed him that there were possible benefits. On the other hand, he had done this to avoid the three from realizing how much Divine Devilbane Lightning he possessed. In the future, the only things that could pose a threat against Han Li in the Heavenly South would be the three great cultivators and the Moulan Divine Sages; he had no choice but to deceive them.

[1]. The strongest cultivator pair in the Heavenly Dao Alliance. They are mid-Nascent Soul stage Dao Companions that can match a late-Nascent Soul cultivator when joined together.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

Chapter 877: Ruined Stone Tablet

Like the last time Han Li delved into the abyss of devilish Qi, he was protected in a net of Divine Devilbane Lightning. Soon, the rings of thunder grew softer as he delved deeper and soon the golden lightning could no longer be seen.

On the surface of the ocean, the three great cultivators were talking with one another as Han Li delved deeper.

“Brother Sunreach, do you feel that Fellow Daoist Han truly doesn’t have enough Divine Devilbane Lightning to make the entire trip? Will his lightning be consumed too quickly to have any remaining for the trip back?” Wei Wuya asked with his hands behind his back.

“Does Brother Wei mean to say that my previous words were false?” Master Sunreach’s expression sank and he appeared displeased.

Wei Wuya chuckled and said, “Please don’t misunderstand me, I didn’t mean that at all. I simply asked because I felt that Fellow Daoist Han agreed far too easily.”

Master Sunreach’s expression relaxed and he said, “If that’s the case, I’m not too sure myself. However, I consumed greater amounts of magic power the deeper I delved into the abyss of devilish Qi. I imagine one would need an astonishing amount of Divine Devilbane Lightning if they wish to make a whole round trip. I don’t believe Fellow Daoist Han can accomplish this with his lightning alone. Perhaps he has something else that can withstand the devilish Qi for a time.”

“That is quite possible. After all, there are an endless number of mysteries and wonders in the cultivation world. But regardless of how it is said, it will be good if this calamity could be smoothly resolved.” Wei Wuya spoke with a smile and took a glance at Devil Concord. The large black-robed man had his arms crossed as he glanced down at the whirlpool, his face emotionless as he remained silent.

For the time being, silence filled the air.

...

Ten kilometers deep into the devilish Qi, a light barrier surging with golden lightning was floating motionlessly. Han Li was inside it, solemnly reading through the jade slip that detailed where the formation plate should be placed.

A short moment later, Han Li withdrew his spiritual sense from the jade slip and looked around. His surroundings were completely devoid of light, not surprising as he already reached the farthest depths of the devilish Qi abyss.

Han Li frowned and opened his mouth, spitting out an inch-long golden sword.

In a flicker of golden light, the small sword flew out of the light barrier with a layer of thin lightning covering the body of the blade. It circled around him before revolving above his head, turning into a strange inch-large golden ring of light.

Han Li formed an incantation gesture and pointed at the ring of light above his head, ordering it to suddenly stop and shoot out in a streak of golden light. He then closely followed after it in a blur.

He flew a meter across the abyss before the small golden sword suddenly shot downward and released a muffled bang. The flying sword had pierced into something.

A trace of joy appeared on Han Li’s face and arrived three meters above where the sword had landed. In the pitch black darkness, all he could see was the faint light of the small sword flickering with lightning. It had pierced into a huge flat rock.

Han Li muttered to himself for a moment and pressed one of his hands against his light barrier. The net of lightning surrounding the barrier suddenly surged with blinding light and released several dense bolts of golden lightning that quickly revolved in the nearby area, turning into several golden pythons. As a result, the golden pythons cleanly swept away all the devilish Qi in the nearby area, illuminating the huge rock underneath.

Han Li examined it for a moment and revealed shock. This wasn’t a rock, but rather the floor of an altar. It appeared to stretch beyond the range of the golden lightning.

He was amazed. The area that the formation masters wished to bury the formation plate was unexpectedly remarkable.

Han Li commanded the golden pythons to quickly envelop the rest of the altar, revealing its general appearance.

It was a square building that stretched out about a hundred meters. All of the characteristics and engravings on the stone walls illustrated that it was a building created by cultivators from antiquity.

After Han Li viewed his surroundings, he waved to the sword embedded in the floor and it returned to his sleeve in a golden streak. He then flew towards the center of the building and after a short moment, it began to flicker with white light.

His heart stirred at the sight and he sped up, eventually clearly seeing what laid at its center. It was a shattered stone tablet. Only a small portion of its foundation remained standing upright with the rest of its fragments scattered around.

Han Li’s eyes wandered around the stone tablet as he observed it. Although it was shattered, he was able to see a few worn talisman characters that he couldn’t understand. It was unknown what kind of material it was carved from as it would only occasionally sparkle with a faint white light.

‘Could it be a rare material on par with the Gold Lightning Bamboo?’ Han Li thought. Soon, he reached out towards a fist-sized piece of the stone tablet and his hand glowed with azure light before summoning it into his grasp.

The stone piece was grey and unremarkable. If it weren’t for the traces of spiritual light, Han Li wouldn’t have found anything particular about it.

Han Li looked at it several more times and his brow stirred before he suddenly exerted great strength into his grasp.

As a result, a strange scene occurred. The stone wasn’t crushed to powder as Han Li thought. Instead, it flickered with white light and suddenly turned soft, allowing his fingers to sink deep into the stone.

Han Li felt his heart jump. He frowned and asked Monarch Soul Divergence, “Senior Soul Divergence, do you know what this is?”

“No, I’ve never seen it before,” Monarch Soul Divergence said with a lazy tone, “But this is no surprise. There were so many rare materials used during ancient times, it is impossible for someone to know them all. You may as well let me research that piece. I am idle and have little better to do.” Then without another thought, Han Li tossed the stone piece into the bamboo tube behind him.

Light flashed from the bamboo tube and a mist of white light sucked the strange stone inside of it.

Han Li quickly turned his attention to the shattered stone tablet. It hadn't been long since it was shattered, and it appeared that when the spell formation was damaged, the stone tablet had shattered as well.

With that thought, Han Li collected the rest of the stone fragments in a sweep of azure light. He then flicked his fingers and launched over ten streaks of azure sword light at the stone foundation, wishing to take the rest of it with him.

A series of booms sounded out and to Han Li’s surprise, the sword Qi wasn’t able to cut through the stone. It didn’t seem to have any effect.

“How strange!” Han Li yelped in alarm and hesitated for a moment. He no longer paid attention to the rest of the stone tablet and launched several streaks of sword Qi in a different direction.

Although he had enough Divine Devilbane Lightning to sustain for a while longer, Han Li didn’t dare to linger too long in such a dangerous place and began to place down the formation plate.

A series of muffled explosions sounded out, followed by the appearance of a three-meter-deep hole at the side of the stone tablet.

With a wave of his hand, white light flickered and an exquisite formation plate appeared. Han Li shook his hand without the slightest hesitation and sent the formation plate into the hole in a streak of light.

Grimly staring at the formation plate, his two hands then formed a hand incantation and the formation plate began to shine with even greater light.

Soon, the formation plate released a clear ring and a thick beam of white light shot out towards the sky, only to disappear without a trace.

Han Li felt at ease. Since the formation plate was functioning as expected, he had clearly found the right place.

With that thought, Han Li swept up an azure gale with a wave of his sleeve, completely burying the hole with rocks. He then released a spell seal and muttered an incantation before melting the pile of rocks to seal the hole completely in a smooth layer. The hole now appeared as if it never existed.

Han Li walked around the large hole to make sure that nothing appeared out of the ordinary and he nodded with a satisfied expression.

With that done, he released several spell seals, striking the nearby golden lightning pythons. With pangs of thunder, the lightning pythons faded away into specks of light and the devilish Qi began to quickly roil as there was no longer anything holding it back.

Han Li pondered to himself before the lightning flashed around his light barrier, preparing to rush back up to the ocean surface.

At that moment, Monarch Soul Divergence’s voice echoed through his spiritual sense, “Youngster, wait a moment!”

Han Li stopped in surprise and asked, “What does Senior have to say?”

“Since this is the center of the sealing formation, it is also the densest area of devilish Qi, and since it has been suppressed since ancient times, it is possible several Devil Essence Diamonds have formed here. According to ancient records, they were a material used to refine precious Devil Dao treasures. You should see if you can find them nearby.”

“Devil Essence Diamonds?” An odd expression appeared on his face. Then after some thought, he slapped his storage pouch and took out a yellow jade scepter with a wolf’s head.

This was the ancient treasure that originally housed Silvermoon. Although its artifact spirit was missing, it was still capable of using simple earth movement techniques, but not to the superb skill that Silvermoon was capable of.

Translator's Thoughts

Chapter 880: The Grey Heron Tribe

A caravan of about thirty men were travelling down wilderness with grassland as far as the eye could see. There were eight carriages among them accompanied by young leather-clothed horsemen with a few of them only reaching the ages of twelve, but they all were in high spirits regardless.

At the very front of the caravan was an old man riding a fine yellow horse. He had sharp creases in his brow and dark-red skin. He also wore a fire-red fox hide cap, gorgeous robes, and a tri-colored embroidered belt that symbolized his position as the master of the group.

They were travelling through the north of the Endless Sky Plains, on their way to pay tribute to a temple belonging to the Soaring Tribes.

The Endless Sky Plains were what the Soaring Tribes called the Moulan Plains. This was due to Soaring Tribe’s belief that their patron god, the Endless Sky Beast, had protected them for generations.

Originally, the Soaring Tribes occupied the southern portion of the Endless Sky Plains, but ever since their victory in the war against the Moulan thirty years ago, they occupied the entirety of the plains, and their strength massively surged, leaving them without match in the area.

Of course, given the huge size of the Soaring Tribes, they consisted of countless smaller tribe divisions. Smaller tribes consisted of a hundred thousand men with the largest tribes reaching around a hundred million men. Because there were many men who won merits in the last war, many new tribes had emerged with a majority of them being quite insignificant, only numbering tens of thousand of men.

The master of the escort was named Ying Lu. He was the leader of a small tribe that had split off from a larger one. Although they were considered a tribe, they only consisted of about eighty thousand men. When he was young, he was a formidable warrior and struck down several small Moulan Tribes in the war, capturing many of their nobles in the process and earning his current rank. However, he was unable to withstand the ravages of time. With the addition of the toil he put his body through over the years, he now appeared elderly despite only being fifty years old.

Ying Lu looked to the blazing sun in the sky, noticing that it was noon before turning to look at the young man behind him. He sighed.

Regardless of how small a tribe was, they had to regularly present tribute to the Immortals in case they came across calamities or demon beasts. However, newly formed small tribes like their own were unable to call upon Immortals. Even the lowest grade Immortals were unwilling to watch over tribes as small as theirs. After all, it was better for an Immortal to join more prosperous tribes, granting them more resources to further their cultivation.

However, there are a few small tribes that had low grade Immortals, but these Immortals had originated from these tribes or their aptitude was too poor to join larger tribes.

As for Ying Lu’s Grey Heron Tribe, they didn’t have the opportunity to nurture an Immortal for themselves. Whenever something happened over the years, they could only hire the Immortals of neighboring tribes at great cost to assist them. Their price was extremely high and would only assist them a few times at the cost of the tribe’s revenue for half the year. As the tribe wasn’t wealthy to begin with, this cost had put them in a hard situation.

Fortunately, twenty years had passed and the Day of Spirit Release has finally come for their tribe once more. Ying Lu handled this with care and didn’t allow this opportunity to pass him. He promptly led several of the tribe disciples to the nearest Soaring Tribes Temple.

The Endless Sky Temples were originally established to honor their patron god, but after many years of development, they have become holy lands to the people of the Soaring Tribes, where low grade Immortals were fostered by the Soaring Tribes.

Every temple was managed by several high grade Immortals, responsible for imparting basic methods of cultivation. Once that was done, the lower aptitude cultivators were sent back to their tribes to receive their support there. As for the high aptitude cultivators, they were accepted as disciples by the high grade immortals and were personally nurtured. But before one could receive personal instruction from high grade Immortals, they must go through the Spirit Release Rites.

There were only about seventy Endless Sky Temples spread throughout the plains, but each of them were the heart of the regions they were located and had thousands of variously-sized tribes surrounding them.

Since there was only one temple in the region, the largest sects resided closest to it, and as a small sect, the Grey Heron Tribe resided in an area farther away. Their journey to the temple would take three months at the very least. Helpless, they could only depart four months ahead of time.

On the previous Day of Spirit Release, he had already established his tribe, but he wasn’t able to gather enough tribute for the temple so he could only watch the opportunity pass him by. As a result, Ying Lu was unwilling to allow this chance to miss his tribe again. He even reduced the rations of the tribe and cut on other costs for the sake of this day so they could acquire an Immortal for their tribe.

However, they had to bring the tribute through wide expanses of grassland, an extremely dangerous task for mortals like them. After all, the tribute consisted of materials useful towards Immortals and even more precious towards mortals. If they weren’t careful, they could be robbed, even by an Immortal. This was a common occurance whenever a Day of Spirit Release approached.

It was better for the tribes closer to the temple as none dared to be too imprudent in its proximity, but it proved extremely dangerous for tribes farther away.

It was once said that the tribute from a mid-grade tribe, a thousand year medicine herb, was leaked and made known to many. As a result, a high grade Immortal from a larger sect plundered it. Of course, the Immortals of the temple were angered by this and dispatched an Immortal to investigate this matter, but it was unknown if anything came of it.

With such events having happened, Ying Lu been extremely worried ever since he left his tribe. Although he was carrying the tribute, he didn’t have the protection of an Immortal.

As the Day of Spirit Release approached, Immortals from many tribes were occupied with matters from the temple. Even if one had spirit stones, the Immortals were too busy to accept. Occasionally, there would be wandering Immortals and the larger tribes nearby would rush to hire them at great cost. Weaker tribes couldn’t hope to compete.

With that thought, Ying Lu sighed and glanced behind him again.

Four of the eight carriages carried tribute, all of them pulled by the most meticulously chosen steeds in the tribe. These carriages were also crafted from the hardy red birch wood. Of course, to make sure that they wouldn’t catch any attention, the carriages’ exteriors were ragged and worn.

Even with these measures, they had encountered a small pack of feral wolves and nearly lost one of their members. In order to escape the wolves, they had to abandon the two slowest carriages. Although the two carriages didn’t carry anything particularly costly, they did hold enough food for two months. It seemed that they would have no choice but to make a temporary stop in two days. There should be a nearby valley where men rarely tread, but there may be some wild bison or other game to hunt.

With that thought, Ying Lu stroked the hardwood bow that hung from his saddle.

“Yi! What happened?” A young woman at Ying Lu’s side yelped in alarm. The woman was fifteen years old and was named Ying Shan. She was a relative of Ying Lu and was one of the few people in the tribe who possessed spirit roots. It was only natural for him to dote on her.

Ying Lu hastily raised his head in alarm and saw waves of azure light in some dense shrubbery ahead of him.

Ying Lu’s heart trembled. As the leader of his tribe, he was naturally familiar with the light released from Immortal techniques. Could it be they wished to act against a group as destitute as his?

Ying Lu’s heart sank and he raised his hand, ordering the group behind him to stop. When the others saw the azure light ahead of them, they instantly grew cautious from alarm.

Ying Lu firmly grasped onto his horse’s reins and had it come to a stop. He then began to think of a plan to defend themselves.

But after a short moment, Ying Lu felt that there was something amiss. The azure light in the shrubbery continuously flickered but there were no Immortals or any techniques that emerged from it.

Ying Lu’s eyes brightened and he hastily examined the shrubbery. The dense shrubbery were about as tall as a person and couldn’t be clearly seen through.

Ying Lu’s gaze wavered and he suddenly shouted, “Tu Meng! Go over there and take a look to see whether or not there is an Immortal there.”

“Yes, Tribe Elder!” A young man with a sturdy and formidable appearance descended from his horse and carefully approached the shrubbery that was sixty meters away from him. When the azure light was only twenty meters away, he hesitated and his feet came to a stop.

“May I ask for the name of the Immortal here? We are the Grey Heron Tribe and we wish to pay our respects in front of your true appearance.” The youth spoke with a clear tone of respect.

However, the light in the shrubbery continued to flicker and no response was given. Tu Meng couldn’t help but to look at Ying Lu.

Ying Lu lowered his head in thought for a moment before silently nodding. The youth then gathered a bit of courage and walked forward with silent steps. When he arrived in front of the shrubbery, he gritted his teeth and parted the wild grass in front of him.

Translator's Thoughts

Chapter 888: Agony Poison

Silvermoon immediately felt Han Li’s sudden movements and couldn’t help but ask, “Master! What happened?”

Han Li stroked his chin and muttered, “There are two cultivators that have stopped about five kilometers away: one at Core Formation stage and the other at Foundation Establishment stage. The aura of that Foundation Establishment cultivator seems familiar. How strange, he seems to be Feng Yue.”

After a moment of silence, Silvermoon asked, “Do you wish for me to use my artifact spirit body to observe them?”

“Forget it,” Han Li shook his head, “You haven’t yet recovered from your injuries. Even with my Foundation Establishment cultivation, I can still simply keep watch over their movements with my spiritual sense until they leave.”

Silvermoon didn’t raise any objections to his words. Then, Han Li closed his eyes and continued to sit in silence.

A while later, Han Li let out a yelp and shock appeared on his face. This time, Silvermoon tactfully remained silent as Han Li tightly frowned before having sudden changes of expression.

“Senior Soul Divergence, if I remembered correctly, you said there were many techniques to dissolve my baleful Qi. Is it true that most of these techniques are Buddhist?”

“That is true,” Monarch Soul Divergence lazily replied, “Confucians and Daoists also have many of their own techniques to dissolve baleful Qi, but none are as effective as Buddhist techniques.”

As Han Li’s expression wavered, he said, “Then is it true that the most obvious property of Buddhist techniques is that a majority of them release a seven-colored light when they are activated?”

“That is right. Why? Have you discovered something?” Monarch Soul Divergence asked with a curious tone.

Han Li lowered his head and muttered, “In that case, this person might be useful. This could be an opportunity.”

Monarch Soul Divergence grew somewhat annoyed that Han Li wouldn’t answer his question. Just as he thought to ask more about it, Han Li resolved himself and set forth, riding a magic tool out of his cave in an azure streak.

This action came as a surprise to Silvermoon and Monarch Soul Divergence. But after seeing Han Li act with such haste, they could only save their questions for later.

Han Li quickly arrived at a small forest rarely seen in the Endless Sky Plains. It spanned about half a kilometer and was made of sparse and short trees. At the center of the forest, there was a patch of empty land that spanned about thirty meters wide where the two previous cultivators resided.

The blue-robed cultivator was lying facedown on the ground. He was motionless and had a black bloodstain on his back. While it was unknown whether he was still alive, a gorgeous seven-colored light covered his body. There was also other person nearby, a purple-robed old man with eagle-shaped eyes. He was striking at the light barrier with a fire-red flying sword.

Although the seven-colored light barrier was unordinary, it had already begun to wildly shake and flash with light as it had no master controlling it.

Han Li didn’t conceal his sudden approach, alerting the purple-robed old man below.

In the old man’s shock, he swept his spiritual sense past Han Li and relaxed after finding that he was only a Foundation Establishment cultivator. The old man then surged with killing intent and raised his hand, launching a remarkable fast black streak at Han Li. It was a tri-pointed stake wrapped in black Qi.

Han Li coldly snorted and stroked the top of his head. Then, a black-green cloud flew out from it and transformed into a meter-long hand, swiping at the approaching black streak.

The purple-robed old man was shocked when he saw this. Before he realized what was happening, the tri-pointed stake was caught with ease and in an instant, he felt his connection severed. Then, the giant hand began to fly downwards.

In the old man’s shock, he flusteredly formed incantation gestures, ordering the red flying sword to protect him. But suddenly, the black-green hand disappeared and a second later, it reappeared three meters above him as a fist and fiercely smashed down upon him.

“Ah!” The purple-robed old man let out a miserable scream before he was pounded into a bloody mush.

Afterwards, the black-green fist unfolded back into a hand and swiped across the old man’s remains, taking an egg-sized ball of green light.

The hand then immediately shot back in Han Li’s direction and circled once around him before transforming back into a Nascent Soul. The Nascent Soul sat down on Han Li’s shoulder with a beaming smile and held the tri-pointed stake in one hand and a small ball of green light in the other.

Han Li’s expression stirred at the sight of this.

While he was besieged by the Soaring Tribes cultivators, he didn’t use his second Nascent Soul even once, keeping it in reserve for a critical opportunity to escape. However, it now proved far stronger than he had anticipated. A simple transformation technique was capable of easily slaying a Core Formation cultivator without the slightest resistance.

With that thought, he began to float down and approached the rainbow light barrier.

At that moment, the red flying sword had fallen to the ground as its master had now perished. It simply shined with faint light as it laid motionless.

Han Li didn’t pay the sword any attention and walked right towards the seven-light barrier before closely examining it. He was able to clearly see the light barrier had originated from the blue jade pendant floating at the center of the barrier.

The jade pendant floated a meter above the blue-robed cultivator’s body and it glowed with seven-colored light. A few strange Buddhist characters would occasionally appear in the light. It was the jade pendant Han Li showed to Silvermoon and was inscribed with the words: “Feng of Ning”.

Han Li stared at the jade pendant for a moment before slowly asking, “How is it, Senior? Is this magic tool refined by a Buddhist Sect?”

Monarch Soul Divergence coldly snorted and indifferently said, “The materials and magic tool are clearly of Buddhist make. However, it was clearly refined by a high-grade Buddhist cultivator. This magic tool wouldn’t have been able to block the attacks of a Core Formation level magic treasure for such a long period of time if that weren’t the case. It seems there is a relationship between a Buddhist sect and the Feng Clan.”

Han Li rejoiced after hearing Monarch Soul Divergence’s explanation, knowing his actions hadn’t been in vain. He then stepped forward and pressed his hand against the barrier, covering it in a faint layer of blue flames.

With his current cultivation, he wasn't able to control a large amount of the Celestial Ice Flames and these meager amount of flames were already pushing his limit. But this proved more than enough as the seven-colored light barrier wasn’t able to withstand its frigid cold for long. Soon after, the light barrier collapsed with a bang.

Han Li approached the blue-robed cultivator and examined the black bloodstain on his back before frowning.

He sensed the blue-robed cultivator’s aura had become incredibly unstable and weak. His body already started to emit the scent of death and it was clear his life wouldn’t last much longer.

Without any hesitation, Han Li struck the blue-robed cultivator’s body with a magic seal and opened his mouth to spit out a cloud of azure Qi that enveloped the blue-robed cultivator. Then with a wave of his sleeve, the youth’s body flipped onto its back.

Han Li stared at the blue-robed cultivator and immediately felt his blood run cold.

It was truly Feng Yue, but his complexion was now totally black and his lips had turned a faint purple. It was a horrid sight to behold.

Han Li grimaced. After a moment of thought, he spread his spiritual sense throughout Feng Yue’s body and blue light flickered from his eyes.

The poison had already spread throughout his body and he should already be dead by all means. Given how odd this was, Han Li carefully continued his examination.

A short moment later, Han Li found something and tugged at Feng Yue’s collar. With a zap, a piece of his robes tore off, revealing a chain held onto a silver key.

The key pulsed with white light and continuously dispersed of the poison at the center of Feng Yue’s chest, which had also turned jet-black.

Han Li’s gaze wandered and he grabbed onto Feng Yue’s arm. Azure light then glowed from his palm and quickly spread through Feng Yue’s body, slowly dispelling the poison. But suddenly, the azure spiritual Qi that Han Li released was turning black and it began to quickly spread back to his hand.

“Agony Poison!” Han Li yelled and his complexion paled. He immediately withdrew his hand and severed his spiritual Qi connection to Feng Yue’s arm.

“Yi! One of the Ten Absolute Poisons? Youngster Han, you’ve wasted your energy. There is no way of saving this person now.” Monarch Soul Divergence chuckled and spoke with a tone of schadenfreude.

When Han Li heard this, he couldn’t help but roll his eyes and annoyedly snort. “It might be impossible for me to completely remove the poison, but it won’t be difficult for me to awaken him and keep him alive for ten days. I merely need to use a good number of spirit medicines, but I don’t know if it will be worth the cost.”

With that said, Han Li stood up and wore a pensive expression.

Silvermoon then suggested, “Master, how about you awaken him first and have him make a few things clear before you come to a decision?”

“That’s true. Until I know about his relationship to the Buddhist sects of the Great Jin, I am unwilling to take any further actions.” Soon after, Han Li slapped his storage pouch and produced a small white bottle into his hand.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Lan (previously known as Lannis)

PR: Mangu King

Chapter 892: A Huge Bat

From the old man's strange discovery, there were only two conclusions: either his spiritual sense was mistaken, or there was a cultivator with a spiritual sense far superior to his own — most likely being the foreign cultivator. Regardless of the outcome, neither of them would be good.

For the first possibility, it would cause a loss of face in front of his two juniors and a loss of reputation as well, but the second possibility could lead to disaster.

While he made it appear that capturing the injured foreign cultivator would be an easy task, he was among the cultivators that had participated in the battle to stop Han Li and held his grand abilities in terror.

The Nascent Soul cultivators who fell in the battle against Han Li had their bodies had turned to purple ice and their Nascent Souls were subsequently frozen over — a scene that remained fresh in the old man’s mind. Even if the foreign cultivator was injured, he reckoned that the foreign cultivator could easily bring him down in mutual destruction.

Since there were no other Nascent Soul cultivators nearby and there was a vague possibility of death, he didn’t have the mind to confirm whether or not the danger was true. In any case, the Grand Immortals and the Saintess will personally deal with this person after the Day of Spirit Release.

With his heart filled with dread, the bald old man sighed and decided against catching up with the caravan. If he were two hundred years younger, he might’ve taken the risk. But now that he was nearing the end of his lifespan, he treasured what little time he had left.

The bald old man stared at the caravan as it made its way into the distance as he motionlessly stood in place. As for the pair standing behind him, they both glanced at each other with a bewildered expression, but neither of them were brave enough to ask about it.

...

When the caravan arrived ten kilometers away, Han Li felt a wave of relief. The master of the spiritual sense that had observed them back at the encampment hadn’t followed them.

Although Han Li had quickly responded to the spiritual sense search, he was unaccustomed to his drop in cultivation and withdrew his spiritual sense a bit late. He wasn't sure if he had truly concealed himself. And given how indiscernible the spiritual sense was, it was clear that the owner cultivated a secret technique.

His heart relaxed a bit for the time being and he continued to conceal his aura, not daring to be careless.

After travelling for over half a day, Han Li felt a wave of relief and began to slowly release his spiritual sense, covering a perimeter of over ten kilometers. Sensing that nothing was out of the ordinary, Han Li summoned the purple-robed old man’s storage pouch with a flip of his hand and poured out its contents in a flash of white light.

Han Li swept his gaze past the pile of items and took a small bottle into his hand. He opened it and took a whiff before shaking his head and setting it aside. Then he took another bottle and did the same as if trying to find something.

Eventually, Han Li opened the lid of an unremarkable green bottle. Before he even recognized what it was, a thread of purple mist drifted out. Han Li’s expression grew sullen and he opened his mouth, spitting out a ball of azure light. The thread of purple Qi wrapped around the light, quickly darkening it.

Han Li’s expression changed. Before the azure light became completely corrupted, Han Li forcefully blew on the light and pushed it into the bottle before quickly sealing it.

He then let out a sigh of relief. His actions hadn’t been in vain. He had acquired the remaining agony poison, a rather significant gain. The Ten Absolute Poisons were rarely ever encountered. The Kong Clan must’ve been an exceptional power to be able to possess something as rare as this.

He carefully put away the bottle in his storage pouch and then released a thread of spiritual sense out of impulse, peeking into one of the Red Wolf Tribe’s carriages.

Feng Yue was currently holding a fist-sized pearl with both his hands and meditating with his eyes shut. Black Qi was flowing in from his eyes to the pearl in his hands, causing the pearl to shine with black light. There was a pile of medicine bottles stacked in front of him, but most of them were opened and there were even a few loose pills scattered to the side.

Han Li shook his head at the sight and withdrew his spiritual sense.

Although this pearl appeared to be some sort of exceptional treasure capable of absorbing poisonous Qi, it had already reached its limit. The absorbed poisonous Qi would soon be replaced by the Agony Poison deep within his body and his efforts would be in vain. It was simply a delusion to believe that he'd be able to rid himself of the poison in a mere ten days.

With this thought, Han Li closed his eyes and sank into meditation.

...

Eight days later, the road had been peaceful apart from two low-grade Ironhoof Beasts. They encountered the caravan in a moment of carelessness, much to the joy of the cultivators in the caravan, but Feng Yue, Han Li, and one other cultivator hadn’t participated in the hunt.

The cultivator that hadn’t taken action had aroused Han Li’s interest and when Han Li examined him with his spiritual sense, he found that the youth was simply a diligent Foundation Establishment cultivator that was immersed in cultivation.

Han Li quickly lost interest in him after examining him a few more times. As for Feng Yue, he had failed in his many attempts to rid himself of the poison and had grown frantic, despair occasionally appearing on his face. His black hair had gradually turned white as well.

This came as no surprise. He was the sole descendant of the Feng Clan and was completely helpless as the death of his bloodline approached. What he suffered was far beyond what an ordinary person could bear. Now, there were only three days left before he ran out of time.

Anyways, Han Li had finished comprehending the incantation Monarch Soul Divergence had given him two days prior. He had gained much peace of mind as he no longer had any fear of being surrounded by Nascent Soul cultivators.

One day as night approached, the caravan of several hundred people stopped beside a river that was about a kilometer wide and made shelter for the night. The various tribes had raised bonfires all around them and were roasting livestock.

When Han Li heard the sound of flowing water, his heart stirred and he departed from the carriage.

The young woman named Ying Shan had been eating a piece of dried meat when Han Li suddenly emerged. With a face flushed with embarrassment, she tossed the meat to the side and respectfully saluted Han Li, saying, “Sir Immortal, do you have any orders?” Since this was the first time Han Li had emerged from the carriage during the long journey, she had been thrown off guard and was somewhat flustered.

Han Li took a glance at the woman’s dainty face and looked at the meat she tossed aside, then saying, “I have none. I’ve meditated enough inside the carriage and thought I’d have a look around.”

“That...” Somewhat at a loss, the woman proposed, “Immortal Han, how about I go fetch you some fresh water?”

Han Li glanced at the river nearby and nodded. “That’ll be good. Although I no longer feel the need to eat, a drink of fresh water will be good.”

When the young woman heard this, she gave a lively response despite the turmoil she felt in her heart and ran to the river with a water sack. When Han Li glanced at her from behind, his heart stirred and he unconsciously smiled.

A short moment later, the young woman brought back the water sack and was holding a piece of roasted meat in her hand. She was panting for breath and offered the two items to Han Li with an embarrassed expression.

With an earnest tone, the young woman said, “Sir Immortal, the roasted meat is quite good. Will you try some?”

Han Li chuckled and said, “Sure! It’s been many years since I’ve eaten something. A bit of food should be interesting.” He then accepted the meat and took a bite, finding the taste to be quite good.

When the young woman saw this, she revealed an adorable expression.

When Han Li was finished with his bite of food, he set it aside and said, “It must’ve been hard waiting at the side of my carriage. You’re participating in the Day of Spirit Release, right? Extend your hand and let me take look at your spirit roots.”

“Many thanks, Sir Immortal.” When the young woman heard him, she extended her wrist with unconcealed excitement.

Han Li grabbed the woman’s wrist channeled a bit of spiritual Qi into her body and pondered for a moment. If his cultivation hadn’t been reduced to Foundation Establishment stage, he would’ve been able to examine her aptitude without touching her.

“Immortal Han, how is my aptitude? Do I have any chance of becoming an Immortal?” The young woman eagerly asked. Her face wore an expression of hopeful excitement.

“You should have no problem becoming an Immortal, but it can be considered destiny that you’ve met me. Take the medicine before the Spirit Release Rites.” Han Li released his grip on her wrist and summoned a small white bottle with a flick of his hand.

“This...” The young woman received the small bottle with complete surprise.

“Although the medicine pill isn’t particularly precious, it will improve your constitution and will aid you on your path to cultivation.” The medicine was a marrow cleansing medicine pill, something valuable to low-grade cultivators but was of little value to Han Li.

“Many thanks for Sir Immortal’s great kindness.” The young woman rejoiced and hastily bowed.

“Stand up,” Han Li waved his hand at the young woman and said, “Perhaps if fate will have, we’ll see each other again in the future. By the way, since this river is so wide, could it be the southern portion of the Heavenly Water River?”

The young woman carefully put the bottle away and said, “That’s correct, Sir Immortal. It is a branch of the Heavenly Water River. It runs over fifty kilometers down before joining with the true Heavenly Water River.

When Han Li heard this, he said nothing else and began to recall all the details pertaining to the Heavenly Water River.

If he remembered correctly, the river was incredibly long, earning its title as the largest river in the Endless Sky Plains, and it even reached down to the Jin Empire under the name of the Mystical River.

He couldn’t help but ponder over this fact.

Then, Han Li’s expression stirred and he raised his head to look at the sky across the river with a gloomy expression.

“Quickly inform the tribe elders that there is something flying towards us,” Han Li sullenly commanded, “I don’t know if they are passing through or if they’re specifically heading towards us.”

The young woman was startled when she heard this and she repeatedly nodded her head before running to Ying Lu and the other tribe leaders. A short moment later, an uproar was raised and everyone quickly ran away from the river.

Before most of the people could return to the carriages, green light flash from over the horizon and a series of low-pitched cries sounded out, revealing a huge bat covered in green light.

Its sinister and frightening appearance caused the mortals to shiver in fear at the sight of it. The many Soaring Tribes cultivators in the caravan all leaped out of their carriages and looked at it with solemn expressions.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Mangu King

Chapter 897: Splitting the Enemy

“Senior, I’ve already shaken off these Soaring Tribes cultivators three times and left a large distance between them each time, but they were always soon to catch my trail. Could it be there is some spiritual sense strengthening technique that is beyond the Great Development Technique? How can they catch sight of me so far away?” Han Li asked, his complexion deathly pale from strain.

At that moment, Han Li had already lifted the Soullock Seal and was flying through the air in an azure streak. He had done this three times already to make use of the Bloodshadow Evasion Technique each time, bringing Han Li’s body to the brink of crisis.

If he wasn’t using several high-grade secret techniques to forcefully suppress his baleful Qi backlash and his use of a dozen drops of Myriad Spirit Milk to make up for the blood essence requirement of Bloodshadow Evasion, he feared he wouldn’t be able to press on.

And under such strain, he had already lost three years of his cultivation. If it weren’t for the many medicine pills he had taken, it was quite possible that he would’ve dropped to an entire level of cultivation.

With his body pushed to its limits and the late-Nascent Soul cultivators pursuing him, he found himself in dire crisis. But before he figured out how the Soaring Tribes Immortals were tracking him, he couldn’t rashly make use of the Bloodshadow Evasion Technique. Otherwise, he’d be ruining himself only for them to eventually track him down.

Monarch Soul Divergence coldly snorted and said, “Although I am completely confident in my Great Development Arts, I don’t dare to boast it as the number one spiritual sense technique in the cultivation world. There aren’t many who possess aptitude greater than mine, but they do exist. The possibility of them possessing a particularly powerful technique is miniscule.

However, those chasing you aren’t tracking you down through an immensely powerful spiritual sense. Instead, they are tracking you through inhuman means.”

When Han Li heard this, he came to a sudden realization. “Inhuman means? You mean that demon beast?”

“That’s right. Didn’t you sense something similar to a demon beast behind you? Its appearance is exactly the same as what the Soaring Tribes mortal described of their patron god, the Endless Sky Beast. Those people from the Endless Sky Temples most likely summoned the beast to deliberately reclaim the face they lost from having their Nascent Soul Immortals killed by you. It isn’t odd for something not from this world to be able to track you down.”

Han Li frowned and hesitantly asked, “The Endless Sky Beast? I’ve made note of it, but this particular beast only possessed magic power around the level of a grade seven demon beast, far inferior to the Moulan’s sacred bird. How can it possess such abilities?”

“Hehe, I’ve heard you speak of your continent's war against the Moulan and how they summoned a projection of their sacred bird with the assistance of a treasure. It merely possessed an illusory body and emerged in this world from nowhere. From what I sensed, the demon beast following you should have a genuine body. If that’s the case, the Endless Sky Beast seemed to use an ability similar to the Elder Devil’s possession through the use of some other beasts as a medium to bring itself into this world. Do not underestimate the abilities this incarnation possesses. If you give it enough time, it will grow into a fearsome existence. To the best of my knowledge, there are several other similar incarnations that descended into this world, but they are all fearsome to behold. And they are rarely ever seen by common cultivators.”

“There are such kind of beings in our mortal world? However, there is no time for me to further discuss this matter with you. Regardless of whether this is a demon beast or a holy beast, does Senior have a method of escaping its pursuit? It will be greatly troublesome if the seal continues to be lifted.” As Han Li swept his spiritual sense behind him, he spotted three cultivators and a demon beast in the distance behind him and grew apprehensive as a result.

Monarch Soul Divergence answered, “There are countless strange beasts in the upper realms. Who knows what kind of amazing abilities it is using to track you. Your Qi restraining abilities are quite to my satisfaction as well. It appears there are no good methods apart from slaying this beast. However, I can instruct you on a simple method of feigning death, capable of extinguishing all signs of life from your body, but I do not know how useful this will be. After all, the demon beast might not be tracking you down through your aura.”

Han Li grew silent and then a cold glint flickered from his eyes. He fiercely said, “Fine, then I will kill this beast.”

Monarch Soul Divergence said with alarm, “I fear you won’t have the opportunity to kill that beast. It is being accompanied by two Grand Immortals and that masked mid-Nascent Soul stage woman should be the Endless Sky Saintess. Her abilities shouldn’t be anything to underestimate either.”

“If I don’t take the risk, there will be no opportunities. I will have to treat my second Nascent Soul as a disposable resource if I am to succeed.” Han Li said with an icy tone.

Silvermoon then said, “Master, if you plan on doing that, I also wish to help you.”

After hearing her, Han Li asked, “How are your injuries? Will you be able to persist in drawing their attention away as an artifact spirit?”

Silvermoon smiled and said, “I am the artifact spirit of Master’s magic treasure. No matter how severe my injuries may be, so long as Master’s flying swords aren’t destroyed, I will not die. Master doesn’t need to worry much on my behalf. At most, I will only remain asleep in Master’s magic treasure for a few years.”

After some consideration, Han Li sighed and said, “Alright. Since our current situation is far from good, I will have to trouble you.”

Afterwards, Han Li learned the incantation for feigning death from Monarch Soul Divergence. With that memorized, he then immediately placed his hand on the top of his head.

His second Nascent Soul appeared in a flash of black light and spat out the Yin Sifting Banner from its mouth. It then shook the flag without end and leaped into the air. In the blink of an eye, black clouds gathered around them in a storm, darkening the sky for a whole kilometer and filling the air with devilish Qi.

“Take this. If the Endless Sky Saintess chases after you with the beast, use this sword to strike it down.” Han Li said with an imposing tone. Then with a wave of his hand, he summoned a small crimson sword and tossed it into the black clouds. It was the Blood Devil Sword.

Afterwards, a piercing shriek echoed from the clouds and the sword flew off with astonishing momentum.

Han Li glanced at the devilish cloud in the distance with a sullen expression. Then, he summoned a small bottle with a flip of his hand and poured a drop of Myriad Year Spirit Milk into his mouth.

His body brightly glowed with spiritual light and he tore through the sky in an azure streak.

...

“What’s going on? If I’m not mistaken, the foreign cultivator’s Nascent Soul materialized and fled on its own?” When the purple-haired woman saw this, she couldn’t help but yelp in astonishment.

The elegant man shook his head and said in a grave tone, “That can’t be right. If an ordinary Nascent Soul materializes, its body cannot move on its own. However, that person is now fleeing in a different direction from his Nascent Soul. Could it be he cultivated something similar to the Three Corpse Soul Technique?”

The purple-haired woman wore a pensive expression and said, “If he’s trying to use a doppelganger technique in an attempt to escape us, he won’t succeed. The Nascent Soul won’t be able to escape us either so long as we pay attention to its whereabouts. Now that an intact Nascent Soul has fled, it shouldn’t be something like the Six Soul Divisions Technique that Fellow Daoist Gui cultivates. Could it be this is a legendary second Nascent Soul?”

The Saintess frowned and felt a wave of alarm.

The elegant man turned his head to the Saintess and asked, “Did the Holy Beast sense anything strange?”

“It can’t,” the Saintess sighed, “the Holy Beast only managed to bring a trace of its spiritual sense into this world. It will need over a hundred years of cultivation before it can completely make use of its spiritual sense. Its abilities are limited as its cultivation is only at the level of a grade seven demon beast.”

The elegant man pondered for a moment before saying, “This will be somewhat troublesome. Since we can’t distinguish which one is genuine, we cannot allow either one to flee. How about I take on the Nascent Soul while you two pursue the man with the Holy Beast. With my abilities, it shouldn't take much time to deal with a mere Nascent Soul.”

“That plan sounds reliable,” the purple-haired woman said with a smile. “With me by the Saintess’ side, nothing should happen to her. While that Nascent Soul might not be his primary soul, don’t kill it for now. First, try to find the method to breed the Gold Devouring Beetles from it.”

“Of course,” the elegant man said, “I’ve considered that as well.”

The Saintess felt there was no problem with this plan either and agreed.

The elegant man parted ways with the other two and flew after Han Li’s second Nascent Soul in a thirty-meter long green streak of light, disappearing from view. The Endless Sky Saintess and the purple-haired woman didn’t change direction and continued pursuing Han Li.

Soon, the two traveled over fifty kilometers and closed the distance between them and Han Li.

...

“We should only be about thirty kilometers away from them. Silvermoon, it’s time for you to leave.” Han Li’s sleeve trembled as a small silver wolf flew out from it, landing at Han Li’s side. Then in a blur, Silvermoon took the shape of Han Li’s form.

Han Li’s face wore a wry smile in response, but since there was no time, he said nothing else and summoned a storage pouch and a thumb-sized azure pearl before handing them over to Silvermoon.

Han Li explained, “Since you’re a tool spirit without a flesh body and won’t be able to nimbly control magic treasures, bring the Gold Devouring Beetles with you and the lightning pearl. If that demon beast follows after you, consider nothing else apart from wounding the beast. It will be fine so long as you disable it for the time being.”

“Master, be at ease. If the Endless Sky Beast follows me, I will not allow it to easily escape.” In Han Li’s image, Silvermoon took the two treasures and tore through the sky in a silver streak.

Translator's Thoughts

Happy Lunar New Year!

PR: Mangu King

ED: Lan

Chapter 900: A Startling Change

Han Li narrowed his eyes and began to circulate the first layer of the Heavenvoid Cauldron’s Artifact Imprint Technique.

A dragon’s cry roared out from the cauldron and the cauldron’s lid launched into the air in a streak of blue light, revealing the rainbow light that shined from within it. Then the sea of azure light the Saintess used to freeze Han Li’s movements was quickly absorbed into the Heavenvoid Cauldron.

They were both shocked to see what was happening.

The Saintess’ huge cauldron had released a strange hum and suddenly shot down in a streak of light.

The Saintess turned deathly pale at this sudden change and hastily formed a hand incantation, ordering the cauldron to stop, but her commands were ineffective and the cauldron disappeared into the Heavenvoid Cauldron down below.

Furious alarm filled the Saintess’ mind, but it didn’t stop there.

The Heavenvoid Cauldron suddenly flew out from Han Li’s grasp and spun in the air before pointing its mouth towards the white mist at the side. As the cauldron faintly glowed with light, a roar of terror sounded out from the mist, followed by a black silhouette shooting out from it into the sky. It was a flood dragon with a bull’s head, the Endless Sky Beast.

Then, an enchanting azure mist shot out from the Heavenvoid Cauldron and chased down the Endless Sky Beast with incredible speed, instantly wrapping around the beast. The Endless Sky Beast wildly howled and struggled with all its might, but the blue mist held firm as if unaffected by the beast’s attacks. The mist spun around and quickly shank itself along with the beast before flying back into the cauldron. Then, the cauldron's lid spun once more before slamming into the cauldron and sealing it shut.

This strange turn of events had occurred all in the blink of an eye.

The Saintess’ expression turned completely pale in complete disbelief. It was clear that she was initially winning the battle. How was it that she had fallen into the abyss of defeat so quickly? Not only did Han Li escape from her cocoon of sand, but he seized both the holy cauldron and the incarnation of the holy beast.

However, the woman was someone of unordinary character and still retained her composure. Her gaze then dropped down to the Heavenvoid Cauldron in Han Li’s grasp.

She clearly understood that the change of circumstance in the battle was due to that cauldron. The loss of control over the holy cauldron must’ve been due to a connection between it and Han Li’s cauldron, or something so great wouldn’t have occurred. She had to acquire that cauldron!

In the blink of an eye, the Saintess resolved herself.

Han Li was delighted by this sudden turn of events, but when the woman’s icy gaze flickered past him, he smiled, knowing precisely what the woman was thinking. Then, his wings flapped, he disappeared in a flash of silver lightning, only to reappear a hundred meters away.

He then recalled his condensed flying swords without any hesitation and his fingers blurred as they formed a series of strange hand gestures. Azure light flashed around his body as astonishing spiritual Qi was emitted from his body. He then opened his mouth and spat several mouthfuls of blood essence into the air. They transformed into threads of blood mist before turning into a strange azure-red color. Additionally, his complexion turned from dark red to a blood-crimson in an astonishing display and his figure grew indistinct inside the mist of blood.

“Not good!” When the Saintess saw Han Li’s actions, she immediately thought of something and she cried out in panic. She raised her hand and released two beams of silver light, turning into countless silver threads in midair in an attempt to cover Han Li.

But by the time the huge sword returned to Han Li, his image inside the crimson mist began to blur and he disappeared from view. In the next moment, crimson light glowed from the horizon before fading away.

The Saintess’ heart sank and she quickly released her spiritual sense, but Han Li had already escaped the limits of her spiritual sense with his Bloodshadow Evasion. The woman remained floating motionless in place with an ashen complexion.

...

In that same moment, over five hundred kilometers away, the elegant man was glancing down at the vast borderless plains with a strange expression as nine humming dark green wheels fluttered around him.

“Wood movement techniques? It was still had the strength to use the vegetation to conceal itself after I injured it to that degree? And that devil artifact is extremely powerful and troublesome, but it risked backlash when using it. However, it has no hope for survival. It is merely a Nascent Soul. With the injuries it sustained, its body will soon vanish. Nevertheless, I have the feeling that something bad had occurred. Could it be something to do with the others?” The youth’s eyes flickered as he muttered to himself before raising his head in another direction. After some hesitation, the nine wheels joined together as one and he shot back in a dark green streak of light.

Under an unremarkable bush, a shining black flag was embedded in the earth. There was a half-foot-wide hole that faintly emerged from it where there was an inch-large black-green Nascent Soul laying inside of it unconscious. Black Qi roiled around its body as it quietly absorbed the pure devilish Qi in the flag to restore its wounds.

...

In another area of the plains, a beautiful purple-haired woman had used a jade ancient treasure to trap several thousands of Gold Devouring Beetles. And she blocked an attack from a bead of lightning before easily piercing through the body of the foreign cultivator with a single attack. However, the foreign cultivator’s body then glowed with silver light to reveal the body of a charming woman. Then, she completely disappeared in specks of starlight.

The purple-haired woman stood in place with shock.

...

Four hours later, the elegant man, purple-haired woman, and the Endless Sky Saintess met together once more. They gave each other an account of what happened and looked at each other with dismay.

The elegant man frowned and sullenly said, “You mean to say that not only did we not acquire the method to nurture the Gold Devouring Beetles, but we also lost the holy cauldron and the Holy Beast?”

The purple-haired woman wore an unsightly expression and said, “The holy cauldron isn’t significant as we have another alternative to summoning the Holy Beast. However, I fear that having the Holy Beast’s incarnation captured will invoke the fury of the Holy Beast in the realms above. We must reclaim it.”

“We were far too careless,” the Saintess said with an exceptional calm, “I didn’t think this person would have a method of restraining the holy cauldron and cause this to happen. I will have to go to the Great Jin to reclaim the Holy Beast incarnation. And that strange small cauldron that was used to control our holy cauldron is nothing to underestimate either.

I suspect that cauldron is the Divine Spirit Treasure that our holy cauldron was modeled after. It can’t be explained any other way.”

“Divine Spirit Treasure? That isn’t very likely,” the purple-haired woman doubtfully said, “Those treasures aren’t something that can appear in this world. There were treasures that ancient cultivators brought down from the realm above. The refinement method for the holy cauldron was something that a unique genius ancestor had acquired after using a secret technique to communicate with the Holy Beast. How could the Divine Spirit Treasure still remain in the mortal world?”

The elegant man shook his head and said, “That might not be certain. Since Elder Devils were able to appear in our mortal world, it is possible there are several Divine Spirit Treasures that exist in our world as well.”

When the Saintess and the purple-haired woman heard the Elder Devil being mentioned, their expressions changed.

The purple-haired woman snorted and said, “It was said the Elder Devil was extremely fearsome, but it is a shame we didn’t have the opportunity to fight it. However, the Devil’s movement techniques are truly wondrous. It was easily able to cross our plains and enter the Great Jin.”

The elegant man sighed and spoke with a wry smile, “That is because the Elder Devil was gravely wounded. If it were to encounter us, we would give chase, preventing it from finding the time to heal. If it weren’t for that, the devil could’ve spread chaos throughout the plains.”

Gloominess worn on her face, the Saintess said, “Regardless of whether that cauldron is truly a Divine Spirit Treasure, he had killed many of our Immortals and seized the Holy Beast. We cannot allow this to be. Since the holy cauldron was seized away from me, I must make the trip to personally find it and the Holy Beast’s incarnation. Otherwise, we will not be able to answer the Holy Beast’s questions the next time we summon it.”

When the other two heard this, they exchanged a glance as if communicating their opinions.

The elegant man then nodded and said, “Since the Saintess feels strongly about this, she may as well make the trip to the Great Jin. However, many cultivators sects of the Great Jin are prejudiced towards our Soaring Tribe Immortals. You had best keep your identity a secret. After all, those of the Great Jin should possess vast abilities. You should first take a look at the Yin Sifting Sect and see if that person is truly a Yin Sifting Sect Elder. After making his identity clear, you should immediately return to the plains and we will lend you our power.”

“I understand. Since that person’s abilities are likely beyond mine, I won’t rashly take action.” The Saintess said with a grave expression.

Thus, the three promptly returned. After the Endless Sky Saintess finished handling her affairs, she set off to the Great Jin to search for Han Li.

...

The Great Jin’s Liao Province was one of the hundred and eight provinces of the empire. It was split into ten prefectures, but a majority of them were located in a vastly snowy area where few lived. The more prosperous of these prefectures were still somewhat destitute.

The Liao Province’s Mystic River is the province’s second largest river and it was one of the few rivers that wouldn’t freeze during flood season. As a result, whenever the time came, merchants and travellers would all use this river to travel as it was far more convenient than carriage or horse. And at every portion of the river, there would be empire vessels making their patrols.

But regardless of this, there were many ships on this vast stretch of river. Naturally, there would be many criminals that would take the risk of seizing the ship of worse. As a result, there would be a few larger ships that would hire skilled martial artists as guards.

Wang Tieqiang was a common example of such a guard. And as his name would suggest [1] , he was somewhat skilled with spears, but this was secondary to his vast experience as a guard. He has been a guard for over twenty years, turning from a hot-headed youth to an experienced and profound Jianghu practitioner.

At the moment, he was steadily standing at the bow of the ship with a hand resting on the boat railing. He was examining the nearby waters with a calm expression.

On this journey, he was only a common bodyguard. The only thing exceptional about this job was that the ship’s owner was rumored to be the trusted confidant of a very important government official.

That being said, most bandits would be unwilling to take action against a ship, even if it were lightly guarded. And this was shown across their long journey, where not even a single event had occurred.

Just as he was lost in his thoughts, he recalled how generous the ship’s owner had paid him. The silver could afford his wife several good fabrics to make several sets of good clothing. With that thought, Wang Tieqiang couldn’t help but smile as he thought about his seven-year-old son.

But then a woman’s voice suddenly cried out, “Quick come! There a huge block of ice there. It... It seems to have someone inside.”

[1]. The qiang 枪 in his name means spear.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

happy 900

PR: Mangu King

Chapter 905: The Coffin

Han Li pondered to himself for a moment before calmly saying, “It’s nothing. It won’t be too late to mention it in the future. Since there is an extensive gathering here, I’ll take a look at there first.”

After the two white-robed youths glanced at one another, the shorter youth smiled and said, “That’s good. Let us lead the way, Senior.”

Soon after, each of them took out a disk magic tool and tossed them into the air before leaping onto them. When Han Li saw this, he tossed a sparkling flying sword and appeared on top of it in a blur.

Having seen the sword, the shorter youth revealed an expression of admiration and said, “Senior’s magic tool is a high-grade flying sword. You must be an inner disciple of a large sect, right? There is no way a master or sect would give a magic tool of that quality to a low-grade disciple.”

Han Li chuckled and answered, “My sect has a rule where we’re not allowed to reveal the identity of our affiliation while we’re on a journey. I hope you two Fellow Daoists will refrain from asking these questions.”

The two youths felt somewhat embarrassed, but now they felt even more certain that Han Li was a disciple from a large sect and their expressions grew even more respectful.

The three cultivators then headed south of the village on their magic tools.

The Snowmound Mountain wasn’t very far away from the village. As they flew towards it, they could faintly see a line of black mountaintops in the distance. It was more appropriate to call it a mountain range than a mountain. The mountain range spanned over five hundred kilometers and was one of the several great mountain ranges in the Liao Province. Additionally, it was reportedly said that there were demons and ghosts lurking deep into the mountain. Let alone mortals, even lower grade cultivators would occasionally disappear in the mountains.

The friends and sect of the cultivators who disappeared formed search parties and scour through half the mountain range only to find no sign of them. After this, more cultivators would disappeared regardless.

Fortunately, disappearances only rarely happened and most of those that disappeared were low-grade cultivators native to the Liao Province. As a result of these repeated incidents, few cultivators ever tread too deeply into the mountains and the disappearances slowly stopped as well.

Of course, the Grand Assembly that was hosted by the three great clans of Guanning wasn’t being held deep into the mountain range. It was located at a town on the top of a lofty mountain at its edge.

When they eventually arrived, Han Li saw beautiful towering buildings erected on top of this mountain. His eyes flickered and he was able to see that the mountain was newly constructed. He couldn’t help but wear a pensive expression at the sight.

“Senior, we’ve arrived,” the taller youth pointed at the town down below and said, “All of the Foundation Establishment cultivators that arrive are given their own room. As for the Seniors at Core Formation stage and above, they are given their own building. This way, all Seniors are given a proper place to rest.”

Han Li nodded and remained silent, only releasing his spiritual sense to carefully look at the town below them. He unconsciously frowned and sensed that there was a Nascent Soul cultivator in the town. It was unknown whether he was a cultivator joining in the gathering, or if he was the Eccentric Kong that Feng Yu had mentioned before he died.

The noble clans of the Great Jin were not to be underestimated as rumor had indicated. In the Heavenly South, cultivation clans had late-Core Formation cultivators within their ranks at most and weren’t capable of producing a Nascent Soul cultivator.

But to his surprise, the Nascent Soul cultivator he sensed on the mountain, faintly emitted the aura of a corpse. Although it was very faint and well concealed, Han Li was able to clearly see through it with his overwhelming spiritual sense. No matter how well it was hidden, it would’ve been detectable with some careful observation.

Could it be this person cultivated a Devilish Dao or a wicked heretical technique?

If he remembered correctly, the Kong Clan hailed from the famous Confucian Sect known as the Heavenly Sage Sect and the clan still received the sect’s backing. Regardless of whether or not this Nascent Soul cultivator was the Kong Clan ancestor, it would be inappropriate for a sect of their standing to either practice this technique or have a guest of this nature.

As he pondered this, they descended to the village gates and were immediately welcomed by four blue-robed cultivators.

...

At nearly the same time in a secret room over seventy meters deep underground, the lid of a pitch-black coffin suddenly moved and a pure-white hand suddenly emerged from the gap. Then it pushed the lid of the coffin completely off to reveal a yellow-robed man wearing a king’s crown. He appeared in his thirties and wore an odd expression of bewilderment.

“What’s going on? I suddenly felt a wave of trepidation. Could it be that someone was spying on me?” The man muttered to himself. After some hesitation, he carefully released his spiritual sense and swept past the entire mountain, particularly focusing his attention on the many cultivators in the village above.

After a long while, he found no trace of any other Nascent Soul cultivators and tightly knitted his brow.

“Perhaps it was just an old fart that journeyed nearby and swept his spiritual sense. The Blackjade Coffin should’ve concealed my corpse Qi so it shouldn’t attract any attention.” The crowned man muttered to himself before returning into the coffin. The lid then slid back in place of its own accord and sealed the coffin, causing silence to fill the room once more.

...

Back on the surface, the blue-robed cultivators recommended Han Li to go to the huge plaza at the center, which was spralling with half a thousand variously dressed cultivators.

However, these cultivators were divided into several groups and each gathered into clearly different areas of the village. There were some that were talking and others that were selling items. The plaza was also covered in variously-sized vendor booths with some that have set up tables and others that had their items arranged the ground. It made for quite a lively scene.

Han Li smiled and recalled the first time he entered the cultivation world at the Great South Meeting [1] . He felt a bit emotional over the memory.

But to his surprise, there was a huge tent that was erected at the center of the plaza. It was sparkling with white light, revealing itself to be a magic tool, and it spanned over three hundred meters wide. There were many people walking in and out of its openings.

His eyes stirred and he looked at the rest of the plaza. There were stone buildings that were flickering with light with people occasionally flowing through them, but they received far less traffic than the tent at the center. There were even a few cultivators that were pacing back and forth around the buildings or were chatting with their companions.

Apart from the few Qi Condensation cultivators from the three clans, there were only cultivators at Foundation Establishment stage and above. With a sweep of his spiritual sense, he found that there were over a dozen Core Formation cultivators present. Even without the Nascent Soul cultivator, the cultivators present were beyond in number of what large clans in the Heavenly South could produce. And this was only a trade fair that a few of the local noble clans in the Great Jin were hosting.

When Han Li thought this, he couldn’t help but sigh.

As he was informed by the disciples that had welcomed him, he knew that morning was the time for free trade and the afternoon was when the auction would start. If he had rare materials, magic tools, or other items, he would be welcome to exchange them before the auction. Additionally, the trade fair was planned to only span three days and on the last day, the thousand-year-old Monarch Ginseng would be auctioned. It was likely that the Core Formation cultivators had come solely for this item.

After glancing around for a while, he began to stroll around the plaza.

Han Li was currently a Foundation Establishment cultivator that had joined the trade fair on its second day. Although his face was unfamiliar, no one took notice of him; he was just another ordinary cultivator in the crowd.

The items around the vendor booths were all common as expected and were of little interest to Han Li. There were items that would prove to be attractive to Foundation Establishment and Core Formation cultivators, but he already had countless precious materials in his possession. The only vendor booths to catch his attention were selling particularly odd magic tools and materials.

But after some careful observation, he easily recognized them. Past that point, there was no further value in investigating them.

After spending quite some time roaming around, he didn’t end up purchasing anything, and just as he thought to enter the tent at the middle of the plaza and see what was being sold there, his expression suddenly changed and he vigilantly turned around. He saw an old man with pointed ears and thin cheeks looking at him with amazement. He possessed cultivation at early Foundation Establishment stage.

With an icy glint in his eye, Han Li coldly said, “Fellow Daoist, you’ve been following me for quite a while. Could it be that you recognize me?”

“Please don’t misunderstand, Fellow Daoist.” The old man wore an embarrassed smile and calmly explained, “My name is Jin Yuan and I don’t mean any harm to you. I was simply curious. This is the first time we’ve met, but you seem to have a great understanding of many of these tools and materials. I hold you in quite some admiration!”

“Oh! I didn’t know Fellow Daoist was so observant,” Han Li calmly said, “But since you’ve been following me for so long, surely you have more business with me than just a chat.”

“ Hehe! It seems you’re quite sharp. In truth, I actually have something to request of you.”

“Please go ahead and state it!” Han Li crossed his arms and wore an indifferent expression.

The old man examined the storage pouches at Han Li’s waist and chuckled with narrowed eyes, saying, “I have a strange treasure here and I’ve been unable to make any sense of its uses and origins. I was hoping Fellow Daoist could appraise it. Of course, if Fellow Daoist is able to read through it, I may as well sell it to you. With your background, you will certainly be able to purchase it.”

“A strange treasure?” Han Li’s brow stirred and his gaze wandered around the old man for a while. He eventually nodded and pointed to a room at the side, “Fine. Since Fellow Daoist has been following me for a while, it seems you hold good intentions. I may as well took a look. Let’s go to that hidden room and have a chat. I also have a few things I wish to have explained as well.”

“A hidden room? You have to pay a spirit stone for that. That’s quite luxurious.” The old man hesitantly said.

Han Li mysteriously smiled and said, “That’s fine, I will pay the spirit stone. I simply hope that your strange treasure isn’t to my disappointment.”

[1]. Chapter 128: Great South Meeting.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Lan

PR: Mangu King

Apologies for the delay.

Chapter 910: Firesmelt Crystals

After a long while inside the Hidden Fortune Room, Han Li eventually decided to put the Weeping Soul Beast inside his storage pouch while it was still inside the golden bubble. Then, he walked out and shrunk the Hidden Fortune Room back to its original size.

After he went back to the main hall, he returned the room to the middle-aged woman before heading out to the plaza.

At that moment, it was already afternoon and there were nearly half as many cultivators as before. They were all heading in a peculiar stone building to participate in the auction. Without another thought, he moved to join them.

A white-robed cultivator standing at the entrance of the auction saw Han Li and greeted him with a salute, “Fellow Daoist, to prevent too many idle spectators, we are charging three spirit stones to participate in the auction.”

Han Li smiled and silently pressed his hand against his storage pouch before handing over three spirit stones to the white-robed cultivator. The cultivator smiled back and gave him a palm-sized jade plate, allowing him to enter.

Han Li glanced at the jade plate as he walked through the entrance of the building and saw that it had engraved “two hundred and forty-three” in silver letters. Aside from that, there was nothing else remarkable.

After walking through a sixty-meter-long passageway, he came across four cultivators guarding a door that shined with white light. When they saw Han Li arrive, they all silently examined him with expressionless faces.

Han Li ignored them and walked past them, opening the gate and entering the main hall.

He then heard a loud man’s voice saying, “Five-hundred-year-old Phoenix Tail Flower, seven hundred and ninety spirit stones. Is there anyone bidding any higher? No? Then this spirit herb goes to Fellow Daoist One Hundred Thirty. In a moment, please go to the back and pay the spirit stones for the medicine herb.”

Han Li clearly saw over two hundred people sitting in the hall. Each of them was sitting in front of a table and had placed down their jade plate on top of it, clearly revealing the shining silver numbers on top of it.

In front of the stone hall, there was a blue-robed middle-aged man with an imposing appearance. As he was speaking, he was holding open a jade box with a bright purple flower inside of it.

The one who purchased this medicine herb was a fat old man. When he saw the middle-aged man verify the winning bid, he stood up with a happy expression and walked over to the side door as if he couldn’t wait to acquire it.

Han Li looked at the scene with indifference and walked over to a nearby empty seat.

He sat down in a chair made of pure white stone. It’s jadelike appearance and its warm sensation had aroused a bit of interest from Han Li.

“This is...” Han Li pondered for a moment, recalling the stone materials in his memory only to find that he hadn’t seen this material before. His lips faintly curled from his surprise.

“Fellow Daoist, is this your first time seeing Warmstone?” He suddenly heard a woman’s voice with a faint giggle.

“Warmstone?” He turned his head to the side and saw two young female cultivators who resembled each other so strongly they could be sisters. One of them was wearing yellow clothes and the other green clothes, but both of them were indisputably outstanding beauties. The one who spoke was the closer of the two and was wearing green. She found it silly how Han Li touched the table.

“Little sister, don’t speak out of turn,” the yellow-clothed woman quickly said, “Fellow Daoist, please don’t take offense. My younger cousin had just come out from the clan and her words are still rash. I hope you’ll forgive her.”

‘Youngster cousin? They’re not sisters by blood?’ Han Li thought with surprise. But for the two to reach Foundation Establishment stage at such a young age, they clearly had exceptional aptitudes.

With that thought, he smiled and casually said, “It’s alright. I’ve only heard of Warmstone before but this is the first time I’ve seen it. Does Fellow Daoist know about this item in detail? It can’t be a common material or else I would’ve heard of it before, despite having cultivated in the wilderness all this time.”

“Warmstone is completely different from the material known as Warm Jade,” the yellow-clothed woman explained with a smile, “It isn’t strange for Fellow Daoist to not know of it as it is a material rarely found in other places. It is only present here because it is a specialty of the Snowmound Mountains. But apart from being warm to the touch and exceptionally white, there is nothing else notable about it. But of course, it is far more valuable that the common jade found in the mortal world.”

“So it was like that. Many thanks for your explanation.” Han Li nodded with understanding and then his expression blanked as he turned to look at the middle-aged man auctioning a top-grade magic tool.

His actions had caused the green-clothed woman to narrow her eyes and curl her lips, betraying a trace of disdain. Just as she was about to say something else, her older cousin shot her a stern glance, causing her to keep her mouth shut.

Han Li completely ignored this and was calmly looking up at the magic tools and spirit herbs being auctioned.

Although the auction was certain to be somewhat lacking considering that it was hosted by local clans, he paid particular attention to it as there was a vast difference in prices between the Great Jin and the Heavenly South. It would serve as preparation for when he would search for rare materials.

After some calm observation, he came to the conclusion that regardless of whether they were spiritual herbs or magic tools, they were significantly more expensive than they were in the Heavenly South. The rarer items were particularly costly.

He came to realize that although the Great Jin was over ten times larger than the Heavenly South, they attracted a far greater number of cultivators considering their complete legacies. This caused a severe lack of magic tools and medicines in comparison to the Heavenly South.

Conversely, it could also be said that the Great Jin was abundant with resources and would have many rare materials that would never be seen in the Heavenly South and even the Scattered Star Seas. In this auction alone, there were a few medicines and tool materials that he didn’t know of.

This was much to Han Li’s joy. It appeared that if he paid a visit to the many high-grade market cities in the Great Jin, there was the possibility of acquiring the few rare materials he needed.

Just as he thought this, the blue-robed middle-aged man on the stage called out to bring out the next item — a tray with three deep-red gems on it. The gems shined with a flicking light similar to a blazing flame. It was rather eye-catching.

“Three Firesmelt Crystals,” the middle-aged man announced with a smile, “An ideal material for refining top-grade fire-attribute magic tools. Fellow Daoists, the bid will now start at five hundred spirit stones.”

Han Li took a casual glance at them and was about to turn his eyes way, but the crystals then caught his eyes and he let out a yelp.

Monarch Soul Divergence’s voice lazily sounded out from the back of his mind, “Youngster Han, from your reaction, it seems those gems have caught your attention.”

“Gems? It seems there are times that even Senior can be mistaken.” Han Li sent out the voice transmission with a chuckle and announced a bid for six hundred spirit stones.

“What? There isn’t anything particular about these gems. Although my cultivation is gone, my spiritual sense remains. I don’t believe I’m mistaken.” Monarch Soul Divergence said with a doubtful tone.

With a strange voice, Han Li replied, “My experience may still be lacking, but I would dare to say there are few in this world that have more experience in demon beast cores than me.”

“This has something to do with demon cores?” Monarch Soul Divergence was stunned from hearing the confidence in Han Li’s voice. Were it not for the many years he spent with him, he would’ve believed Han Li to be confused.

After a moment of silence, Monarch Soul Divergence continued, “Since you’re certain, there must be some reasoning behind it, but I cannot bring myself to believe that there is something strange about those Firesmelt Crystals before I have the evidence. Needless to say, I’m not the only one who didn’t see anything strange about the gems, even the auction appraisers couldn’t find anything exceptional about them, and they are vastly experienced in dealing with rare items.”

After hearing Monarch Soul Divergence’s words of doubt, Han Li smiled and declared a higher bid, forcing the competing bidders to back down.

Happy that the gems were sold for a high price, the middle-aged man glanced at the number on Han Li’s jade plate and loudly shouted, “Eight hundred spirit stones! The three Firesmelt Crystals go to Fellow Daoist Two Hundred and Forty-Three! Please head to the back of the hall to pay for the item.”

When Han Li heard this, he took his jade plate and walked to the side hall.

There was a white-robed Qi Condensation cultivator waiting for him there. When he saw Han Li arrive, he immediately led Han Li to a small waiting room in the rear hall. A moment later, a servant girl brought him a cup of tea before departing.

Han Li glanced at the cup of tea and left it alone as he calmly examined the room.

Soon, a bald old Foundation Establishment cultivator walked in with a beaming smile.

“I am truly ashamed we kept you waiting for so long. Please take a look and see if this is the item you bidded on!” After he said this, he handed a jade box over to Han Li.

Han Li promptly opened the jade box and found three crystals blazing with red light.

With a calm expression, he carefully examined them and remained silent for a long while.

Translator's Thoughts

Even the Monarch himself is outdone by the great Han Li!

ED: Lan

PR: Mangu King

Chapter 912: A Small Town Inn

Han Li brought the large man to an unremarkable room in the building and laid him on the floor. His body was covered in blue frost, and his eyes were open wide and filled with terror.

Han Li then summoned a silver needle in between his fingers with a wave of his hand and stooped down, quickly stabbing the needle several times into the large man’s head. The man trembled as a result and turned completely lax.

Han Li formed a hand gesture and softly muttered an incantation before striking the man’s body with several spell seals. The frost immediately disappeared from the man’s body and he sat up with blank eyes and stiffly crossed his legs, to then wait motionlessly like a puppet.

With azure light covering his face, Han Li waved his sleeve, releasing several various colored spell flags around him. They surrounded the two, creating a Qi concealing spell formation. After activating the formation, his body blurred and reappeared behind the large man.

He raised his hand and pressed it against the top of the large man’s head. At that moment, light brightly glowed from Han Li’s body and enveloped the man.

“What is your name and what is your position in the Kong Clan?” Han Li’s cold and emotionless voice echoed from the light.

The large man listlessly replied, “I am Kong Dou. I am the chief of external affairs.”

“Since when did the Kong Clan occupy Falcon Cloud Village? Where did the original residents go?”

“Seven years ago, the original residences were all relocated to a town by the name of Snowriver.”

“What is the purpose of the Kong Clan’s Grand Assembly?”

“That is...”

After a string of questions, Han Li extracted most of the information he wanted. At the end, he released his grip on the large man and the man immediately fell to the ground. Han Li then took out a medicine pill and forced him to swallow it before striking all the acupoints on the man’s body with a silver needle.

A while later, Han Li stood up and muttered, “With the Worryfree Needle, his recent memories should be sealed. He won’t immediately stir any trouble. It is a pity I can’t make use of the Dreamtear Technique because of my lacking cultivation and save myself all this trouble.”

Han Li shook his hand and then withdrew the spell flags before walking out of the building. Afterwards, he directly made his way to the village’s exit, having completely lost his interest in further participating in the Grand Assembly.

There were quite a few cultivators that were already leaving. As a result, Han Li hadn’t attracted any attention from the guards at the entrance.

In a streak of azure light, he made his way to the small town that the large man had mentioned.

The small town wasn’t very far away from the Snowmound Mountains. Soon, he faintly saw Snowriver Town over the horizon. It was about four times larger than Falcon Cloud Village, but it still barely qualified as a town. When he entered, it was already late and the sky was dark, leaving scarcely few people wandering on the streets. As a result, Han Li’s arrival hadn’t stirred up any attention.

As he walked through the streets, he slowly released his spiritual sense, in case there were any Nascent Soul cultivators hidden nearby.

As he expected, there were cultivators in the town, but a majority of them were low-grade ones. The highest of these cultivators was a Core Formation cultivator that was hidden in a courtyard in the southwest corner of the town. As Han Li stealthily swept his spiritual sense through the town, none of them detected him in the slightest.

After confirming that there were no threats to him present in the town, he concealed his aura and walked down the street, occasionally sweeping his eyes to either side as if he were looking for something.

Soon, he arrived at a wide intersection, what seemed to be the center of the town. He glanced at the sign for an inn and narrowed his eyes before coming to a stop.

The signboard was a meter long and was written with the silver words, “Pleasant Arrival”. It was a common name for inns in the Great Jin. There were surely several hundreds at the very least, if not thousands. Han Li was staring at the teapot mark at the corner of the sign in particular and his eyes wandered.

After examining it for a short moment, he took a deep breath and looked up at the small inn. Seeing that there was no one around, his figure blurred and in a flicker of faint yellow light, he phased through the door as if it weren’t there.

The main hall was pitch-black and completely quiet. It was unknown if there were any guests or if they were all sleeping. After some consideration, Han Li closed his eyes and released his spiritual sense, immersing his mind with the image of the place.

He then silently turned into a gust of wind and disappeared into the darkness.

...

The owner of the Pleasant Arrival Inn was a shriveled old man in his fifties and was among the wealthiest people in the village. After a busy day, he had drawn himself into deep slumber, embracing a young concubine that he had married earlier in the year. But suddenly, he felt an icy bone-chilling wind blow past him, rousing him wide awake. He suddenly opened his eyes and broke out into a cold sweat.

In the pitch blackness, there was someone standing at his bedside, staring at him with cold shiny eyes.

“You...” Just as he was about to yell, a silver line flashed and his throat turned numb; his voice coming to an immediate stop.

“Don’t be loud. Although there are no cultivators in the inn, I don’t wish to alarm anyone. I only want to speak to you about this item.” Han Li raised his hand and a key shining with silver light appeared in front of the old man.

When the old man saw this key, his body trembled and then relaxed. Suddenly, a trace of delight appeared on his face.

The old man hastily jumped up from the bed and gestured with his hands, attempting to speak but no sound came out from his mouth. Han Li smiled and raised his hand, taking out a silver needle from the man’s throat.

The old man coughed several times and eventually regained his voice, then asking, “Could you allow me to examine the silver key?”

After a moment’s pause, Han Li handed it over.

The old man took the silver key and examined it for a long while before handing it back to Han Li with both hands. With a respectful expression, he deeply bowed to Han Li and said, “Are you the great Young Master?”

“You already saw the key,” Han Li said, “Is there a problem?”

“None. Since the Young Master sought me out and he has the genuine key, your identity is certain, but...” The old man then turned his gaze to the young woman sleeping behind him.

Han Li blinked and calmly said, “Don’t worry, I already put her under a spell before I woke you up. No matter how loudly you shout, she will hear none of it.”

“That is good,” the old man sincerely said, “The clan master hasn’t contacted me after several years. I am only a mortal, so I didn’t know what was happening. I didn’t dare to make any inquiries, fearing that I would attract the attention of other cultivators. Now that the Young Master has brought the silver key, I can finally relax. Were if not for the clan head mentioning that you had changed your appearance, I wouldn’t have dared to believe it.”

“Something had truly happened to the Feng Clan. As such, I will need to open the secret reserves and take a few items out. Apart from the clan head, none knows of its location. He should’ve left behind a backup map with you. Give it to me.” Han Li spoke bluntly and with a commanding tone.

“Yes! Since you have the key to the reserve, you clearly have the qualifications to open it. Just a moment, Young Master!” The old man then covered himself in several articles of clothing and led Han Li to the inn’s rear courtyard.

Once they reached the courtyard, the old man grabbed an iron hoe and began to dig at an unremarkable corner of the courtyard. Afterwards, he used his hands to carefully search the soil, eventually finding a stone brick with a common appearance. At that point, he was already covered in sweat.

The old man handed over the brick to Han Li and said, “The location of the secret reserve is sealed in here. There is a restriction on it and I am incapable of opening it, but Young Master should be able to!”

“Of course I do!” Han Li gave the brick a few appraising glances and nodded with satisfaction. Then with a stern expression, he commanded, “Now that I have this item, you shouldn’t stay here any longer. Travel far away and hide your identity!”

The old man’s expression turned dim when he heard this. “Then something must’ve truly happened to the Feng Clan! Don’t worry Young Master, I will immediately depart in a few days. I won’t have the information of Young Master leak out.”

Han Li put away the stone brick and took another glance at the old man’s dim expression. With a moved heart, he flipped his hand and gave a small azure bottle to the old man. “You should know how things stand now. Since you’ve always remained loyal to the Feng Clan, take this bottle of medicine pills. Although you are only a mortal, the pills will strengthen your body and allow you to live a longer life!”

The old man was stunned for a moment before happily replying, “Many thanks for your generosity, Young Master!”

Han Li waved his hand and expressionlessly said, “Alright, I’ll be leaving now. Take care of yourself!” Then in an azure flash, he disappeared from the inn without a trace.

The old man glanced around him in shock and after a long while, he confirmed that Han Li had left. Then, he lowered his head and blankly looked at the medicine bottle before letting out a sigh.

...

When Han Li left the inn, he immediately flew out of the town and went to find a desolate mountain. After dropping down, he summoned an azure brick with a flip of his palm.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Mangu King

ED: Lan

At least Han Li arrived late enough that he didn't see anything unpleasant.

Chapter 913: Killing Intent

With the brick in hand, Han Li took a closer look at it and swept his other hand past it. With fingertips glowing in azure light, they brushed past the brick’s surface and caused it to ripple in white light.

He curled his lips into a smile and nodded.

The brick was consistent with what Feng Yue told him. It was actually a storage pouch in disguise, but it needed to be opened with a specific incantation. If it were opened by force, the items it contained would be turned into ash.

Han Li acquired the incantation from Feng Yue before his death and now uttered it, spitting out a ball of azure light with talisman characters roaming across it. It struck the brick and enveloped it within.

Soon, he formed an incantation gesture with a single hand and quickly pressed against each corner of the brick with his finger. With a light bang, a pitch-black hole appeared on its surface.

He didn’t take the risk of sticking his hand into it. Instead, he slapped the bottom of the brick and it trembled with light, causing two items to fly out from the hole. There was a jade slip that was several inches large and a pile of tightly bundled documents.

He easily caught them in the air with a single hand.

After putting away the brick, Han Li paid no attention to the documents and immediately immersed his spiritual sense into the jade slip. Not long after, his expression warped and turned sullen.

Monarch Soul Divergence saw his reaction and asked, “What is it? Could it be it doesn't contain the location of the Feng Clan’s secret cave?”

“It’s there, and it even details its exact location.” After letting out a long sigh, Han Li withdrew his spiritual sense from the jade slip and frowned.

“Then why are you so gloomy? Could it be the cave is in a dangerous place?” As expected of an eccentric nearing the age of ten thousand years, Monarch Soul Divergence guessed correctly.

Han Li sighed and wore a helpless expression, saying, “It is possible I’ll run into trouble. The secret cave is located deep into the Snowmound Mountains.”

“Why did the Feng Clan establish it there? Could it be they didn’t know there was something strange about the mountains and that cultivators often disappeared?” Monarch Soul Divergence spoke with a flabbergasted tone.

“Who knows?” Han Li said with a wry smile, “Perhaps the Feng Clan Ancestor felt that the more dangerous the area, the safer it would be.”

Monarch Soul Divergence lazily said, “Since they had always used this secret cave, it shouldn’t be too dangerous. There’s no point in being too worried.”

“I hope so! Now that I’ve acquired the map, I can’t let this go by because of some unknown danger. If this goes smoothly, I’ll arrive there in a day.”

Afterwards, Han Li put away the jade slip and then picked up one of the documents, flipping through it before yelping in surprise.

He then said, “These are the deeds for the Feng Clan properties in the mortal world. They can be said to own the most land in the region.”

“Is this anything strange?” Monarch Soul Divergence asked. “The noble clans of the Great Jin and the Immortal clans of the Heavenly South have quite a few differences. Interfering with the mortal world can be considered quite ordinary and it isn’t a disgrace to interact with high ranking government officials and the wealthy. Even vagrant cultivators take the initiative to reach out to them for help. Not only does the Great Jin span across a great amount of land, but the mortals living there exist in far greater density than the Heavenly South. As a result, there are fewer desolate areas, and spirit medicines and spirit stones often found themselves in the hands of mortals. This is different in the Heavenly South where mortals occupy far less land and there is much more wilderness. As such, the Heavenly South cultivators don’t interact much with them.”

Han Li doubtfully said, “You mean to say the many sects allow the royal powers of the Great Jin to control their cultivation resources?”

Monarch Soul Divergence chuckled and said, “It isn’t that they allow it. The Great Jin isn’t like the Heavenly South where there are many different countries and clans, but rather, a single powerful imperial court has ruled over the Great Jin’s mortal world since ancient times.

No matter how powerful a cultivator may be, they won’t dare to harm mortal affairs, or else other sects and powers will use this opportunity as a pretext to move against them. As a result, the Great Jin court had reached a compromise with many of the great powers in the cultivation world. If I remember correctly, the agreement would dictate that the powers or sects wouldn’t pressure or interfere with the mortal imperial court, and would even allow the imperial court to directly hire a few vagrant cultivators in order to preserve the prestige of the court. Of course, the Great Jin imperial family can also nurture a certain number of their own cultivators, but the great sects keep a close eye on them to make sure they don’t get carried away.”

Monarch Soul Divergence continued, “For all of these great powers to acquire cultivation resources and manpower, they had made agreements in secret with the royal family and imperial court. A few particularly powerful officials will likely have been backed by various sects in order to prevent other powers from holding the advantage. Under these circumstances, noble clans began to appear from sects and as a result, noble clans gradually accumulated many mortal properties and became accustomed to interacting with the mortal world. However, these lands should have cultivation resources on them since they’ve been so carefully stored away. These are crucial for the survival of any noble clan.”

When Han Li heard this, he stroked his chin in utter amazement.

“Since these documents are so important, why were they placed here?” Han Li pondered, “Did the Feng Clan Master sensed something was about to happen and put them here as a contingency measure?”

“That’s possible, but this has nothing to do with us,” Monarch Soul Divergence said. “Let’s not waste our time thinking about this and instead head straight to the secret cave. Perhaps there could be a Buddhist Technique to dissolve your baleful Qi.”

“It is as you say, Senior!”

Han Li smiled and then put the documents away in a jade box. After making certain of his direction, he flew off on a magic tool towards the Snowmound Mountains.

...

At that moment, in a tomb underneath the Snowmound Mountains, there were two silhouettes enveloped in green Qi. They were kneeling in front of three stone coffins and remained motionless. Suddenly, two streaks of green light flew out from one of the coffins and each entered into the silhouettes’ foreheads.

“Go! Kill him and retrieve the treasure!” A man spoke from the middle coffin with an imposing tone.

The two silhouettes blurred into streaks of green light and circled the room before flying off.

“Alright, I’ve acquired the appearance of the person who took away the vajra barrier and gave it to the incarnations. The prince’s remnant Qi should also remain in the vajra barrier for a short amount of time. So long as he doesn’t immediately leave the Guanning Province, it will be impossible for him to escape.”

“M... Many thanks... Lord Father!” A happy stutter came out from the other coffin.

The man from the center coffin snorted and said, “I will leave it be this time, but there had better not be more trouble!”

“Yes... this will not happen... again!” The stutter now had a fearful tone.

No further words were spoken from any of the coffins. But after the time it took to finish a meal, a loud bang sounded out. The lid of the middle coffin flew ten meters in the air, and a thin silhouette wearing a crown sat up from it.

“My king, why are you...?” A sweet woman’s voice sounded out from the other coffin.

With glowing red eyes, the man said, “The veins of Yin Qi in the earth will soon erupt and a temporary leave from the tomb room won’t cause me a large loss in cultivation. It is a good opportunity to lend General Ge some aid and dispose of some troublesome characters outside of the noble clans. After I head out, I’ll activate all the restrictions in the tomb to prevent any outsiders from entering.”

After a moment of hesitation, the woman replied, “Yes, your majesty! Please be careful!”

“Don’t worry, my beloved concubine. I will return to the tomb after two days. I won’t be leaving much after that.” The man nodded and then stood up from the coffin.

His body blurred several times and then became indistinct, turning into a cloud of grey mist and disappearing from sight. It was unknown where he went.

Soon, silence filled the tomb room, only to be interrupted by a woman’s deep sigh.

...

When Han Li caught sight of Snowmound Mountain, it was already dawn. Without another thought, he rushed into the mountains on his flying magic tool.

Fearing that he would provoke trouble, he concealed his aura and flew at a low altitude, releasing his spiritual sense to only cover a couple of kilometers, and carefully watching everything that happened nearby.

The location of the Feng Clan’s secret cave was near the heart of the mountain and in a well-concealed area.

After flying around for the day, Han Li looked down at the mountains from the air before dropping down on an unremarkable peak, discovering a huge waterfall that was a kilometer tall. The scene was completely the same as the jade slip described, much to his relief.

After looking at the surging mists of white water, he floated down and formed an incantation gesture. Then he raised his hands and released two streaks of azure light into the waterfall.

A series of muffled rumblings sounded out, followed by the appearance of a three-meter-wide hole in the waterfall. He flew in without hesitation, and soon after, the hole disappeared.

Of course, Han Li didn’t know that in the instant he entered the cave, two green silhouettes were pursuing him from five hundred kilometers away. They snarled with rage and bared their pitch-black fangs, occasionally releasing out series of low roars reminiscent of a dreadful two-headed beast.

However, these two silhouettes couldn’t have known that a few kilometers behind them, there were two hidden figures coldly watching them. They were whispering to each other with lowered heads.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Mangu King

ED: Lan

Danger right around the corner?

Chapter 921: Treasure Possession

“Perhaps!” Han Li had no objections over the claimed power of the altered Sevenflame Fan. Regardless of their shape or form, fire-attribute treasures were most likely specialized in attacks. After all, fire-attribute spiritual power was unrivaled in destructive power amongst the elements.

After Monarch Soul Divergence finished speaking, Han Li said nothing else and lightly waved his sleeve, tossing the two pearls into the air and striking them both with a spell seal. Gold and white light began to glow from the two pearls as they floated motionlessly in the air.

Han Li blinked and proceeded to slap his storage pouch, suddenly taking out an assortment of bottles and boxes and suspending a small cauldron in the air as well.

With his hands in an incantation gesture, he pointed at the cauldron, causing it to tremble as its lid shot up into the air. The lid then flew a circle before suspending itself midair.

Meanwhile, one of the jade boxes opened itself, revealing a pile of overflowing green dust. Han Li blew a mist of azure light onto it and in a flicker of light, about half of the powder was brushed into the air by the light and flew in a circle before entering the small cauldron.

Then with a soft shout, a slim thread of azure flame shot out from his mouth. Despite the meager size of the flame, the small cauldron was immediately ignited upon contact, wrapping its bottom half in roiling fire. But after Han Li released this flame, his complexion paled as his strength had weakened.

Han Li couldn’t help but wryly smile. He didn’t think that forcibly extracting a thread of Nascent flames while his magic power was still sealed would prove so challenging. Of course, this was also in part due to the grave injuries he received in the Moulan Plains that he had yet to fully recover from [1] .

Then, he pointed at a slender jade bottle and had it slowly float over to the small cauldron. The lid of the bottle opened by itself and poured a stream of green liquid into the cauldron, instantly fusing with the green powder.

Han Li uttered an incantation and struck the azure flames into the cauldron with a spell seal, causing it to surge in strength and cover the entire cauldron.

After only a short moment, a faint medicinal scent emitted from the cauldron.

Han Li’s brow stirred and he waved his hand. A jade box then flew halfway into the air and a stalk of fire-red spirit grass flew out from it and directly into the cauldron.

Then as time passed by, Han Li added more materials into the cauldron at regular intervals with meticulous control.

A day later, the refinement process was complete.

Han Li swept his sleeve and caused the Nascent flame lighting the cauldron to disappear. Then the cauldron slowly flew through the air and onto his hand.

Han Li lowered his head and looked into the cauldron, seeing an extremely dense liquid that was several inches deep. It was translucent emerald green and had a strong fragrance.

After looking at it for a moment, Han Li saw that it was exactly the same as the jade slip described. Then he cautiously asked, “Is this spirit liquid acceptable?”

“That is it,” Monarch Soul Divergence slowly said, “I didn’t think that your pill refinement techniques have reached such a profound level. It appears to exceed even mine when I was at my peak. I originally believed that you would fail at least two times before you could refine the spirit liquid! After you immerse the Heavenly Corpse Pearl in the liquid for an entire week, the corpse poison will be entirely extracted. Afterwards, you may consume the pearl as you wish.”

Han Li smiled when he heard this and pointed to the golden pearl that was floating in the air. In the blink of an eye, it shot into the small cauldron and the lid soon followed it down, rigidly sealing it inside.

Han Li placed the cauldron down at the corner of the room and paid no further attention to it.

Refining the other pearl wouldn’t take much more effort. He muttered an incantation and summoned a small ball of purple flames with a flip of his hand. He flung the fireball onto the Snow Crystal Pearl. Then, the crystal brightly shined with white and purple light as the Purple Apex Flames merged with the pearl.

A trace of delight appeared on Han Li’s face and he breathed out a mist of azure light to completely cover the crystal.

The crystal pearl suddenly shrank to the size of a medicine pill and was quickly swept down Han Li’s throat. He then closed his eyes with a solemn expression and his hands formed an incantation before he peered into his body.

The Snow Crystal Pearl was residing in his Dantian and the purple flames had wrapped around it in the form of a continuously-revolving, inch-large lotus flower. Below the pearl, there was a Nascent Soul that was sincerely meditating with its hands held in an incantation gesture. The contrast of the purple flames with the Nascent Soul made for a mysterious appearance.

Han Li felt relief when he saw this.

With Han Li’s Foundation Establishment cultivation, it was impossible for him to directly cultivate the pearl, but fortunately, the Purple Apex Flames were overbearing to the point that he could use the flames to take in the pearl within his body. When he recovers his cultivation, the pearl will have already been partially refined, and in case of an emergency, he would be able to forcibly control it with the Purple Apex Flames.

With the matter of the two pearls dealt with, Han Li didn’t immediately move on to the next matter at hand. Instead, he sat down cross-legged for half a day and recovered a portion of his magic power before he took out a spirit beast pouch from his waist and flung it into the air.

A white mist of light flew out to reveal a golden bubble suspended in the air. Inside the half-finished vajra barrier, the Weeping Soul Beast was lying down and was soundly asleep.

When Han Li saw this, his mouth curled, at a loss of whether he should laugh or cry.

The Weeping Soul Beast was truly too fond of sleeping. Most of the times he would summon it, it would already be asleep.

He wryly chuckled and flicked his finger, striking the golden bubble with a small streak of azure light.

The bubble trembled upon impact and began to bounce around, gently awakening the Weeping Soul Beast inside.

When it saw that it was outside the spirit beast pouch, it let out a series of cries before shooting out of the vajra barrier in a streak of golden light. It flew a circle in the air before nimbly landing on Han Li’s shoulder, then proceeding to rub its soft fur against Han Li’s neck.

After spending the past years with Han Li, it had begun to treat Han Li with great intimacy.

Han Li smiled when he saw this and petted the monkey’s head before turning his attention back the vajra barrier floating in the air.

With a wave of his sleeve, he sent out a gust of azure light at it and engulfed it. Then as brilliant light flickered, the light repeatedly revolved around the treasure, but the golden bubble didn’t react in the slightest.

Han Li wore a pensive expression when he saw this and then quickly formed an incantation gesture and uttered an incantation. Streaks of spell seals followed, striking at the vajra barrier, but apart from a few ripples from the bubble, nothing had changed.

Han Li’s expression changed when he saw this. With his current knowledge and abilities, those were the only two types of treasure possession methods that he knew of.

After letting out a long breath, he repeatedly formed different hand incantations and his voice fluctuated in intensity as he uttered more incantations. A series of rainbow spell seals then struck the vajra barrier with flickers of his fingers, but the vajra barrier still showed no sign of change.

“Senior Soul Divergence, what’s going on? Although my current cultivation is only at Foundation Establishment stage, I should still be able to put this treasure under my ownership.”

Monarch Soul Divergence calmly said, “Vajra barriers are a protective treasure refined by corpse flames using Buddhist crystal relics. It was a treasure that was originally rarely seen as crystal relics and corpse flames would mutually oppose one another. It should come as no surprise that ordinary treasure possession techniques wouldn’t work. How about you try and use the incantations I gave you for possession of the vajra relic?”

“Alright, I’ll give it a try.” Han Li agreed without another thought.

After half a day had passed, Han Li used his newly learned spell seals to force the vajra barrier to shrink and fall into his hand, much to his relief. However, if he wished to finish the refinement process for the vajra barrier, it would prove quite troublesome.

Not even his Nascent flames would be able to temper the vajra barrier, and Monarch Soul Divergence didn’t have any answers to this problem as well.

According to Monarch Soul Divergence musings, the final step of the vajra barrier’s refinement process would require myriad year corpse flames.

When Han Li heard this, he couldn’t help but roll his eyes and gloomily snort, “Myriad year corpse flames? Are you suggesting I go to the Snowmound Mountains and deliver myself to King Glorious Blaze?”

When Monarch Soul Divergence heard this, he snorted back in response but remained silent afterwards.

Just as Han Li felt completely helpless over the matter despite having already acquired the vajra barrier, the Weeping Soul Beast sitting on Han Li’s shoulder suddenly spat out a wisp of grey-white flames from its mouth out of boredom, striking at the vajra barrier floating in the air.

The originally still vajra barrier then let out a series of groans as the flames engulfed it and began to fluctuate in shape within the grey flames.

Han Li was greatly shocked by the sight of this.

“Myriad year corpse flame!” Monarch Soul Divergence muttered in amazement.

[1]. While Han Li was in the Moulan Plains, he was ambushed by a late-Nascent Soul cultivator and have yet to fully recover since.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Lan, Mangu King

Chapter 922: The Gan Clan

At the border of the central and northern portions of the Jin Empire laid a region that was ranked among the smallest in land of the thirty-six regions of the empire but was also ranked the top five in terms of wealth. There were many fields and rivers amassing a great amount of wealth and there were many large regions of spirit mountains as well. Mortals on those mountains would even commonly see Immortals dressed in Daoist and Buddhist robes fly off into the horizon. Needless to say, Daoism and Buddhism were prevalent in the region and their temples were profusely found throughout. Regardless of one’s standing or wealth, they would always pay great respect to either of these schools.

But in addition to these two prevalent schools, one could see the influence of many Confucian schools in the many cities and towns in the area.

There were thirty-nine of these Confucian schools with one of the largest of these schools consisting of experts of Confucian teachings with many government officials in their ranks. On the other hand, the smallest of these schools only had ordinary Confucian instructors that could only explain the most basic aspects of Confucianism. If they felt that any of their disciples were outstanding, they would be recommended to a higher school, granting poorer disciples a good opportunity to advance.

After all, Confucian scholars that graduate from a high-grade Confucian School were welcomed to the higher echelon of the Jin Empire. Confucian scholars that stem from the highest schools are even heavily recruited by nobility of all ranks.

The Taichang Prefecture’s capital city, Taichang City, was the location of one such of these prestigious Confucian academies.

Although the city wasn’t ranked amongst the best in the empire, it was one of the centers of commerce in the Nan Province and was where the rich and powerful took residence. There were four families titled as nobility that resided in the city as well as countless people of every trade.

In the Taichang City’s west side resided the Gan Clan, a clan of particularly wealthy merchants. They possessed over twenty restaurants in their prefecture’s cities. In smaller cities, they were hegemony of wealth, but in Taichang City, there were simply among the many elites that resided there.

But even among the elite, the Gan Clan did own a particularly large estate in the district where the wealthy resided and had over forty servants in their employment.

One day as the sun blazed at noon, a youth in Confucian robes slowly walked down a street. The young man appeared in his early twenties and wore a package on his back that was thickly wrapped in grey cloth and covered in dust.

As he walked down the street, he repeatedly looked around and soon spotted the Gan Clan’s glossy gate. When he read the words “Gan Estate”, he unconsciously smiled.

When he approached the gate, he examined it for a moment before pounding the iron door.

Thud. Thud. Hurried footsteps arrived from the other side of the gate.

The gate cracked open to a middle-aged man wearing servant robes who had a respectful expression on his face.

When the servant saw the youth, his respectful expression suddenly froze before quickly fading away. He stood up straight and asked with a doubtful tone, “Who is your esteemed self looking for?” He then examined the youth as if trying to make out his origins.

The youth cupped his hands in a salute and smiled. “Is this Uncle Gan Chi’s residence?”

After examining the quality of the youth’s clothes, his original display of contempt had disappeared. Instead, he was now greatly alarmed after hearing Han Li speak and he respectfully said, “Uncle Gan Chi? Gan Chi is the esteemed name of my master. Then young sir must be...”

“I am Han Li. Uncle Gan Chi is a distant relative of mine. I have made this trip to pay my respects to him.” Han Li continued to smile as he spoke.

It was now a year after he had cultivated in whole-hearted seclusion. During this time, he drawn the aid of the Heavenly Corpse Pearl and the vajra relic to refine the first layer of the Brightjade Arts. With that done, the roiling baleful Qi was mostly calmed, much to Han Li’s delight, but it still remained a priority for him to deal with. As such, he had hurried over to the Gan Clan for the next step in his plan to rid himself of the baleful Qi.

After a moment of hesitation, the middle-aged servant said, “So it was Young Sir Han. Unfortunately, the Master had left in the morning to meet with his colleagues. Currently, the Eldest Young Master is in charge of the residence. Shall I make a report to him?”

“Please, I must thank you for the trouble,” Han Li calmly replied.

“Please wait a moment, Young Sir. I will immediately make the report.” The middle-aged man bowed and closed the gate before heading back.

Han Li idly stood in front of the gate and examined the surroundings of the huge estate, occasionally catching sight of a few carriages that passed by.

Although he hadn’t swept his spiritual sense past the city, it was clear there were a large number of cultivators in it. Furthermore, there were many areas that housed many high-grade cultivators. This was rather odd to him as he couldn’t fathom why these cultivators would have such a high interest in the mortal world.

After the time it took to finish a cup of tea, the door creaked open to reveal an embroidered-robed youth with a refined appearance. Standing behind him was the servant from before.

After the youth gave Han Li an appraising look, he courteously said, “You must be Sir Han. I am Gan Yu. I heard that you were a distant relative of the Gan Clan. Although I’ve never heard of this before, I cannot forget my manners. If you’d like, will Sir Han like to follow me to the living room?”

“So you’re the Son of Uncle Gan. Since you’ve given me the invitation, I will not refuse it.” Without another thought, Han Li promptly agreed.

With a faint smile, Gan Yu stepped to the side and welcome Han Li inside. Then, the black gates silently closed.

...

Two hours later, the Gan Clan Master, a plump fifty-year-old man wearing blue noble robes named Gan Chi, returned to the Gan Estate by carriage.

Gan Chi looked at the gatekeeper below the carriage and asked, “Has anything happened while I was away?”

The middle-aged gatekeeper sincerely replied, “Lord, there is a young man surnamed Han that had arrived. He claims that he is your nephew and is waiting in the living room with the young lord. They seem to be having an excited conversation.”

Just as Gan Chi stepped off the carriage and approached the estate gate, he paused and muttered, “A nephew? Surnamed Han?” A trace of doubt could be heard from his voice.

“What? Is this person a fraud?” In his alarm, the gatekeeper hastily suggested, “Shall I call for the guards?”

“It’s hard to say if he’s truly a fraud. I do think I have such a relative, but it has been quite some time so my memory fails me. Continue to guard the gate. There is no need to involve yourself over the matter!” Gan Chi recovered his calm and rebuked the gatekeeper before hurrying into the estate. Without even taking the time to change his clothes, he rushed into the main hall.

Just as he entered the entrance of the main hall, he heard a cheerful and familiar voice speak, “I admire Brother Han’s deep understanding of the Confucian teachings. But with regards to those great words, my understanding is that...” The voice clearly belonged to his eldest son and he seemed to be excitedly conversing with the guest.

When the old man heard this, his expression grew somewhat sullen and a trace of unease was betrayed from his eyes. But a short moment later, he gritted his teeth and walked into the hall.

“Lord Father, this is Sir Han.” When Gan Yu saw his father walked in, he immediately stood up and saluted him.

“Yes. I’ve already heard from the gatekeeper,” Gan Chi waved his arm at his son and then stared at Han Li, asking, “Then your esteemed self must be the one who claims to be my distant relative. Do you have a letter or a keepsake perhaps?”

At that moment, Han Li stood up and couldn’t help but smile when he heard that question. Then without another word, he handed over a sparkling white jade pendant.

When Gan Chi saw this jade pendant, his expression became moved.

He solemnly took the jade pendant and closely examined it once through before saying, “So you must be the young descendant, Brother Han. Please follow me to my study. I wish to ask about a matter pertaining to my deceased aunt.” Gan Chi grabbed Han Li’s wrist with great excitement and pulled him out from the hall.

Remaining behind in the hall, Gan Yu stood up in shock and muttered, “Your aunt? Was there such a relative in the Gan Clan?”

After they entered the study, Gan Chi carefully closed the door of the study and deeply saluted, saying, “I pay my respects, Sir Han!”

“Stand up,” Han Li said. Then with a wave of his sleeve, he shook Gan Chi’s body straight with a gust of blue light before continuing, “There is no need for you to ask about my origins. You only need to know from today on that I was sent here by the people in charge of you.”

Gan Chi’s doubts were washed away by Han Li’s display of magic power and he respectfully replied, “Yes! So you are close to the two sirs that were related to the Gan Clan... but they disappeared since twenty years ago. Young Master Han couldn’t have come at a better time.”

Han Li nodded and then said in a commanding tone, “I’ve only arrived at your Gan Clan in passing. I have more important affairs to attend to, but I will require assistance from your connections to the mortal world.”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Lan

Chapter 925: Essencejoin Devouring Arts

The offer had thrown Han Li’s plans into chaos. He didn’t know anything about this sect, or if it would be as fitting for him as the Pure Revelations Academy. Additionally, if he refused such a good offer and entered the academy regardless, he feared he would attract the suspicion of Senior Teacher Lu. As such, Han Li couldn’t help but roll his eyes at Nun Hualian’s offer and repeatedly cursed in his heart.

“Senior Hualian, I will be honest to you. I don’t know much about the Royal Serenity Monastery. But since it is a female monastery, it shouldn’t be very accommodating in terms of cultivation methods and techniques for male cultivators.” As Han Li’s thoughts quickly stirred, he found something wrong with the situation and was barely able to raise an objection.

Nun Hualian smiled and calmly said, “So it turned out Junior Han was worried over this matter, but there will be no problem. Our Royal Serenity Monastery is only a branch of the Three Royals Monastery. There is also our brother branch, the Royal Yang Monastery, which is our male counterpart. There will be no lack of male cultivation techniques for you. I’ve also noticed that your body is lacking noble spirit Qi. You would have to cultivate this new Qi after entering Pure Revelations Academy, so our cultivation techniques should be much easier for you to cultivate. Of course, if you manage to cultivate Confucian sects to completion, you will be able to employ abilities far beyond Daoist techniques, but this is too early to speak of for Fellow Daoist Han. Could it be that you believe the Royal Serenity Monastery to be beneath you?”

Senior Teacher Lu calmly added on, “Fellow Daoist Hualian’s words are reasonable. Our Confucian techniques are slower than even Buddhist techniques at the beginning. Young Friend Han, it seems more suitable for you to enter the Royal Serenity Monastery. Since Fellow Daoist Hualian has agreed to look after you, you have a chance of achieving Foundation Establishment if you accept her offer.”

When Han Li heard this, he was completely speechless. It seems he had no choice but to deviate from his original plan. Fortunately, the Royal Serenity Monastery also shares the spirit veins of Jadefield Mountain. So long as he was careful, nothing strange should happen.

With that thought, Han Li could only accept his bad luck. With feigned excitement, he said, “Since both Senior had made this recommendation to me, this opportunity must be good. I will agree to it!”

After hearing this, Nun Hualian nodded and Senior Teacher Lu silently smiled. As for Teacher Yan, he couldn’t raise any opposition to his agreement despite his wishes for Han Li to enter the Confucian sect.

With this matter settled, the four chatted in the room for a moment more, speaking not of the fantastical tales that occurred in the cultivation world but rather the changes of the Great Jin political court, much to Han Li’s bewilderment.

It wasn’t too surprising with regards to the Confucian sects as their interests are tied to the mortal world. But he found it rather strange for a monastery nun to talk about politics with even moderate interest. Could it be that the Royal Serenity Monastery was also a cultivation sect that was involved with the mortal world? Han Li couldn’t help but ponder about this.

As the conversation in the room was continued with vigor, footsteps sounded out from the outside and a young voice said, “Reporting to Martial Ancestor. As per your orders, I have brought the Purple Essence Copper from the storehouse.”

“Oh, bring it in,” Senior Teacher Lu said without another thought.

“Purple Essence Copper!” Han Li’s heart stirred. This ore was an outstanding material for refining top grade magic tools and treasures. It might not be particularly valuable to Han Li, but it was undoubtedly a rare item to those in front of him.

As Han Li thought this, the room doors were pushed open to reveal a fair child that was twelve years old. He walked in with a large red tray covered with a bulging silver cloth. Then, he respectfully placed the tray on the table in front of Nun Hualian and Senior Teacher Lu.

Senior Teacher Lu glanced at the boy and calmly ordered, “You may leave. There is no need for you to wait here.” The child acknowledged the command and deeply bowed before heading out of the room.

Afterwards, Senior Teacher Lu promptly handed the tray over to Nun Hualian. Then with a smile, he said, “Fellow Daoist Hualian, this is the Purple Essence Copper we are lending to you. Your monastery has looked everywhere for this material. It appears you truly plan on refining a precious treasure. Could it be a top-grade magic tool or a magic treasure?”

Nun Hualian hesitated for a moment and then apologetically said, “This isn’t very clear to me. I am only following the orders of Fourth Senior Nun. If Senior wishes to know more about this, it would be better for him to ask her. They should tell you the truth.”

When Senior Teacher Lu heard the mention of Fourth Senior Nun, his expression changed for a moment and then he responded with a chuckle, “There is no need to do that. It was only a passing question.”

Nun Hualian smiled and lifted the cloth off of the tray, revealing a pile of golden stones glowing with purple light.

She grinned after she saw the tray-full of Purple Essence Copper and uttered a word of thanks before taking it into her storage pouch in a sweep of light.

With her objective fulfilled, Nun Hualian uttered a few more words with Senior Teacher Lu before taking her leave.

He didn’t urge her to stay and promptly called for the child to lead Nun Hualian out of the academy. Han Li bid his farewell as well and followed after the woman.

After Han Li and Nun Hualian left, silence filled the hall.

Teacher Yan and Senior Teacher Lu didn’t speak for some time and simply looked at each other in silence. Teacher Yan in particular had a troubled expression.

Senior Teacher Lu eventually broke the silence and spoke with a sullen emotionless tone, “How are your preparations? In order to deal with that monster Niu Tiande, I will have to rely on my Essencejoin Devouring Arts. Now that we are at the final strand, do you have any second thoughts on keeping your life?

Teacher Yan’s expression turned sullen and he snorted, saying, “So long as I am able to take revenge for the extermination of my clan, what is the cost of a single life in comparison? My sole worry is that after you finish cultivating your ability, you would be unwilling to provoke the old devil out of fear for his fierce flames.” Reminded of his family, he clasped his hands with force, deeply sinking his fingernails into his palm.

Senior Teacher Lu wasn't angered by his words and calmly replied, “ Hehe! Why does Brother Yan have such doubts towards me? Didn’t I already say once you assist me in cultivating this ability, I will inherit your body’s noble spirit Qi which will contain traces of your resentment? If I don’t eliminate this Niu Tiande, there will come a day I will no longer be able to use this Qi. In order to make sure that I can still make use of it, I must eliminate him. Besides, does Brother Yan feel that there is anyone else that will assist you in killing this wretch? And someone that has no fear of retaliation from the Black Yang Sect?”

Teacher Yan pondered for a moment, then saying, “You’re right. Although I’ve strived to make friends with a few cultivators over the years, none of them have abilities or cultivation as vast as Brother Lu’s, and only you are willing to assist me in getting revenge for the extermination of my family. It isn’t that the others aren’t capable, but that they’re unwilling to provoke one of the ten Great Devil Dao Sects on the behalf of a mortal like me.”

“Naturally,” Senior Teacher Lu sighed, “That Niu Tiande is an external affairs enforcer of the Black Yang Sect. How could a small sect dare to provoke them? Confucian sects like ours were always at odds with the devil Dao, so there is no fear of worsened relations. In a show of my sincerity, I have agreed to every one of your requests in the last five years. This clearly illustrates my kind intentions.”

Teacher Yan’s expression turned icy and he coldly stared at Senior Teacher Lu in silence.

Seeing that Teacher Yan wouldn’t yield, Senior Teacher Lu wryly smiled and helplessly said, “Fine, in order to set Brother Yan’s heart at ease, I am willing to face the portrait of our noble sage and swear a heartlock oath. In the future, if I do not fulfill my oath, my noble spirit Qi won’t progress in the slightest.”

Teacher Yan let out a long sigh and his brow twitched. Then, with a stiff expression, he said, “Good, that will do. Then don’t hesitate to use this body to assist in your cultivation. It isn’t that I can’t trust Brother Lu, but as the sole surviving member of the Yan Clan, I cannot help but be more cautious.”

Senior Teacher Lu waved his hand and calmly said, “I naturally understand why Brother Yan is being difficult. The cultivation arrangements will take place in one month. Please finish making your funeral arrangements before returning to the academy.”

Teacher Yan nodded and the room sank into silence once more.

Then, he suddenly broke the silence and asked, “That’s right, why did that Royal Serenity Monastery nun had to take away Han Li? Could it be that the academy didn’t wish for another tool refinement disciple?”

Senior Teacher Lu casually smiled and said, “I was merely using the situation for my own benefit. The treasure that the Royal Serenity Monastery is refining should be quite important. They are lacking even subordinates to refine materials. Although our academy can lend low-grade tool refinement disciples to Royal Serenity Monastery, we will find it difficult as we don’t know what they will be subject to. With the appearance of Young Friend Han, we were able to fulfill their request without troubling the sect.”

When Scholar Yan heard this, he calmly let the matter drop. If he felt truly ill over the matter, he would’ve pressed his friend further.

Meanwhile, Nun Hualian was bringing Han Li along on a scarf magic tool. They were flying toward a shorter point of Illusory Cloud Peak.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Lan

Chapter 943: A Chance Encounter

After the time it took to finish a meal, Han Li appeared in front of the jade residence with an unmoved expression.

Elder Wang frowned for a moment, but when Han Li arrived in front of him, he smiled and asked, “Is the treasure to Fellow Daoist Han’s satisfaction?"

“The residence isn’t large, but it has rooms for pill refinement, beast nurturing, and everything else I can think of. However, there is something that I’m unsure of. I’ll need Brother Wang to explain it to me.”

“If you have any questions relating to the Hidden Fortune Mansion, I will answer to the best of my ability,” Elder Wang cheerfully replied.

Han Li met his gaze and asked, “I’ll be blunt then. I understand that the greatest advantage of the Hidden Fortune Mansion is that it can be enlarged and shrunk at will, allowing it to be easy to carry, but will it behave like a storage pouch and shrink the items that are already inside of it? And will spirit beasts properly shrink inside without a problem?”

“The mansion is able to compress all furnishings that it was refined with, but living things like spirit beasts will not do. Even if they possessed profound transformation abilities, they would be destroyed from the spatial pressure of the mansion’s reduction. Even if they are able to endure the immense pressure, they will be sealed from the outside world and disconnected from the world’s spiritual Qi, surely leading them to death.”

Elder Wang gave a full and honest explanation. After all, this was something that would be easily discovered with a bit of testing.

After a moment of thought, Han Li added, “In that case, I would also have to store away the medicinal plants in the garden each time I put away the mansion. Is this correct?”

Elder Wang frowned in thought and spoke with a blank expression, “That’s right, Fellow Daoist. This is an unsolvable problem for these Hidden Fortune Mansions. Despite that, you are able to summon or send the mansion at your beck and call as a result of its attached restrictions. It isn’t comparable to ordinary treasures in terms of value.”

Han Li smiled, “That’s also one of the reasons I am interested in acquiring one, but I fear I might not have enough the means to acquire it.”

“You mean to say that you plan on trading for this item?” Elder Wang’s eyes lit up with pleasant surprise.

With an easy expression, Han Li said, “I have some rare materials on hand that I have no use for. Once you give me the clear details on the mansion’s price, we can discuss what to specifically trade for.”

“Of course. All of what we desire is in this jade slip. Please take a look.” With a wide smile, his sleeve trembled as he sent a streak of white light towards Han Li.

Han Li caught it and then began to read it with his spiritual sense.

...

Two hours later, Han Li left the gates of the Hidden Fortune Pavilion with Elder Wang sending him off with a smile. Before departing, Han Li gave a salute back and uttered a few words of farewell.

Elder Wang stared at Han Li’s departing figure and then returned inside the pavilion with a satisfied expression.

Han Li was also smiling as he stroked the bulging storage pouch at his waist.

After he traded for the Hidden Fortune Mansion using a large number of rare materials, he took out a few demon cores and spirit herbs, and sold them for an astonishing amount of spirit stones.

When he thought to sell even more materials, he saw the astonished look on Elder Wang’s face, and grew vigilant despite having found the scene humorous.

As humans would often kill themselves over greed, Han Li believed that if he revealed any more wealth, it would surely attract trouble despite his status as a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator.

Although the Hidden Fortune Pavilion had a grand reputation and should be reasonably trustworthy, he had to be especially careful since he was under the identity of an overseas cultivator; it was quite possible he had tempted Elder Wang into conspiring against him. With this in mind, Han Li had released a thread of spiritual sense into his surroundings after he left, ensuring that no one was following him.

After shortly attending to this matter, he found an empty alleyway, and his body blurred as it underwent a sudden transformation with azure light shining from his clothes.

When he emerged, he looked like a blue-robed middle-aged Confucian scholar with long facial hair and a bright face. Apart from late-Nascent Soul cultivators, nobody would be able to see through his true appearance.

With this done, Han Li was able to continue browsing shops without worry, but to his disappointment, none of them had the materials he needed.

It wasn’t that the larger stores didn’t have anything of value, rather that the materials the shopkeepers had recommended to Han Li weren’t required for refining Monarch Soul Divergence’s grand puppet or the Triflame Fan. And with no lack of ordinary ancient treasures either, he decided not to purchase any.

Not long after, Han Li arrived at the end of the street and faced an imposing stone building. ‘It seems we’ll have to wait for the auction to convene.’

It was a simply decorated palace by the name of Treasureshine Hall. The scope of the building was colossal as it consisted of three floors with each story stretching over sixty meters high. The huge building could fit over a thousand cultivators, was probably the reason why the auction was being held there.

There were several Foundation Establishment cultivators standing guard at the entrance, preventing ordinary cultivators from entering as the auction was being prepared.

In addition to Han Li, there were other cultivators that were loitering nearby the building, knowing that it was the location of the grand auction.

Han Li took a deep glance at the Treasureshine Hall and was about to leave when a group of four cultivators suddenly emerged from it.

When Han Li saw them, his expression dramatically changed and he turned around with feigned indifference, intending on leaving immediately.

But just as he took a few steps, he could hear a sweet voice speaking from behind him, “Please wait, Fellow Daoist.” His heart sank and his cheek twitched before he decided to remain in place.

After turning around, Han Li’s expression remained calm as he said, “Do you have any business with me?”

Twenty meters away, there was a white-clothed woman with a face covered in a veil. She was currently examining him along with her three companions.

He swept his spiritual sense past them to discover that they were all Nascent Soul-stage cultivators. Most notably, the middle-aged black-robed man standing behind her had mid-Nascent Soul cultivation like himself, causing Han Li to feel somewhat sullen.

Seeing that she captured his attention for the time being, the white clothed woman’s eyes beamed and she said with a sweet tone, “No, I simply wish to befriend you since I saw your cultivation was unordinary. Does Fellow Daoist mind?”

From her tall stature and captivating movements, Han Li could tell she was no doubt a remarkably beautiful woman. However, he wasn’t particularly flattered by her invitation; rather, he wanted to immediately leave knowing the woman was the Endless Sky Saintess.

“Befriend me, are you serious? I would be honored to befriend a person of your cultivation and quality, but I have an urgent matter to attend to and cannot stay for long.” Despite the apprehension he felt, Han Li retained a calm appearance and saluted them before turning around.

In a blur, Endless Sky Saintess blocked Han Li’s path and spoke with a frown, “There is no need for Fellow Daoist to be in such a rush. I still have a few questions to ask you. Could you give me a moment?”

Han Li’s expression turned solemn and he spoke with a harsh tone, “Oh, you want to question me?”

The black-robed cultivator lost his patience and asked, “Lady Lin, do you have a dispute with this Fellow Daoist?” The black-robed cultivator lost his patience and a layer of faint black Qi began to cover his face. It was clear at a glance that he was a cultivator deeply skilled in devilish arts.

The Saintess brushed back the hair from her face and coldly stared at Han Li. “No, this is the first time that I’ve seen him, though he reminds me of the person that I’ve been seeking in the Great Jin for these past years for some unknown reason. As such, I wish to make sure that I am not mistaken.”

The black-robed cultivator’s handsome face suddenly contorted as he gazed at Han Li with a hostile gaze. “What? You mean to say this is the person who used my sect’s Ghost Sifting Banner?”

The Saintess narrowed her eyes and said with an unwavering tone, “I’m not sure, his appearance and stature are different, but he gives me a similar impression. And the person I am looking for carries a bamboo tube on his back.”

“A bamboo tube!” When the black-robed devil cultivator saw this, his gaze dropped to the wrapped bundle on Han Li’s back.

Just as he attempted to look into it, he suddenly felt a powerful spiritual sense repel him. In his shock, he hastily withdrew it with an icy expression.

“Fellow Daoist, I am the Yin Sifting Sect’s Ge Tianhao. Could your ‘esteemed self’ reveal what you are carrying on your back? So long as it isn’t what we think, we won’t continue to bother you.” He spoke slowly and caution began to appear on his face.

As for the other two similarly-dressed cultivators in their party, they exchanged a glance and then blurred, appearing at Han Li’s side to coerce him.

Han Li remained silent as he stood in place with his hands held behind his back.

Although nothing had actually happened yet, the air surged with suffocating hostility.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: akiwimain, Lan

Chapter 947: Glacial Quintessence

The youth paled and said with an uncertain tone, “That’s impossible. My master’s cultivation may be inferior to that villain, but he should’ve still had a chance to escape.”

Ge Tianhao coldly snorted in annoyance and said, “What do you know? Let alone early-Nascent Soul cultivators, that scoundrel has already killed cultivators of a similar grade. It is no surprise that your master wasn’t able to protect himself. You had best explain in detail what Old Man Xiao had told you.”

At that moment, the Endless Sky Saintess quickly swept her spiritual sense through the area and blurred twenty meters away. She took an picked something off the ground and carefully examined it before wearing an unsightly expression.

“Master didn’t say anything,” the youth muttered, “He only gave me a magic tool and told me to come find you if something strange happened to it or if he didn’t return in time.”

The Saintess waved her hand and tossed the item to the youth. “There is no doubt that your master has met mishap. Isn’t this a part of an ancient treasure your master used?”

The youth hastily reached out and his heart dropped at the sight of it. It was a small piece of yellow wood and it faintly shined with a familiar light.

“How could my master’s wooden shield possibly be destroyed? It possessed astonishing defensive power and durability...” The youth’s complexion had become completely bloodless.

“Fellow Daoist Lin, you mentioned that you weren’t convinced that this person truly had the ability to kill opponents of equivalent cultivation ⸺ it appears he is more vicious than we originally believed. Although the old man had early-Nascent Soul cultivation and was skilled in many exceptional evasion techniques, he was killed before he even had the chance to call for help. He could already possesses the capabilities of a late-Nascent Soul cultivator, we don’t have the strength to capture him.”

The Saintess frowned and asked, “What? Brother Ge, don’t tell me you’ve given up on taking back your sect signature treasure? Since the Ghost Sifting Banner is in his hands, he is most likely the culprit who killed your sect’s fourth elder.”

Ge Tianhao dryly laughed. “Even if he was a late-Nascent Soul cultivator, our sect would still pursue him for killing one of our sect elders and seizing our sect’s signature treasure. However, your people seem to have a deep hatred for this person as well. Why else would you stay away from your people for so many years?”

The Saintess pursed her lips before wearing a sweet smile. “So long as this person is killed, I’ll increase the reward by a fifth of what was agreed. However, our sacred temple requires one of the treasures in his possession.”

“Make it three-tenths! The sect will lose a vast number of men in the hunt for this formidable cultivator. As for that treasure, we’ve already agreed to it previously and don’t intend to go back on our word.”

The Saintess hesitated and then said, “Our temple will agree to those conditions.”

“Very good. I’m sure with your status, you will keep your promise,” Ge Tianhao turned to the Yin Sifting Sect Elder at his side and said, “Junior Martial Brother Hu, send out a voice transmission talisman to gather all of the sect elders and disciples near the Jin Capital. Since he’s appeared in the market, he will definitely be participating in the grand auction. We must use all our strength to take advantage of this opportunity. However, our actions must avoid attention from the other sects and our low-grade disciples mustn’t act without the support of several sect elders. In truth, it would be safest to draw him into a spell formation and attack him there.”

“Should I report this to Sect Master Fang? After all, he was the one who sent the Fourth Elder to take care of him in the past.”

With a trace of hesitation, Ge Tianhao said, “With the plan to restore our Ghost Sifting Banners left half-completed and the loss of the Fourth Elder, the Grand Elders have become dissatisfied with Sect Master Fang, and I heard he is currently refining a vicious treasure in seclusion. Even if he were to immediately come, he wouldn’t be able to make it into the grand auction in time. We can later send him a sound transmission talisman though. That way, if we fail, we can make another attempt with the aid of his forces.”

Having settled the matter, they immediately departed. Of course, they had disturbed many mortals with their appearance before they vanished from sight.

Although the Jin Capital had rules that restricted flying, cultivators from sects as large as the Yin Sifting Sect didn’t take them to heart.

...

Meanwhile, Han Li was walking down a small road over ten kilometers away, looking through the large assortment of items in the old man’s storage pouch.

Then, he came to a sudden stop as a trace of astonishment appeared on his face.

Monarch Soul Divergence lazily asked, “What, Have you discovered something?”

“What could this be? I’ve never seen something like it before.” With a flip of his hand, Han Li took out a slender jade bottle that was seven inches tall and had an exquisite appearance.

He stroked the bottle to find a stinging icy sensation, causing him to reveal a trace of surprise. Then, he shook the small bottle and heard the faint sounds of splashing liquid.

Han Li raised his brow and muttered, “Maybe some sort of spirit liquid? Though the bottle itself is quite strange, I can’t see into it with my spiritual sense.”

Monarch Soul Divergence warned, “You’d best wait until you return to open it. This is a mortal’s road and it could attract attention if something strange happened.”

“Obviously.” With a shake of his hand, the small bottle disappeared from sight.

Monarch Soul Divergence added, “Youngster Han, since you’ve revealed your identity, you’ll have to be more careful. The Yin Sifting Sect and the Endless Sky Saintess won’t leave you be. They’ve probably already guessed that you’ll be participating in the grand auction.”

“It is of no concern,” Han Li replied, “I don’t believe there will be another spiritual beast in the Jin Capital that can see through illusions. So long as I avoid the late-Nascent Soul cultivators, nothing should happen. Even if it's dangerous, we’ll have to take the risk to be able to gather the materials we need in time.”

Monarch Soul Divergence indifferently said, “That will be fine. But since you’ve come here to find materials for my grand puppet, I will make an exception and use the Great Development Technique’s Soulfright Thorn Technique to assist you in combat when it becomes too dangerous.”

“Many thanks, Senior. Your words have put many of my worries at ease.” Han Li replied with a happy heart.

Two hours later, Han Li slowly walked back to the Daoist monastery he last stayed at. He chatted with the building’s master for a moment before calmly returning to his room.

The room was then quickly surrounded by several temporary spell formations and Han Li proceeded to thoroughly examine the slender dark-green bottle.

As he nimbly opened it, a cloud of glacial light shot out, causing the temperature in the room to violently drop. Even Han Li felt his body shiver in contact with the cold light despite having cultivated the Purple Apex Flames.

In his alarm, he hastily covered his body in a layer of purple flames and the mist was immediately repelled when it made contact, spreading across the room and covering it in a thick layer of ice. Were if not for the restrictions he placed on the room, he feared the icy Qi would’ve left the room.

Its coldness was about the same as the Celestial Ice Flames.

“What in the world is this?” With purple flames covering his hand, he shook the small bottle with an interested look and gazed at the glacial light that shined out from it.

He saw it dissipate midair and cover the room in more frost. He eventually brought the bottle to his his eye as blue light flickered from it. Past the sparkling white mist, he could see a silver liquid that shined with blinding brilliance.

Monarch Soul Divergence’s voice suddenly spoke with excitement, “This is... Carefully pour a drop of the liquid onto a jade disk and let me look at it.”

Han Li’s heart stirred and he wordlessly took out a palm-sized jade disk from his storage pouch. With a slight tremble from the small bottle in his other hand, a drop of silver liquid dropped onto the platter and released a clear ring upon landing. Unexpectedly, it had turned into a silver pearl after landing and continued to roll around in the plate.

To Han Li’s surprise, the silver pearl didn’t release the slightest glacial energy and appeared rather ordinary.

Monarch Soul Divergence took a deep breath and said, “As I thought, only a bottle of Myriad Year Ice Jade could nurture Glacial Quintessence.”

“I’ve never heard of Myriad Year Ice Jade before, nor Glacial Quintessence. They seem quite rare.”

Monarch Soul Divergence calmly replied, “Glacial Quintessence is a type of jade essence that is used in tool and pill refinement. However, finding one being nurtured in Myriad Year Glacial Jade is something that is rarely seen in this world. If I remember correctly, the North Night Palace in the Great Jin’s northwest should have a small bottle that they keep as a legacy treasure. I’ve never heard of this item existing in another place in this world. Ah yes, that Snow Crystal Pearl of yours is something that was refined from the Myriad Year Glacial Jade as well.”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Lan, akiwimain

Chapter 950: The Grand Auction

“Second Uncle, don’t worry. Our preparations for the auction are flawless. We’ve hired unremarkable vagrant cultivators to purchase the items we require. On the surface, they are unrelated to our Ye Clan and after the auction is over, they will all be killed and silenced.”

With some hesitation, the beautiful woman asked, “But how are you dealing with matters on the Emperor’s side? The High Zenith Sect’s Sable and the Heavenly Devil Sect’s Sevenwonders were sent to the palace. Could it be due to the rumors?”

When the old man heard this, he wore an anxious expression.

The middle-aged man’s cheek twitched and he answered with a solemn tone, “Rest assured, Eldest Brother has already probed their reason for coming— the Three Royal Monastery’s Mountain Crushing Seal. Since it is on the verge of completion, the information collected from their many spies and the rumors that we’ve deliberately leaked had led them to believe that we are refining a treasure. As a result, they are putting pressure on your Ye Clan to sell the treasure to them. In fact, this is a good result; With the bait out in the open, they won’t take notice of our true scheme. But just in case, all elders that know of the plan are to stay together whenever they go out. If they are not careful, those two eccentrics could ambush them and forcefully read through their souls. Daoist Sevenwonders in particular is skilled in all sorts of bewitchment techniques. Even Nascent Soul-stage cultivators will fall prey to him if they aren’t careful.”

The old man then sadly said, “So it was like that. But aren’t we letting go of the Mountain Crushing Seal too easily despite the efforts we put into refining it?”

The middle-aged sneered. “Not at all! If one sect were to visit us, we wouldn’t be able to resist the pressure and only give in. But with two of them here, there is an opportunity to exploit. Eldest Brother had already made a plan. Regardless of who the Mountain Crushing Seal goes to, it will cost them quite a bit.”

The old man and the beautiful woman exchanged a glance of confusion and could only tactfully drop the matter.

The three then talked for a moment more before departing on their own ways.

...

Time quickly passed and it was the day the grand auction convened.

During this time, the Yin Sifting Sect had searched all over the city for Han Li’s whereabouts, but they had actually only looked at the other markets, inns, and other places where cultivators had gathered. Since Han Li was wholly focused on refining the Snow Crystal Pearl, he hadn’t emerged even once.

During the morning, Han Li had changed his appearance to a large tan man, and the bamboo tube on his back transformed into a longsword. With his disguise prepared, he made his way to the West Jin Market with his cultivation restrained to mid-Core Formation stage to avoid attracting much attention.

As he had anticipated, the closer he approached the market, the more high-grade cultivators he could detect. While a majority of them were at Core Formation stage and low-grade cultivators, there were quite a number of Nascent Soul eccentrics.

It appeared that the more wealthy cultivators were unwilling to let the grand auction pass them by.

After Han Li passed through the restriction and headed into the market, he discovered that the street was filled with cultivators dressed in a variety of unfamiliar styles.

As he swept his gaze past them, he discovered several black-robed individuals at the entrance, including Ge Tianhao. They were currently looking at all those entering the market.

Han Li inwardly frowned and calmly walked through the entrance without meeting their gaze. But just as he was walking by, a faint thread of spiritual sense examined him and quickly moved on to look at another Core Formation cultivator.

The Yin Sifting Sect Elders didn’t look at every cultivator that entered the market with their spiritual sense, only those that they found unfamiliar or suspected to be vagrant cultivators.

While their stealthy prying wouldn’t be sensed by Core Formation cultivators, vagrants at Nascent Soul stage would be angered and they would bitterly glare at the Yin Sifting Sect elders.

Fortunately, the Yin Sifting Sect had no intention of stirring up trouble and didn’t continue after they were done with their cursory inspection. Although the vagrant cultivators felt resentful, they weren’t about to provoke a sect as large as the Yin Sifting Sect and simply continued on their way.

As if dissatisfied with the fruitless search, the old man with sharp eyes from the Yin Sifting Sect members said, “Elder Ge, I heard that this person is skilled in appearance transformation techniques. I fear there is no use in guarding the entrance.”

Ge Tianhao glanced at the old man and calmly said, “Senior Martial Brother Yin Li, I’ve only had you do this to stir him into action. This wasn’t meant to actually find this person. As his abilities are great, we have no method of seeing through his true identity. However, the aggressive manner of this search might fluster him and cause him to break his appearance. Even if he is completely unphased and can keep his disguise up, you don’t need to worry. As the Soaring Tribes and the Heavenly Devil Sect have a bit of friendship between them, Fellow Daoist Lin has already gone to the borrow the Clearsound Mirror from Fellow Daoist Sevenwonders. Unfortunately, he is occupied in his residence and won’t emerge for a few days. As such, our best plan of action would be to continue searching. And even if we can’t find him, he might let his guard down. Then, during the last two days of the auction, we will have the Clearsound Mirror break through his concealment and we’ll be able to quickly capture him.”

The sharp-eyed old man’s face lit up and he excitedly said, “ Given your unrivalled skill in planning, it is impossible that we’d do something of wasted effort. If it's like that, we won’t need to call over the Sect Master and the grand elders. We’ll gain great merit in the sect once we capture him.”

“I hope so.” Ge Tianhao dryly laughed and then glanced in the direction of the Treasureshine Hall.

From how he was being handled, it was clear that they viewed him as a fearsome character. It was only natural considering that he killed their sect’s fourth elder who was at the peak of mid-Nascent Soul stage. It wouldn’t be strange for things to go against their expectations so it was best for them to be careful.

With that in mind, Ge Tianhao unconsciously wore a sullen expression.

...

At that moment, Han Li was standing in front of a huge stone building. There was a layer of rainbow light covering it, giving the building a mysterious aura.

But what surprised him was that there was now another white stone hall floating above the Treasureshine Hall. It was one third the size of the building below but it was still colossal and spanned at least a kilometer in area.

In front of Han Li stood a yellow-robed attendant with Foundation Establishment cultivation. He was giving Han Li an explanation with a respectful tone. At that point, Han Li had ceased concealing his Nascent Soul cultivation. While the auction attendant viewed him with indifference, he didn’t dare to be rude.

In front of the building, there were several other similarly dressed attendants present. They were all accompanying Nascent Soul stage cultivators. As for the Core Formation stage cultivators, they were simply standing in front of a stone tablet that was set up in front of the building gate. They were reading what was carved on it.

After a while, Han Li withdrew his gaze from his surroundings and turned his attention back on the attendant, saying, “The participation fee for the Nascent Soul-stage auction will be a thousand spirit stones, and will take place in the Nine Firmaments Hall. And the Core Formation-grade auction will take place in Treasureshine Hall with a participation fee of a hundred spirit stones. Is that right?”

The attendant smiled and said, “It is exactly as Senior says. There are quite a few more cultivators participating in this auction than expected. As such, we had no choice but to borrow the Nine Firmaments Hall from the Hidden Fortune Pavilion in an emergency. Our spirit stone fees are the same as always, though. They are primarily used to avoid having the auctions from being too crowded, or else anyone could enter, allowing over ten times as many people. However, a senior like yourself shouldn’t view such a small sum of spirit stones with much regard.”

“A thousand spirit stones? Your hall is quite skilled in acquiring riches. But as you said, so long as I am able to grab the items I desire, this amount of spirit stones is of little cost. I have no interest in the Core Formation-grade auction and will only be participating in the Nascent Soul-grade auction.” Han Li waved his hand and tossed ten mid-grade spirit stones towards the yellow-robed attendant.

“Please come in, Senior. The Nascent Soul-grade auction will begin in the late morning. This is an auction badge. You can this to enter the later days of the auction.” The attendant took the spirit stones with a smile and handed over a jade badge over to Han Li.

He accepted the badge and his body wordlessly flickered with azure light. He then flew towards the large hall in the sky in a streak of light, along with other cultivators.

When Han Li arrived at the gate of the Nine Firmaments Hall, he saw that there was no one there apart from a barrier of white light.

His brow stirred and he poured a bit of spiritual power into the jade badge. Suddenly, a beam of red light flew out from the badge and split the barrier.

Without another thought, he flew inside in a blur before the gate sealed itself again.

Four hours later, several hundreds of Nascent Soul-stage cultivators had gathered together in the Nine Firmaments Hall.

With three huge bell strikes, the grand auction convened.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Lan, akiwimain

Chapter 953: The Nine Serenities Sect

Not long after the Yin Sifting Sect members departed, two cultivators appeared from a nearby building in a blur.

When the two saw that there was no one left at the entrance, they solemnly spoke to each other through voice transmissions before tailing the Yin Sifting Sect members out of the market.

When they arrived at the market entrance, the two immediately set off in their separate directions. One of them waved a small flag and their body disappeared into a cloud of purple smoke, chasing after Ge Tianhao’s group. The other cultivator streaked through the sky in the direction of the imperial city.

...

Near a nameless mountain close to the Jin Capital, Old Man Fu glanced at Han Li with a curious look and said, “Don’t you have anything you want to ask?”

After the teleportation, Han Li carefully glanced around the transportation formation and had found nothing amiss, much to his relief. He calmly replied, “What’s the point? I am somewhat puzzled as to why Brother Fu used a transportation formation to leave the market, but I’m sure you have your reasons.”

Han Li’s careful actions hadn’t gone unnoticed by Old Man Fu, but he wasn’t angered in the slightest. Rather, he was quite satisfied by his show of caution.

Old Man Fu narrowed his eyes and then wore a mysterious smile. “In truth, my reason wasn’t much. I simply acquired information that there were Yin Sifting Sect cultivators waiting at the entrance of the market. I may have reckoned that Fellow Daoist Han wouldn’t wish to see them, so I decided to use teleportation to avoid them. I hope you didn’t feel I was being too meddlesome.”

“...Fellow Daoist Fu, what do you mean by that?” Han Li’s heart trembled but he managed to keep a calm attitude.

Old Man Fu chuckled, still wearing his mysterious smile, and slowly said, “There is no need to worry. If I truly wished to mean you harm, I would’ve set up an ambush here. When Brother Han stood in front of the Treasureshine Hall, didn’t you clash with Ge Tianhao and his sect members?”

After a moment of silence, Han Li replied, “I didn’t expect that Brother Fu would know this. But why did you help me? I’m not convinced that you would risk offending the Yin Sifting Sect over our appointment.”

Old Man Fu calmly stated, “Risk offending the Yin Sifting Sect? It appears Brother Han is unaware of my background. I am the Enforcement Elder for the Nine Serenities Sect. We’re already at odds with the Yin Sifting Sect to begin with. I will happily obstruct them if the opportunity arises. Though, the main reason I helped you is because I have a request.”

When Han Li heard that he was an elder of one of the ten great Devil Dao sects, he was alarmed and grew vigilant. “The Nine Serenities Sect? It seems I’ve been disrespectful. I’ve long heard of the grand reputation of your esteemed order. But, why would a sect as powerful as yours need my help?”

“This is a private matter so I cannot ask them for help,” Old Man Fu said with a smile, “However, there is no hurry. After the trade fair is done, we can discuss the matter further. There are benefits to be had, but if you dislike the conditions, I won’t force you to agree.”

After some consideration, Han Li smiled and said, “In that case, I’ll agree to the favor.”

Since he had already offended one of the great ten Devil Dao sects, it would be best not to offend another one. As such, he decided to give an empty promise and leave the matter for later.

“I see Brother Han is also a straightforward person! Let’s go, the trade fair isn’t far away.” A happy expression appeared on Old Man Fu’s face and then he took off into the distance.

With haste, they arrived at a barren mountain range over a thousand kilometers away from the Jin capital. They circled around one of the countless mountains and dropped down in front of a stone cliff dirtied with earth and moss. It didn’t appear the slightest out of the ordinary.

Han Li’s attention wasn’t focused on the cliffside, but rather his surroundings. He discovered that they were in a deep overgrown valley. If he wasn’t led here, he wouldn’t have noticed there were cultivators present in the area.

It was clear Old Man Fu had been there before. He casually waved his sleeve and a small palm-sized plate flew out. It flickered with white light and sank into the stone without a trace.

Soon, the cliff-face began to glow with dazzling yellow light and suddenly disappeared to reveal a huge cave that was over thirty meters wide. There were two green-robed, middle-aged cultivators standing at the cave’s entrance. They both possessed late-Core Formation cultivation, and one of them was holding onto Old Man Fu’s plate.

The one holding the disk saluted the two and then spoke with a neutral tone, “So it was originally Senior Fu. This other Senior appears unfamiliar. May I ask for your esteemed name?”

Old Man Fu glared at him and bluntly said, “This is Fellow Daoist Han, a cultivator from overseas. Since I’ve already given him a recommendation, what is there to check? Quickly give him an identification so we may join in the trade fair.”

“ Hehe . Since Senior Fu was the one who recommended him, there will be no problems of course. This is a Nascent Soul-stage identity plate. If Senior violates any of the trade fair rules, we will take it back. This plate will allow you to take part in four trade meets, though you will only have to pay for the first one. The rules require you pay ten thousand spirit stones for the plate.” The green-robed cultivator courteously gave Old Man Fu back the jade plate and then took out one for Han Li.

“Here are the spirit stones.” Although Han Li felt a bit of heartache, he readily handed over a storage pouch containing ten thousand spirit stones.

After counting the spirit stones in the bag, the green-robed cultivator smiled and handed over a plate that had the number three hundred forty-seven written on it. “Here is the jade plate. Please take care of it.”

Han Li glanced at it and raised his brow. “Three hundred forty-seven? Are there that many people participating?”

“Of course not,” the other green-robed cultivator explained, “A portion of these seniors will not be attending the trade fair for various reasons. In my experience, there will only be about two hundred people.”

“Oh, that is still quite a few.” Han Li nodded with understanding.

“Alright, it is about time that we join the trade fair. If I have the opportunity, I’ll give my regards to your master.” Old Man Fu then led Han Li deep into the cave.

As Han Li followed behind him, he said, “Their cultivation wasn’t weak. From your tone, it sounded as if they had the same master.”

Old Man Fu chuckled and asked, “Do you know of the four great vagrant cultivators of the Great Jin?”

“Yes, of course. Is their master one of them?” Han Li asked with a curious tone.

“That’s right. Their master is Fellow Daoist Yi Xitian who possesses the most mysterious abilities of the four. He has already been in late-Nascent Soul stage for many years now, though his cultivation is nearly immeasurable. In the past, I had the opportunity to personally witness him use his grand abilities to slay a grade eight demon beast with ease. It is said that he is one of the two in the Great Jin who possesses the greatest chance of ascending to Deity Transformation stage. Since the organizers of the trade fair had selected the two of his disciples to act as gatekeepers, I reckon they intend on drawing support from their master’s fame.” After Old Man Fu gave Han Li the explanation, he let out a deep sigh of admiration.

“May I ask who is the other Fellow Daoist to have the possibility of entering Deity Transformation stage?”

With a wry smile, Old Man Fu answered, “The other person is the Buddhist Cleansing Fire Sect’s Monk Jademoon. In a sparse four hundred years, he had already entered late-Nascent Soul stage. He is a prodigy that only appears in the cultivation world once every ten thousand years. While I do consider myself one of the outstanding talents, we aren't close to exceptional when compared to those two.”

“But Brother Fu’s cultivation is quite profound and I hold you in quite some admiration. Late-Nascent Soul stage appears to be a single breakthrough away for you.”

“Nonsense, I’ve remained trapped in my stage of cultivation for three hundred years, and have long given up hope of reaching late-Nascent Soul stage. Yet, it appears you’ve achieved mid-Nascent Soul stage not long ago. Perhaps you’ll reach a breakthrough in the near future.”

“Brother Fu is quite funny. How could such a thing happen?” Han Li dryly laughed. Of course, he wasn’t about to take his words seriously.

With Old Man Fu taking the lead, Han Li eventually saw a white light shine in front of him and a large hall bustling with activity from the opening. He couldn’t help but grow excited.

...

In an area over fifty kilometers away, Ge Tianhao wore a fierce expression and black Qi was roiling from his body. He was holding onto the head of an unfamiliar cultivator in a rigid grasp, forcefully extracting the memories of the victim’s soul using secret soul searching techniques.

The victim’s appearance became warped, his eyes flickered, and his body trembled in a display of gruesome agony. The Endless Sky Saintess and a middle-aged black-robed cultivator were watching at the side.

A short moment later, the victim of the soul search suddenly trembled and fell to the ground with a stream of black blood flowing out his nose.

Ge Tianhao frowned and he set the corpse alight in a black inferno, instantly turning it to ash. He then closed his eyes and began to look through the memories he extracted.

When Ge Tianhao eventually opened his eyes, the Saintess asked, “What was his identity? Why was he stealthily following us?”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: akiwimain

Chapter 963: Secret Talisman

Han Li stayed in the Heavenly Talisman Sect’s record hall for three days and read through the jade slips related to talisman refinement. There were quite a few secret techniques, and he nonchalantly duplicated some of their contents so he could further research them at a later time.

Shockingly, a few records had even elaborated a bit on the other two secret talismans of the Heavenly Talisman Sect.

The Spiritform Talisman was peculiar in that it entered one’s body. It would then be tempered inside the Dantian and could be used endlessly. If one nurtured it to a stage, not only will it become limitlessly sharp, but one would be able to use Devil Dao Techniques like ‘Cataclysmic Graft’ without the sacrifice of a limb. [1]

The other talisman was the Sixpeak Armor Talisman. It condenses the nearby spiritual Qi into a six-layered shield. If given an endless source, the six-layered shield would endlessly reform itself. It was one of the few incredible techniques that could control worldly spiritual Qi that didn’t involve Deity Transformation cultivation.

Of the sect’s three secret talismans, the Spiritform Talisman was the easiest to grasp. After a cultivator entered Core Formation stage, they would be able to nurture it in their Dantian. He reckoned that successive cultivators of the sect used this ability. However, the might of the talisman not only depended on the cultivation of the user and the time it was nurtured, but also the quality of the materials used to refine it, very much like a magic treasure.

The Sixpeak Armor Talisman was different. So long as it was refined, anyone could use it. The might of this talisman depended on the concentration of worldly spiritual Qi in its surroundings. Under ideal circumstances, it would display astonishing might.

According to the records of a past Sect Elder, the Sixpeak Armor Talisman refinement method was lost when Master Heaven Talisman passed away. Back when the Heavenly Talisman Sect was at its peak, they were alarmed by this disappearance and made its recovery the sect’s top priority for many generations after. Unfortunately, they weren’t able to find the slightest clue of its whereabouts and the search came to an end.

As for the Soul Subjugation Talisman, it hadn’t been refined ever since the founding of the sect. As a result, only the Spiritform Talisman truly had any practical use.

Han Li was greatly interested in the other two talismans. The Spiritform Talisman in particular was an optimal life-saving measure as it would allow him to use sacrificial techniques.

Three days later, Han Li read through the last talisman of interest to him and had finally stood up. He swept his spiritual sense down below and found that Old Man Xiang was still there.

He frowned and mulled with worry. In these past few days, the old man had remained in peaceful cultivation and hadn’t taken a step outside of the building.

As for the circumstances outside, Han Li had found it to be quite laughable. Fearing that he would depart without warning,, the sect’s Foundation Establishment cultivators had taken turns waiting outside.

After some further thought, he descended to the ground floor.

“Senior, are you finished reading?” When the old man saw Han Li appear, he immediately put away the jade slip in his hand and grinned.

Han Li smiled and said, “Yes, I’ve seen everything I wanted to. You may do as you please!” Afterwards, he made his way out.

A bright glint flashed from the old man's eyes as he watched Han Li depart, but his expression soon returned to normal.

When he left the building, he caught sight of the middle-aged man who brought him here. When the man saw Han Li, he hastily greeted him and respectfully requested that he make a trip to the main hall.

After perusing through their collection of records, Han Li agreed as it would be inappropriate for him to refuse. The middle-aged man happily sent a voice transmission talisman to the main hall.

Waiting there was the upper echelon of the Heavenly Talisman Sect and two unfamiliar middle-aged Core Formation cultivators, a man and a woman.

When the Heavenly Talisman Sect members saw Han Li, they saluted him. The Sect Elder Wen then gave an introduction, “These two are Fellow Daoist Chang of Gold Mist Mountain and Fellow Daoist Xie of Bright Yang Valley. When these two Fellow Daoist heard that Senior had graced us with his presence, they had come here to pay their respects and have been waiting ever since.”

“ Ah! You two are quite considerate to have waited while I had spent the past few days researching talisman refinement techniques.” Han Li wore an indifferent expression that betrayed no emotion.

“Hardly, it is our honor to be able to see you.” After the two made certain of Han Li’s cultivation, they both saluted him. In truth, when the Heavenly Talisman Sect requested them to arrive, the two had doubted if they truly had a visitor who possessed Nascent Soul cultivation.

After all, the two were well aware of the Heavenly Talisman Sect’s current circumstances. Although they were all classified as small sects, the Heavenly Talisman Sect was the weakest of the three in their alliance, so it was rather surprising for a Nascent Soul cultivator to visit them. The benefits were obvious if it were true.

The two hadn’t remained idle when they heard this and rushed over to the sect overnight to verify this matter. Their doubts were now dispelled after personally witnessing Han Li’s profound cultivation.

It was only after Han Li took a seat that the others dared to follow suit. Apart from the Heavenly Talisman Sect Master, the other Foundation Establishment cultivators simply stood at the side.

The woman surnamed Xie said with a pleasant voice, “Has Senior gained anything from his stay in the records hall? If Senior is interested, we do have a few records on the matter as well, although our valley isn’t particularly adept in talisman refinement techniques.”

Han Li smiled at the woman and said, “There is no need to trouble you. I have some urgent business at hand and will need to soon depart to the Linjiang Province.”

The man surnamed Chang yelped out in surprise. “Does Senior mean to deal with those fierce flood dragons?”

“Oh, you know about it?” Han Li asked with a changed expression.

With a hesitant tone, Cultivator Chang said, “The cultivators journeying to the Linjiang Province are all going for the fierce flood dragons. I’m afraid Senior’s information isn’t very new.”

Han Li’s expression sank and he slowly said, “I acquired this news half a year ago at a market. Since the flood dragons are around grade seven, they shouldn’t have been so quickly hunted by other cultivators.”

“Not at all,” Old Man Wen hastily explained, “In fact, not long ago they managed to kill a flood dragon in an ambush. But the flood dragons fiercely retaliated and killed many cultivators in return. There was even a Nascent Soul cultivator that was gravely injured.”

“How was the Nascent Soul cultivator injured?” Han Li asked with surprise.

Old Man Wen answered, “A transformed grade-eight blue flood dragon had appeared amongst them. The cultivators who lied in ambush had suffered heavy losses since they hadn’t expected it. While the South Seas Sect had dispatched many elders, they were only able to repel the group of flood dragons. The flood dragons had made their way to the many islands by the shore and hid there, frequently attacking lone cultivators and mortal ships in the vicinity. If Nascent Soul cultivators grouped and attacked them together, the flood dragons would immediately flee deep into the ocean using ice evasion techniques. Their attacks have become increasingly vicious recently and far more troublesome. I heard that the South Seas Sect have already invited many high-grade cultivators to gather at Jade Blossom Island in preparation of a hunt as grade-eight flood dragons are rarely ever seen.”

“A grade-eight flood dragon...” Han Li muttered to himself with a calm expression. He was reminded of the grade-eight Venomous Flood Dragon he had killed in the past.

Although the demon beast was only grade eight, they had a true strength that was beyond that of a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator. On top of this, it was particularly difficult to deal with when it was at sea.

However, Han Li had no interest in the blue flood dragon. He then asked, “I recall that there was a red fire-attribute flood dragon among them, a Scarlet Flame Flood Dragon in partiuclar. Is this true?”

Cultivator Chang seemed to know much about the matter and quickly answered, “There does seem to be a red flood dragon among them, but I’m not too sure if it is a Scarlet Flame Flood Dragon.”

“That will do.” Han Li nodded with satisfaction.

When the others in the hall saw that Han Li’s face had relaxed, they all sighed with relief.

At that moment, Old Man Wen and the other two exchanged a glance. Then he probingly asked, “Senior Han’s cultivation is quite vast. Surely you must be an elder of a great sect?”

Han Li glanced at the three and wore a mysterious smile. “ Hehe , I came from a rather remote region. I am not the elder of any sect in the Great Jin.”

Han Li’s sharp gaze had startled the group, but upon hearing his words, they couldn’t help but rejoice.

After a moment of hesitation, Old Man Wen then cautiously asked, “Since Senior has already researched the Spirit Subjugation Talisman, what does he think of it? Is it worthy of your notice?”

Han Li sighed and bluntly said, “If you have anything to say, state it. There is no point in beating around the bush. Could it be you wish to have me enter your sect?”

After hearing Han Li’s unhappy tone, Old Man Wen as alarmed and quickly explained, “Please don’t misunderstand, Senior. I wouldn’t dare to have such an extravagant request. I only wished to ask if Senior is willing to become a joint guest elder of our three sects.”

“A guest elder?” Han Li soon narrowed his eyes.

Small and mid-grade sects in the Great Jin would often have a sect position for high-grade vagrant cultivators. Although the position sounded the same as an ordinary elder, in truth there were quite a few differences.

To small sects, guest elders were only that in name. Guest elders couldn’t be restricted by the sect and wouldn’t be bound to their orders either. Typically, they would only find the need to take action when their sects were subjected to mishaps.

However, even this assistance wasn’t mandatory and depended on the mood of the elder. Guest elders were even paid appropriately of their position and sometimes were paid even more than ordinary elders.

The reason why the position of guest elder was widespread in the Great Jin was due to the vast number of small sects and lacking number of Nascent Soul cultivators in comparison. Let alone small sets, even mid-grade sects would find themselves lacking a Nascent Soul cultivator at times. Under such circumstances, it would only be natural for them to strive their hardest for the support of a vagrant Nascent Soul cultivator.

But usually vagrant high-grade cultivators found it disdainful to enter the restrictions of a sect, but were tempted by the compensation. As a result, the position of guest elder came to be.

[1]. In Chapter 573: Yin Devil Execution vs the Six Apex Devils during Han Li's battle with the Disciple of Archsaint Sixpaths in the Scattered Star Seas, the disciple used a technique called Cataclysmic Graft. It allowed him to sacrifice a limb and some vitality in order to completely avoid the damage of an otherwise lethal attack.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ed: akiwimain

Chapter 965: Fighting Flood Dragons

Currently, Han Li’s party was thousands of kilometers to the west of Jade Blossom Island.

A few days ago, a party of cultivators were ambushed by a grade-eight blue flood dragon. Although the flood dragon was rather cunning and wouldn’t likely to stay in the vicinity, the South Sea Sect had sent them on a search regardless to see if they could acquire any unexpected gains.

When in the presence of so many people, Han Li couldn’t fully use his spiritual sense or he would risk attracting the attention of the Nascent Soul cultivator leading their squad. He could only release enough spiritual sense for him to detect traces of the flood dragons ahead of time, which was five kilometers around him and the surface of the ocean.

As the day went on, they finished most of their search, but surprisingly, they weren’t able to find anything.

Suddenly, a cultivator at the front yelled out in surprise, “What’s that!?”

Han Li turned his attention from the sea to the sky after hearing this, catching sight of surging clouds that spanned for over a kilometer flying towards them.

An uproar was raised amongst the group and one of them shouted with delight, “This is good! There should be a high-grade demon beast within. Do not allow it to escape.”

One of the more vigilant cultivators hesitantly said, “Something is amiss. Those flood dragons usually flee as soon as they see us. So then why would they take the initiative to approach us? Do they have some sort of plan?”

The Nascent Soul cultivator leading the squad was a large middle-aged man who wore golden robes. He frowned when he heard the two and unconsciously turned in their direction. However, his face suddenly froze and he loudly shouted, “Be careful! There are demon beasts approaching us from another direction!”

When the group heard this, they were frightened into action. They all spat out their magic treasures and prepared themselves for battle, but as far as the eye could see, they couldn’t find any trace of a demon beast.

The cultivators glanced at one another. Just as they were about to speak, an ear-piercing roar shook the air. Then, various-colored clouds had appeared in the distance. They continuously lurched and revealed the faint silhouettes of flood dragons from within.

But what was most noteworthy were the two particularly large demon clouds in the east and the west, glowing in red and blue light respectively, making for a gorgeous display.

At this close distance, the cultivators could feel the fearsome power of the flood dragons that the clouds contained. Most turned pale with terror, and one of them even lost himself to fear and cried out, “How can this be? Two grade-eight demon beasts...”

Another grade-eight flood dragon had made a sudden appearance. They were no longer satisfied with ambushing them, but now wanted to completely eliminate them. The hunters have turned into the hunted.

The squad leader was still able to keep his calm under the circumstances and he fiercely barked, “Don’t panic! Quickly send word to the other squads! Divide into groups to face the enemy. Do not let them gather together, their strength will become even greater. And don’t even try to escape; with their water movement techniques, they’ll be able to pick us off one by one.”

The orders steadied the group and several immediately released a flurry of voice transmission talismans into the sky.

The leader then sullenly added, “I will go and deal with one of the grade-eight flood dragons. Two cultivators skilled in evasion techniques should tie down the other to keep it occupied for a while. You don’t need to fight it. As for everyone else, go and stall the grade-seven flood dragons.”

But this time, the cultivators looked at each other in dismay.

Although these cultivators couldn’t prove to be their match, they were confident in surviving the grade-seven flood dragons for a time. But wasn’t it asking for too much for only two of them to fight against the grade-eight flood dragon? Even if it were only to stall for time, ordinary cultivators couldn’t last for long.

“If two won’t do, then let’s have three!” Their leader anxiously spoke.

Not long after, thunder sounded out and an astonishing scene had occurred. An unremarkable cultivator from their group suddenly took to the skies with overbearing momentum, turning into a streak of blinding azure light as it flew towards the crimson cloud.

“A Nascent Soul cultivator, at mid-Nascent Soul stage!” Those present shouted out in both surprise and delight.

Their leader also rejoiced. ‘Could it be the South Sea Sect felt that something was amiss and hid a Nascent Soul cultivator in my group?’

With that thought, he turned his sights on the incoming sapphire cloud and charged towards it without another thought.

Seeing that the two biggest threats were being blocked by Nascent Soul cultivators, the squad’s morale rose and they flew off in different directions to obstruct the other approaching demon clouds.

Soon, lights began to shine in every direction, followed by the sounds of distant explosions.

But unlike the others, the cloud in front of Han Li remained motionless as a sea of scarlet inferno burned around him. He was protected by a layer of faint purple flames, and it would only let out the crackle of an occasional singe, a sound that was nothing in comparison to the thunderous booms echoing from the other battles.

A hundred meters in front of him, there was a transformed half-human demon beast. He was surrounded by a pillar of flames and was coldly glaring at Han Li. Although the demon appeared to be mostly human, his body was covered in sparkling fist-sized scarlet scales and variously-sized threads of flame were streaming out from his body.

Han Li widely smiled and said, “So it was actually a Scarlet Flame Flood Dragon, I was right in coming. Your scales will prove much more effective than a grade-seven one.”

“You’re going to fight me?” The transformed scarlet flood dragon blankly stared at Han Li before widely grinning, revealing snow-white fangs. Then with a green glint from his eyes, the flame pillar surrounding him surged with an astonishing pressure.

Despite the flood dragon’s fierce display, he truly felt anxious.

The cultivator who charged towards him was not only at mid-Nascent Soul stage, but his purple ice-attribute flames were profoundly lethal. Those strange flames restrained his own diligently cultivated demon flames, which would greatly restrict his own abilities in the coming battle.

Furthermore, Han Li’s calm attitude had caused his heart to tremble for some unknown reason. The flood dragon faintly felt that disaster would soon befall him, and became even more uneasy.

Han Li chuckled and indifferently said, “The reason why I came here was because I heard that there were grade-seven flood dragons. Now that you’re here, I no longer have any interest in those minor prizes. However, I also don’t have much of an interest in killing you since you were able to cultivate to this stage and am willing to let you go. How about you take the initiative to hand over the vital scales on your neck and have the other flood dragons depart?”

“My vital scales? Your tone is truly bold. Does a trifling mid-Nascent Soul cultivator dare to be so arrogant? Let's see if your attitude will persist after you turn to ash.” Han Li’s words had thrown the flood dragon into a rage.

Vital scales were something that a flood dragon kept since they were born and were irreplaceable. As they aged, much of their magic power and vitality would be cultivated into their scales, similar to a demon core. If lost, they would lose nearly half of their cultivation.

Enraged, the half-human flood dragon began to distort and a soft bang sounded out. The flame pillar surrounding it scattered, revealing a twenty-meter-long and meter-thick scarlet flood dragon. The original fear in his mind was replaced completely by a thirst to rend Han Li to shreds.

As soon as the beast revealed its demon form, it opened its mouth and spat a stream of crimson lava towards Han Li.

When he saw this, he raised his brow and muttered, “Concentrated Flameslag! This demon flame has been well cultivated. It seems I’ll have to personally take action.”

With that said, Han Li didn’t dare to tarry. Slapping the back of his head, he spat out the Snow Crystal Pearl.

As soon as a pearl appeared, it immediately expanded to the size of a fist and directly flew forward to meet the attack. At the same time, Han Li softy spoke and pointed at the pearl before muttering a short incantation. The pearl ignited in a purple blaze, quickly forming a three-meter-long flood dragon of raging flame with the pearl held in its mouth.

As soon as the purple dragon took shape, it charged forward to meet the lava stream.

With a loud snap , a white mist suddenly filled the air and enveloped the two of them. The purple flame dragon was using the pearl in its mouth to spit out a stream of purple flames, slowly pushing back the lava.

When the scarlet flood dragon saw this, a hint of fear was betrayed from his face. But soon, an ominous gleam shined from his eyes and scarlet light glowed from his body as he let out a fierce screech.

The sea of flames surrounding Han Li was roused by the noise and began to form two thirty-meter-tall waves of flame to crush him from opposing directions.

Han Li coldly smiled when he saw this. He slapped his hands together and then separated them to point at the waves of lava.

Purple light flickered in front of him and a clear ring sounded out. A sparkling hundred-meter-tall mountain of brilliant ice suddenly condensed around him, firmly blocking the incoming tides of lava.

Upon this, the flood dragon blurred and reduced his body to a mere three meters in length.

As soon as that happened, the beast ceased spewing lava and shot towards Han Li in a scarlet streak. He traveled sixty meters in the blink of an eye and began to swipe its claws down.

Now that the flood dragon saw that its inferno was ineffective against Han Li, he planned on striking him down with his claws.

Translator's Thoughts

The flood dragon is going all out!

ED: akiwimain

PR: Lan

Chapter 973: Twin Scorpion Mountain

Half a day later, Han Li put away the Hidden Fortune Mansion and flew off to the mainland in a streak of light. He rapidly reached land after a few undisturbed weeks.

He didn’t revisit the Heavenly Talisman Sect and instead rushed to Nanjiang, the southern border. He intermittently stopped throughout the journey to refine the portion of the Triflame Fan that required human flames. Han Li was gloomy that he wasn’t able to encounter a thunderstorm along the way.

He wasn’t worried, rather the opposite, the dense jungles of the southern border had a rainy climate with lightning often mixed in. It would only be a matter of time before he could refine the heaven flame.

Four months had passed before Han Li arrived at the Nanjiang Region [1] , having to go through multiple provinces along the way.

The region was one of the few places that weren’t under the rule of a large sect. Rather, the region’s resources were split up between a dozen or so mid-grade sects. Although there would commonly be strife in between these sects, if an external power were to invade, they would immediately unite. Even the great ten righteous and devilish sects haven’t been able to subject the territory under their rule, assuming an almost independent position in the Jin Empire.

Under such conditions, these sects were distrusting of outsiders and cultivated closely related techniques that were born of themselves.

They mostly cultivated rare Yin Poison techniques that were rarely seen. Not only were they skilled in using poison and insects, their skills in curses had reached perfection. If one fought with a Nanjiang cultivator, a single moment of carelessness would result in a vicious, unblockable blow.

The Chaoyun Prefecture was placed west in Nanjiang, with Twin Scorpion Mountain located in one of its desolate mountain ranges. It was covered in miasma hundreds of kilometers wide yearlong. Unless one had high enough cultivation or took medicine for the miasma, they would be unable to enter.

The mountain range was actually somewhat famous in Nanjiang. As a result of its miasma, the mountain grew many valuable poisonous plants and is the home to two types of venomous scorpions that were ideal for low-grade cultivators using insect techniques.

When Han Li arrived near this mountain, it was during the yearly eruption of miasma. Many cultivators were gathered nearby as the two breeds of venomous scorpions would emerge from their burrows during this time.

However, a majority of these cultivators were at Qi Condensation stage with a few Foundation Establishment cultivators mixed in. Since the mountain range was of little interest to high-grade cultivators, not even a single Core Formation cultivator was present.

If a mid-Nascent Soul eccentric like Han Li was discovered in the area, it would be cause for a great commotion. As such, he hadn’t stayed in the mountain’s surroundings and instead flew into the dense, pink miasma. The azure light protecting his body easily blocked it and the venomous insects that lurked inside.

After making sure of his bearings, he directly made his way to the heart of the mountain.

Although Elder Wei had originally mentioned the name of the Twin Scorpion Mountain, he hadn’t given a specific point. As such, Han Li decided to visit the main peak first.

While he flew and pondered about the purpose behind Elder Wei’s request, he suddenly heard a miserable scream from far away.

“It’s a Scorpion King, an Iron Tail Scorpion variant! Everyone, run!” A hoarse man’s voice shouted out in terror, followed by the nearby sounds of explosions and a strange insect’s cry.

Han Li glanced in their direction with blue light flickering from his eyes.

With sounds of tearing wind, a group of men and women began to appear within the miasma as they rushed in his direction. They were running with pointed feet and were sweeping across the ground in a clear display of body lightening techniques.

One of the women in the group caused Han Li to suddenly yelp in surprise when he saw her.

Soon after, he swept his sleeve and an azure mist spread out, clearing the miasma in the area, clearing an area of a hundred meters. The group came to a sudden stop when they entered the clearing.

Before they could react, Han Li pointed to the area behind them and made a fist. A hand of azure light appeared and captured something black in its grasp. Then, it flew in a circle and returned to Han Li.

The hand held a foot-long scorpion with a shiny jet-black shell, its half-foot-long tail was barbed and glowed with a purple light. This was the Iron Tail Scorpion variant that was pursuing these low-grade cultivators.

The scorpion was only a grade-two spirit beast, and was firmly confined by the hand of light, only capable of snarling in its capture. These cultivators were all dumbstruck when they saw Han Li in the air and were at a complete loss.

The light around him scattered and he asked one of the women, “I didn’t think I’d see Fellow Daoist Wang here after I left the Jin Capital. Is Young Miss Cao doing well?” [2]

“It’s Fellow Da- No, Senior Han! Junior Martial Sister Cao is still in the Jin Capital. I’ve only come here with a few comrades in search of spirit medicines.” Lady Wang hurriedly took the initiative to respectfully salute him. Ever since Han Li took off after he was attracted by the sword cry, she had come to realize Han Li’s identity as a high-grade cultivator and didn’t dare to act casually with him.

When the others saw that Lady Wang recognized this great cultivator, they felt relieved and all stepped forward and saluted Han Li in thanks. However, they all believed Han Li to be at Core Formation stage as Nascent Soul cultivators were far beyond the possibility of contact.

Han Li nodded in acknowledgment and then turned to look at the confined scorpion with a frown. “As the niece of the South Pillar General, you shouldn’t need to brave the risk of looking for spiritual herbs.”

Lady Wang’s expression blanked and then she wryly smiled, “Although my clan is rich and has provided me with a few spirit stones, my aptitude is only average. How could they possibly afford so many spirit stones on me?”

“ Hmm . In truth, your aptitude is quite good; Foundation Establishment stage isn’t out of reach for you. Since we had the fate to meet again, I’ll hand this over to you. I have business to attend to soon, take care of yourselves.” After that was said, Han Li casually pointed to the hand of light.

With a soft bang, the hand scattered into specks of light and the large scorpion trembled before falling to the ground, completely immobile.

“Senior, I...” Just as Lady Wang was about to utter words of thanks, Han Li disappeared in a flash and her words came to a sudden stop.

The other cultivators looked at the large scorpion variant with envy.

However, since the scorpion was something a high-grade cultivator had given her, none of them dared to rob her. They could only watch as the woman stuck several talismans on it and happily placed it in her spirit beast pouch.

Moments later, an explosion sounded out and the miasma covering the sky began to coil. Then, a furious wind scattered some of the miasma to reveal a black storm cloud floating in the air.

At that moment, Han Li glanced at the black mountain in the distance and muttered, “The time has finally come.” He then flew towards in the mountain in a streak.

Rolls of thunder sounded out and heavy rain pelted the surrounding miasma, causing it to shrink down to several meters off the ground. On the mountain in the distance, a storm began to reveal itself.

Han Li descended onto a large boulder on the mountaintop, remaining dry with the aid of a barrier of light surrounding him. However, there were eight cultivators already gathered: two at Foundation Establishment and the rest at Qi Condensation.

The group all had their hair wrapped in a bun and wore native outfits. When they saw Han Li appear, they all looked at each other in dismay.

Han Li swept his gaze at the cultivators and released a flood of astonishing spiritual Qi. After waving his arm at the cultivators, he coldly shouted, “Get lost!” as wind wildly blew around him, a mist of azure mist surged.

In their alarm, a few of the cultivators released protective barriers and hastily flew off on their magic tools. However, all of them were engulfed by azure mist and flung a hundred meters away. This made for a sorry sight as they wore faces of terror.

At that moment, they wordlessly rushed off the mountain now that they knew Han Li was a high-grade cultivator.

As Han Li watched them disappear from the mountaintop, he expressionlessly turned his gaze to the sky.

Lightning roared and danced in the black clouds above him.

[1]. The Nanjiang Region is a name that literally translates to the southern border. Not only is this territory on the southern border, but its name literally translates to this as well.

[Back]

[2]. The green-robed woman Han Li spoke to was Cao Mengrong’s Senior Martial Sister Wang who he had earlier met on his way to the Jin Capital.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: akiwimain

Chapter 974: Visitors

After his outburst, Han Li felt the last trace of distress from Monarch Soul Divergence’s passing dissolve. In any case, since he planned on gathering the storm’s lightning, he didn’t want any interruptions. With a long sigh, he slapped his storage pouch and took out various colored spell flags, sending them off in every direction with the wave of his hand, burrowing into the ground without a trace.

He looked at the unceasing lightning in the sky and the corner of his mouth twitched. His body glowed with light as he floated a hundred meters in the air. Forming a strange hand gesture, he began to mutter an incantation.

Suddenly, various-colored light flashed from down below. Muffled pops sounded out followed by several pillars of luminescence emerging to the sky and forming huge spell flags. They stood off the ground and remained completely motionless.

Continuing his incantations, the spell flags beneath him began to release threads of spiritual Qi and slowly took the form of a thirty-meter-wide spirit gathering spell formation.Within the brilliant glow, talisman characters began to rise from the center, fully activating it.

In that instant, the lightning flashing in the distant skies were suddenly attracted towards the formation and gradually grew closer as the sounds of thunder quickened.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and ceased casting incantations. He flipped his hand and summoned a slender jade bottle, a magic tool he had specifically refined to capture the lightning.

He released it into the air and struck it with an azure spell seal, causing it to quickly spin several times before it held still in the air.

At that moment, Han Li clapped his hands and raised them, releasing two dense bolts of golden lightning, both simultaneously striking the bottom of the jade bottle. In a clap of thunder, the bottle trembled and completely absorbed the lightning.

With a murmur, Han Li pointed at the air. Crackles sounded out as lightning arced from the bottle and formed a flickering ten-meter-tall pole pointing up into the dark sky. Silver lightning split the sky and struck the golden pole before it was dragged into the bottle.

This happened in great succession as more and more silver bolts struck down and was easily collected.

Two hours later, the bottle gathered another dense bolt and began to release the sounds of a rumbling storm.

When he heard this, he inwardly rejoiced. He raised his arm and reached out for the bottle, causing the golden pole to disappear and summoning the jade bottle into his hand.

He then flung his sleeve into the sky and produced another bottle of a similar appearance, repeating the process all over again.

With that done, he began to carefully examine the bottle that he recovered. It rumbled and trembled without end, flashing dazzling silver light from its mouth as if it could rupture at any moment.

Han Li slapped a golden talisman onto it, and the bottle’s activity came to a sudden halt. After properly placing the lid and putting it away, he turned his attention to the sky once more.

Half a day later, Han Li collected his fourth bottle, but the thunderstorm showed no signs of stopping. Rather, the rain only grew heavier.

He pondered to himself before putting away his fourth bottle. He believed he nearly collected enough lightning to create the heavenly flame he needed for the Triflame Fan’s materials.

But his expression stirred solemn and he suddenly turned to a corner of the sky. He faintly saw a flash, followed by the appearance of a white streak.

He knew that with the shining spell formation beneath him and the bolts of lightning wildly dancing above him, his position was extremely noticeable.

The white streak hurriedly shot in Han Li’s direction. It stopped a hundred meters away and the light disappeared to reveal a woman in palace robes.

She had a slender stature and a dainty appearance with a pair of vivid eyes, seeming to be a beauty in the prime of her youth. Her robes were made of some sort of rare material that not only shined with silver light but also glowed dazzlingly.

Han Li swept his spiritual sense past her and discovered that this woman was a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator much like himself.

She looked at him and sweetly smiled. She said with a soft, pleasant voice, “I am North Night Island’s Bai Yaoyi. Are you also here on business with Fellow Daoist Fu?”

Han Li’s heart trembled and he astoundingly asked, “Are you a cultivator from the North Night Palace?”

Bai Yaoyi chuckled, “I am the North Night Palace’s External Affairs Elder. Since we are located in a remote area, I am surprised that you know of it. May I ask for your esteemed name?”

Han Li calmed down and answered, “My surname is Han, a vagrant cultivator from overseas. I have indeed come to meet with Fellow Daoist Fu, though I have long heard of your palace’s resounding reputation.”

Bai Yaoyi stole an interested glance at Han Li and asked, “Oh, does Fellow Daoist Han know or have a relationship with any of the three great overseas Immortals?”

“I’ve never met them as I’m not someone who often deal with others. I normally cultivate in seclusion on my island.”

“So it was like that, I’ve been presumptuous. Does Fellow Daoist Han need any assistance in collecting lightning?”

“Many thanks for the offer, but I am about done. This will be the last bottle.”

When Bai Yaoyi heard him, she flew a circle in the air and landed on another rock. “Ah, then I will go ahead and rest as we wait.”

She raised her hand and summoned an umbrella magic tool up into the sky. It swirled in the air before releasing a cloud of white light down below, blocking any rain from approaching her. Then, she calmly sat down and summoned a palm-sized object into her hand in a flash of cold light.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and immediately glanced at the item. It was as white as fresh snow and shined with sparkling glamour.

‘Ice Jade!’ He immediately recognized: the same myriad year ice jade from the bottle the Glacial Quintessence he acquired!

Using the plate of ice jade in her hands, she closed her eyes and sank deep into meditation.

It appeared that the woman’s cultivation art wasn’t purely an ice attribute, but rather that of glacial Yin, else she wouldn’t have needed to draw on the support of the jade’s glacial power. This would produce a somewhat similar result to Han Li’s Snow Soul Pills, but it couldn’t possibly compare to the effectiveness, no matter the quality of the jade.

Though Han Li’s expression remained calm, he unconsciously grew wary of the woman.

Given how the North Night Palace would rather fight to the death against high-grade demon beasts every several generations than hand over some of their Glacial Quintessence, it was clear to see how much they valued it. If he allowed this woman to know he had her sect’s signature treasure on hand, it would certainly be troublesome.

Not long after, he put away his fifth bottle full of lightning and slowly floated to the center of the spirit gathering spell formation. Then after striking it with several spell seals, it formed an azure barrier around him, blocking the storm from disturbing him.

Then, he took a seat with his eyes closed. Of course, he couldn’t refine any of the Triflame Fan’s materials in this woman’s presence.

Soon, only the sounds of thunder and wind could be heard.

After an entire day, the rain finally began to slowly go away and the scorching sun appeared in the sky. The weather immediately became hot and humid as miasma slowly restored it domain, enveloping the entire range once more. In addition, the many insects that had taken refuge had again emerged from the ground.

With great calm, Han Li slowly released his spiritual sense to a ten kilometer range. Able to sense everything from the trees to the smallest insect all clearly in his mind, he sank into tranquil meditation.

Whenever low-grade cultivators made their way up the mountain, they would immediately flee with terror after discovering the astonishing cultivation of the two Nascent Soul cultivators.

As for Han Li and the palace-robed woman, they remained seated for three entire days.

On the morning of the fourth day, another high-grade cultivator eventually arrived on the main mountain. This time, it was a man with a towering stature. He had a grotesque appearance and dark, shiny skin. From the result of some unknown technique, he left behind an evil wind in his tracks as he flew here on a large tortoise shell.

When this large man saw them both, he heartily laughed and found another boulder to sit on. However, he had no intention of meditating. Instead, he took out a sparkling golden book and began to read it.

His scholarly actions made for a drastic contrast with his appearance. Although they had turned a blind eye to his actions, Han Li was in truth inwardly frowning.

This towering man was also at mid-Nascent Soul stage. It appeared that Old Man Fu’s objective would be unordinary to gather so many cultivators at their level.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: akiwimain

our dear editor believes that the third visitor looks like a certain character from a famous series.

Chapter 983: Black Crystals

Nearly a month later at the bottom of the Yin Yang Cave, Han Li stood in a giant wind cavern and held his hands in an incantation gesture. A dozen golden swords were revolving around him, shredding the countless moths flooding him into thin lines of black Qi.

The moths were several inches long and completely black. With each flap of their wings, they released thin blades of wind towards him, but they were all easily blocked by the golden light.

But with each fallen moth, two came to take its place. Han Li grew sullen with annoyance. He tossed a spirit beast pouch from his waist and summoned a swarm of sparkling golden beetles into the air.

When the black moths met the Gold Devouring Beetles, they suddenly began to shrink back as more of their numbers fell to the ground. When he saw this, he withdrew a majority of his flying swords and stepped into the depths of the cavern.

The Yin winds here were blowing with far greater frequency and blocked his more powerful spiritual sense from seeing even ten meters ahead. At the very least, he didn’t have to worry about being harassed by the moths.

After walking to the approximate center, his eyes shined with blue light, allowing him to see the nearby surroundings with clarity. But when he looked in a certain direction, he couldn’t help but gasp.

He walked sixty meters before tossing out a moonlight stone and carrying it in the air with a mist of azure light, illuminating ten meters around him.

Underneath the white light, a skull-sized black crystal was half embedded in the wall.

But what was astonishing was that the gem was flickering with a haunting light and would release black moths without end, swarming towards Han Li and the dazzling moonlight stone in a mad rush. However, the Gold Devouring Beetles had intercepted them midway, but when each moth was killed, they simply faded away as if they never existed.

“This is the third one, but it is able to use the nearby Yin Qi to create Dark Yin Moths. How peculiar,” Han Li muttered.

When Han Li took a closer look, he saw the black crystal release a flare of black light. A pop sounded out, followed by the appearance of a meter-wide moth. It fiercely glared at Han Li with crimson eyes.

Han Li raised his brow at the sight and flicked his finger, releasing a bolt of golden lightning and dispersing the moth in an instant. Although it was certain to have a few peculiar abilities, the Divine Devilbane Lightning was its natural nemesis.

Then, he reached out for the crystal without any hesitation, and a large hand of sparkling blue light appeared in front of him. With a bang, the crystal was taken out from the wall.

In the instant the crystal was grasped, the surrounding Yin winds were decreased by over half. All the moths had turned into black Qi in a bright flash and blew away in the wind.

Han Li didn’t appear particularly surprised by this and instead mulled over the two smaller crystals he found earlier in other wind caverns. These strange crystals caused Han Li to click his tongue in amazement, but he decided to leave the matter for later.

After his first return to Old Man Fu for another application of the Dark Violet Pearl’s protective light, he split up with Bai Yaoyi. Now that she wasn’t following him, Han Li made full use of his abilities.

Over the last few days, while he slowly headed deeper into the cave, he was several times faster than the others. He also came across high-grade ghosts with greater frequency, but his flying swords and golden lightning made short work of them. He hadn’t needed to use the Weeping Soul Beast even once.

It was starting to make sense why high-grade cultivators hadn’t explored the Yin Yang Cave. Deeper inside, he had found little, apart from a few abandoned magic tools and inferior ore veins.

But several days ago when he pursued a ghost, he unintentionally entered a small wind cavern. He initially had little interest in exploring it as the Umbra Yin Horse they were looking for shouldn’t be able to survive in a place with fierce Yin Winds. In addition, the frequent Yin winds in the cave would force him to consume even greater amounts of magic, even with the protection of the Dark Violet Pearl’s light. As such, it would prove quite difficult of him to tread deeper inside, but after he discovered the first black crystal, he became interested in exploring deeper. With the Divine Devilbane Lightning protecting him and the Myriad Spirit Milk to replenish his magic power, he also had little to fear.

Han Li hadn’t seen these black crystals before in any records. Although they resembled Devil Essence Diamonds at first glance, they were completely different.

They weren’t nearly as hard as Devil Essence Diamonds and didn’t contain devilish essence either. They appeared to be strange wind-attribute gems that were condensed inside these caverns for countless years, but they also contained large quantities of Yin Qi.

When Han Li searched through tens of wind caverns, he only managed to find three of them. The first two he found were the size of a fist, but the third and most recent one he found was the size of a skull and could produce ghosts.

After examining the gem for a long while and finding that it hadn’t made the slightest reaction, he stuck several restriction talismans on it before placing it in a large jade box and into his storage pouch.

After a cursory search through the large wind cavern to make sure he hadn’t missed anything, he withdrew to the passage where he came.

He traveled another kilometer and was searching through another small cavern, eventually finding that the tunnel became increasingly narrow. In the end, he was met with a wall of ice.

Han Li sighed but still continued forward. He raised his hand and released a streak of azure light, sinking deep into the icy wall. He didn’t stop there, and pressed his hand against it and swept his spiritual sense through.

After finding no mechanisms or restrictions, he turned around and moved back without another thought. He was several times faster on the way back than when he was exploring forward.

Although he didn’t know the exact shape of the Yin Yang Cave, they should be close to the heart of the cave given the variety of ghosts they’ve encountered. However, none of them had yet to discover any trace of the Umbra Yin Horse, much to Han Li’s impatience.

Since he had hurried to refine the Triflame Fan in preparation for this trip, he didn’t want to return empty-handed.

It was an extremely difficult affair for a Nascent Soul cultivator to breakthrough to a later stage. All cultivators who ascended to mid-Nascent Soul stage in the Heavenly South were blessed geniuses, and of these talents, only three were able to break through to late-Nascent Soul stage. And although there were more late-Nascent Soul cultivators in the Great Jin, they were still rarely seen.

As a result, Han Li had considered using the Copulation Essence Arts with Mu Peiling to break through the bottleneck to late-Nascent Soul stage, but it wasn’t a guarantee. Now that the Nascent Cultivating Pill appeared before him, he couldn’t allow the opportunity to pass him by.

If they truly couldn’t find the Umbra Yin Horse, he would have to see if he could acquire the medical formula of the Nascent Cultivating Pill from Old Man Fu. Although his chances were slim, if he could acquire the formula, he could try looking the Umbra Yin Horse elsewhere. After all, there were many places in the world where Yin Qi naturally gathered.

Han Li’s mind mulled over this matter as he flew through the tunnel.

But suddenly, his expression stirred and his attention turned to his front. A flicker of green light flashed in front of him and was flying in his direction. He instantly waved his sleeve in response, releasing a mist of azure in front of him. The green light was captured by the mist and dragged in front of him, revealing a gleaming sword that had a red jade slip attached to it.

Han Li pursed his lips and raised his hand, taking the slip into his hand before tossing the sword back into the air. The green sword let out a ring, circling in the air before flying through Yin winds without a trace.

Han Li ignored it and instead sank his spiritual sense into the jade slip.

“They’ve found traces of the Umbra Yin Horse!” A short moment later, Han Li withdrew from the jade slip with a smile. Then with a flip of his hand, he summoned a white formation plate.

He tapped it and in a flash of azure light, it became as glossy as a mirror. Four differently colored lights appeared on different places of the plate.

He looked at the positions of the light and immediately put it away before flying forward at greater speed.

Half a day later, Han Li arrived at a four-way intersection, finding Cultivator Yuan and Old Man Fu meditating there. The Dark Violet Pearl was floating motionlessly above the old man’s head.

After Han Li arrived, he asked, “Fellow Daoist Yuan, you’ve found it?”

“That’s right,” Cultivator Yuan chuckled and his face wore a trace of excitement, “The Umbra Yin Horse is in this passageway, but it is extremely cunning. I wasn’t able to capture it, and could only block the way out and wait for you all to arrive.”

“Good,” Han Li nodded with a smile, “So long as we know of its whereabouts, it will only be a matter of time.”

Old Man Fu happily said, “Junior Martial Sister Chang and Fellow Daoist Bai are still quite far away. Let’s wait. When we’re all present, the capture will be easier.”

When Han Li heard this, he felt relieved and also took a seat.

Several hours later, the black-robed woman and Bai Yaoyi rushed over. After they heard the news, they were also overjoyed. With several simple spell formations placed down at the passage entrance, they promptly set off inside.

Not long after, a dark light suddenly flashed from the ground underneath, followed by the emergence of three pitch-black dried corpses.

The chests of the corpses were all hollow and their bodies lacked any flesh, but their eyes shined with a chilling green light as they stared in the direction of Han Li’s party without the slightest emotion.

Translator's Thoughts

Foreshadowing~

ED: akiwimain

Chapter 985: Ghostfiend Threads

As the Corpse Wolf moved to escape, a crimson light flashed near its side to reveal a red needle. It flickered and pierced through the green flames protecting the wolf’s body in a crimson line, cutting through with incredible sharpness.

In the huge wolf’s alarm, it attempted to turn its head and avoid the attack, but the needle had already pierced through its neck. A deafening painful howl followed, and the black Qi that gathered around it’s legs disappeared into the nearby Yin winds. When the group saw this, they rejoiced.

“Pursue it!” Someone yelled. The party then began to glow, intending to quickly fly after it.

However, a cry sounded out from a pouch at Han Li’s waist. Although it was soft, Han Li’s expression vastly changed and he flicked his hand, shooting several azure swordstreaks at an area over thirty meters away. As the attack drew closer, a dark light shined from the ground to reveal several jet-black figures. One of them had easily repelled the swordstreaks with a flick of their finger.

Afterwards, Yin winds began to erupt with great strength and the three figures were partially concealed. These three were the same dried corpses that had appeared at the intersection that the cultivators had passed. It was unknown what they conspired or how they evaded the spell formations that had been placed, but they managed to tail them with profound concealment.

Just as Han Li and company were about to give chase, one of the dried corpses had revealed a trace of its aura in a moment of carelessness, allowing Han Li’s Weeping Soul Beast to detect it. These dried corpses were entirely shriveled, and were of differing heights. Han Li even recalled having seen one before, as he had struck it with lightning and turned it to dust.

While Han Li betrayed shock from his face, the others all let out a cry of alarm.

“How can that decayed corpse move?” The black-robed woman shouted out in astonishment, “When I discovered it, it was without life.”

Bai Yaoyi was also particularly surprised as she had discovered one alongside Han Li as well.

“You recognize these ghosts? We can’t deal with them now; we must first give chase to the Umbra Yin Horse. Fellow Daoist Han and Junior Martial Sister Chang, deal with these ghosts for the time being. The rest of us will chase after the horse. If it conceals itself once more, it will be difficult to find again.” Although Old Man Fu was greatly alarmed by the appearance of these three mysterious ghosts, he obviously prioritized the capture of the Umbra Yin Horse. From his point of view, Han Li and his Junior Martial Sister shouldn’t have a problem dealing with these three strange refined corpses, neither would his three have any problem with the Corpse Wolf. None of the other party members had raised an objection as well.

After the black-clothed woman curtly agreed and Han Li nodded, Old Man Fu and the others flew in the direction of the Corpse Wolf without further hesitation.

Han Li then put away his flying needle, and stood beside the black-robed woman, both of them coldly glaring at the dried corpses. Although Ghost Dao techniques were abnormally sly by nature, he found it incomprehensible that one of them was able to survive a strike from Divine Devilbane Lightning. Nevertheless, he still maintained a calm appearance, despite the increased vigilance in his heart.

As for the black-robed woman, she was an elder of the Nine Serenities Sect and possessed much understanding of both devilish and ghost techniques. Not daring to underestimate these corpses either, she had her giant red sword revolve above her in a display of dazzling glamour, protecting her rather than attacking.

The three corpses facing them were the first to move. The taller of the lot took two large steps forward and opened its mouth to spit out a grey thread towards the woman.

“You’re courting death!” She snorted with a sullen appearance. With a flick of her sleeve, over ten fireballs shot out in succession. Soon after, she pointed to the huge sword above her head and it sliced through the air, releasing a crimson swordstreak. She believed that this unremarkable thread was simply condensed corpse flames and that fire techniques should be able to restrain it.

But then, the thread passed through both the fireballs and the red swordstreak without resistance, thoroughly absorbing their entire being with just a touch, and continued to rush forward without any sign of slowing down.

The black-robed woman swept her sleeve in alarm and produced a small green shield in front of her. It glowed with light and massively expanded. At nearly the same time, the huge sword above her head chopped down towards the grey thread.

The black-robed woman believed that since the thread was able to absorb attacks of spiritual power, physical treasures should be able to block it.

As predicted, the grey thread stopped upon being struck with the huge sword.

The beautiful woman rejoiced and thought to activate the sword’s abilities, but then the grey thread suddenly blurred and multiplied into a hundred copies of itself, quickly moving to restrain the huge sword. Afterwards, a strange dark light glowed from the threads, fusing together with the sword’s red light, slowly overwhelming it and turning it black as if it were being corrupted. The woman also felt her mental connection to the sword grow dull.

Her heart sank and she slapped her storage pouch without another thought, summoning a dharmic wheel [1] into her hand.

But before she could use it to free her sword, thunder rang out, followed by a bolt of dazzling lightning. The golden bolt struck the grey threads in rumbling wrath and freed the large red sword.

“Many thanks, Brother Han!” The woman hurriedly uttered before forming a hand gesture and recalling her sword into her sleeve after splitting into three red streaks.

With her weapon freed, Han Li didn’t pay any further attention. Rather, he was staring at the air with a tight frown. The grey threads he had scattered apart condensed back into its original form after only a short delay. As for the other two dried corpses, they hadn’t yet taken any action.

When the black-robed woman saw this, her expression turned unsightly, but she continued to look at the grey thread in the air.

“This isn’t ordinary corpse Qi, but that of a Baleful Corpse Qi. Could this be a Ghostfiend Thread?” She cried out with a deeply pale complexion.

“Baleful Corpse Qi?” Han Li found the name familiar and after a moment of thought, he recalled it being mentioned in the Great Development Treasure Scriptures [2] .

His expression wavered for a time. This was a grand ability of the Ghost Dao that few cultivators ever could witnessed.

As the name implied, Baleful Corpse Qi was originally corpse Qi, but fused with the lingering resentment of a fresh death — what was otherwise known as baleful Qi.

Baleful Corpse Qi was said to be extremely difficult to manufacture, at minimum requiring the corpses of Core Formation cultivators along with other unknown conditions. When it took form, it was said to be everlasting, and was capable of absorbing elemental Qi and corrupting various magic treasures. As expected for one of the greatest abilities of the Ghost Dao, it was beyond difficult to deal with.

However, he hadn’t heard of a Ghostfiend Thread before, but given that it was created from Baleful Corpse Qi, it was no wonder it was so troublesome. It seemed his Divine Devilbane Lightning was able to disperse it but not exterminate it entirely.

As these thoughts flew through his mind, all three of the corpses simultaneously raised their hands and flicked their fingers, each releasing grey threads.

The black-robed woman deeply gasped and unleashed the dharmic wheel from her hand, chanting a series of evocations. The wheel whirled in the air and shined with a seven-colored light, covering both Han Li and her in a barrier.

‘Seven-colored light, a Buddhist treasure?’ Han Li had already raised his hand with arcs of lightning sparking between them, but when he saw her take action, he paused with a trace of surprise. The threads then struck the seven-colored barrier but were all completely repelled.

Han Li wasn’t astonished by the barrier’s effectiveness. Since Buddhist techniques were specialized in restraining the Ghost Dao, even something as vicious as Ghostfiend Threads shouldn’t be able to break through Buddhist light in an instant. But what surprised Han Li was the fact that a devilish sect elder even possessed a Buddhist treasure.

The three hadn’t stopped their attack after seeing that their threads were repelled. Instead, their fingers stirred and countless grey threads began to take form in the air and weaved countless layers of threads on top of the seven-colored barrier, as if intending on thoroughly trapping the two within it.

A cold glint flashed from Han Li’s eyes and he slapped his hands together, raising them to release two dense arcs of golden lightning at the barrier of light protecting them. As loud crackles sounded out, a net of lightning appeared on the surface of the barrier and instantly dissolved the grey threads.

The three corpses didn’t seem to care when they saw this. They simply shot out more Ghostfiend Threads from their hands and restored the form of the grey Qi that had been scattered.

“Fellow Daoist Chang, open it up!” With that said, thunder rang from Han Li’s back, revealing a pair of silver wings.

She thought to persuade him otherwise, but after seeing the wings, she immediately uttered an incantation and created a fine opening in the barrier.

His wings flapped and he disappeared in a flash of silver light.

The three corpses suddenly stopped when they saw this and began to look around. Then, the light flashed once more meters behind them to reveal Han Li. The corpses instantly flicked their fingers in response and shot dozens of grey threads at him.

Han Li didn’t remotely attempt to dodge, instead opening his mouth to spit out three golden streaks in the direction of each corpse.

[1]. Eight spoked wheel commonly associated with Buddhism.

[Back]

[2]. Monarch Soul Divergence’s autobiography, and collection of techniques and secrets. He gave it to Han Li before he passed.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ed: akiwimain

Chapter 986: Silver-winged Nightfiend

It was clear that Han Li’s golden light was far faster than the grey threads. In sharp gusts of wind, the three small golden swords pierced through the corpses’ abdomens.

At nearly that same moment, the Ghostfiend Threads had arrived in front of Han Li and were about to strike him.

However, Han Li let out a shout and a ring of seven-colored light suddenly appeared around him. When the threads touched it, they became disconnected from the world.

When the black-robed woman saw this seven-colored light, she was stunned.

Han Li then expressionlessly pointed at the three dried corpses in the distance.

Three bolts of lightning escaped from the small swords, followed by loud pangs of thunder, each of them covering the three corpses in a net of lightning.

Before the corpses could even let out a groan, the lightning turned them into clouds of black dust, continuing to tear at the dust clouds and prevent them from reforming, but it appeared that the corpses were undying in the face of the Divine Devilbane Lightning.

Han Li frowned at the sight of this.

The black-robed woman rejoiced upon seeing him restrain them and happily put away her light barrier. She flew over and proposed, “These refined corpses had fused Baleful Corpse Qi with their own bodies. I fear we won’t be able to kill them. We’ll have to use restrictions to seal them for the time being.”

“There is no need to waste such effort, it is unknown what strange abilities these ghosts have. Common restrictions might not be able to seal them. Rather, let’s just finish them off.”

“Finish them off?”

The black-robed woman wore an odd expression, and before she realized what he meant, Han Li slapped his storage pouch and a streak of black light flew out, circling once around him before revealing itself to be a small monkey, the Weeping Soul Beast.

It was awakened by the smell of corpse Qi and immediately reveled in excitement. It let out a snort with its large nose without any command, releasing a hazy light that easily absorbed the clouds of dust from within the net of lightning and brought it into its mouth.

After a few eager gulps, it held its hands on its stomach with satisfaction and joy.

The black-robed woman was dumbstruck by these events.

There were only a few spirit beasts in this world that were capable of devouring ghosts, but she had never heard of a small monkey capable of consuming such powerful ghosts. The closest thing that came to mind was the Jade-eyed Ape, but its appearance didn’t match in the slightest.

As the black-robed woman mulled, Han Li was relieved to find that the Weeping Soul Beast wasn’t negatively affected by absorbing the three dried corpses.

But rather than immediately withdrawing the beast, he beckoned to, promptly having it obediently jump on his shoulder.

Han Li glanced at the black-robed woman and said, “Let’s go, perhaps Brother Fu has already finished capturing the Umbra Yin Horse.”

Suppressing her curiosity towards the monkey, she smiled, “Most likely, that Corpse Wolf has already been injured by you and shouldn’t be able to run far.”

Han Li returned the smile but before he could say anything, he felt his body tremble. The two of them exchanged bewildered glances, and each summoned a formation plate in their hands.

Han Li took a deep breath and solemnly asked, “Fellow Daoist Yuan’s marker is gone. Fellow Daoist Chang, do you know what’s going on?”

“My marker on Fellow Daoist Yuan is also gone. How could something have happened after only a short time separated!” The black-robed woman spoke with disbelief.

“I’m not sure,” Han Li answered, “It is possible that the others encountered a formidable enemy, or that Fellow Daoist Yuan was careless and became trapped in a restriction.”

“In that case, we must hurry. Their markers show them to be nearby,” the black-robed woman said with a trace of worry.

Han Li indifferently nodded and the two set off in streaks of light.

...

After flying for about five kilometers, they encountered a large spacious area filled with piles of ore refuse.

The two then slowed down and carefully examined the area.

After another three hundred meters, the piles disappeared and opened into a large room.

The place had a huge spell formation that nearly covered it all and a giant bamboo tree growing at its center, reaching all the way to the top of the cave. There were also a dozen giant stone pillars intermittently placed, each with a pitch-black dried corpse chained to it, exactly the same as the three Han Li had seen before.

But what shocked Han Li was a silhouette covered in green hair next to the bamboo. It was sitting there absorbed in munching on a headless body. From its clothes, there was no doubt that was Cultivator Yuan’s corpse.

Next to the monster was a huge figure, the Corpse Wolf they fought from before. The wolf was gnawing at something underneath its claw, Cultivator Yuan’s huge tortoise. It lacked an aura, clearly indicating it’s death.

As for the Umbra Yin Horse, it was still perched on top of the Corpse Wolf’s head, unmoving.

The black-robed woman’s face paled and she hurriedly glanced around before shouting in terror, “Senior Martial Brother Fu!”

Han Li followed her gaze and saw two figures floating in midair, wrapped in cocoons spun from grey threads. It was clearly the Ghostfiend Threads they had seen previously.

However, the density of the threads were far beyond what the dried corpses could produce.

Thunderous explosions continuously sounded out from the two with traces of dazzling light occasionally escaping from within.

It appeared that Old Man Fu and Bai Yaoyi still lived.

In only a short moment, one of three mid-Nascent Soul cultivators were killed with two of them trapped. Han Li managed to maintain a calm appearance in spite of this but he was thoroughly aghast.

As for the black-robed woman, she was worried for Old Man Fu, but knew this wasn’t the time to save him. She shook her sleeve and summoned the dharmic wheel into her hand before turning her attention elsewhere.

Meanwhile, the green-furred monster hadn’t paid any attention to them and was focused on eating with a lowered head.

Strange cracking sounds came from the monster as it tore off the arm of Cultivator Yuan’s corpse and quickly ravaged it.

When Han Li caught sight of the mutilated body, he narrowed his eyes as blue light shined from them.

Then the Weeping Soul Beast on his shoulder let out a high-pitched cry, and the fur on its back stood straight. It glared at the green-furred monster, assuming a position to attack.

But from the Weeping Soul Pearl within his body, Han Li could sense that that the monkey mostly felt fear as if it had encountered its nemesis.

The monster heard the Weeping Soul Beast’s scream and its feasting came to a sudden halt. It flung away the corpse in its hand and flew sixty meters towards the two cultivators before landing on the ground.

Han Li’s and the black-robed woman’s face warped upon sensing its powerful aura.

The green-furred monster simply stood in place as it watched them.

At that moment, Han Li was finally able to clearly see the monster’s appearance. Its face appeared very much like that of a monkey, with blood brimming in its mouth and razor fangs several inches long. Its eyes sparkled with sharp silver and lacked irises, making for a rather odd appearance.

But what especially caught Han Li’s eye were the two protrusions from its back wrapped with flesh.

The green-furred monster swept its gaze past the cultivators with indifference and locked eyes on the Weeping Soul Beast perched on Han Li’s shoulder. Then its face revealed an odd expression resembling bewilderment.

When the Weeping Soul Beast met the green monster’s gaze, it leaped ten meters in front of Han Li and pounded its chest with all its might, causing black light to surge all around it.

In the blink of an eye, it grew thirty meters tall to become a vicious ape that had the image of a malevolent crimson ghost on its back that appeared to move with life.

The green-furred monster seemed to sense something from the Weeping Soul Beast’s transformation and hastily took several steps back. At that same time, the bags of flesh protruding his back trembled and tore apart, revealing two three-meter-long wings that shined a dazzling silver.

“Silver-winged Nightfiend!”

The black-robed woman shouted out its name with a faceful of terror and his complexion paled.

In the mortal world, Silver-winged Nightfiends were refined corpses that were capable of flight and were seconded only by Gold-clad Lunar Corpses. They were a fearsome existence that were said to be superior to even late-Nascent Soul cultivators.

Not only were they a natural prodigy of wind and earth-attributed movement techniques, it was nearly invulnerable, incredibly strong, and quite skilled in illusion and bewitchment.

As these thoughts quickly flashed from Han Li’s mind, he tightly pursed his lips.

Light flashed from the beast’s wings, and its fear of the Weeping Soul Beast immediately disappeared. It loudly uttered, “I didn’t expect more would come to find me. It’s been quite some time since I’ve had...fresh meat. You will all make quite a meal.”

These words were spoken as clearly as a human’s voice.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: akiwimain

Chapter 993: Change in the Sky

Not long after, the others returned from examining the concealment formations and they all found the same result. The formations were annihilated and the disciples in charge had disappeared.

With this, all those present felt that there was something greatly amiss and they fell silent.

The scholar bitterly laughed and said, “There are no other cultivators within fifty kilometers. And it is too timely an occurrence for someone to break our concealment while we are dissolving the seal. It seems this is the doing of one of us.”

“One of us?”

“How is that possible? There are only Ye Clan members here. What is going on?”

“No, there is someone that doesn’t truly belong to our clan!”

After some discussion, it was obvious who came to mind.

A majority of the cultivators all turned to look at a single person.

He had a common appearance and a calm face; he was the disguised Elder Devil.

The Ye Clan Grand Elder said, “Elder Han is someone that I personally invited, and he has always remained at Seventh Uncle’s side.”

“That’s right!” The large-headed eccentric said, “Fellow Daoist Han has always stayed close.”

When the other cultivators heard this, their suspicions were dispelled.

Then, the scholar turned to the square-faced cultivator and said, “Second Brother, can you check the bottom of the lake and see if there is anyone missing apart from the disciples that have disappeared.”

“Yes,” the square-faced man readily agreed. Afterwards, he flew deep underwater in a radiant streak.

The scholar solemnly said, “Clan Elders, let’s all make our preparations. Although an astonishing change had occurred and we can no longer conceal this matter, there will be no threats to us during this short time. Nanjiang has no extremely powerful sects and it will require at least half a month for those who could contend with us to arrive. We may not know what lies in Kunwu Mountain, but we will need to excavate its hidden treasures as soon as possible. The two Divine Spirit Treasures in particular must be acquired first, or we will not have the power to defend ourselves against the coming storm. Those parasites have been plotting against us for thousands of years, and will exterminate our clan given the opportunity. Failure is not an option.”

The others felt their hearts tremble at his words and replied in sync, “As you command, Grand Elder!”

...

Soon, the square-faced cultivator, the Grand Elder, and the old formation grandmaster were gathered above the lake.

“Third Brother, there are two spell formation masters missing: the nephews of Old Fifth and Twelfth. Could it be they betrayed us?” The square-faced cultivator sullenly spoke.

The scholar snorted, “It is more likely they were killed and had their souls scoured. When did they go missing?”

With a face lined in cold sweat, the white-haired old man answered, “About two days ago, Grand Elder. They were in charge of the spell formations farthest away, so their disappearance hadn’t raised any suspicions. We only discovered they were missing after the disciples had gathered.”

The scholar coldly replied, “It seems the problem stemmed from those two. But what happened to them is no longer important. When we enter Kunwu Mountain, we will have all our disciples and spell formation masters depart. Have we verified the location of the seal’s opening?”

“Yes, it is ten kilometers north and three kilometers deep. The opening itself should be a hundred meters wide.”

“Lead the way, we set off now,” The scholar spoke without hesitation.

“Yes, Grand Elder!” The white-haired old man bowed.

The party of nine was led north and soon arrived above a verdant jungle.

The white-haired old man swept his gaze down below before summoning a silver plate with a flip of his hand.

After muttering an incantation, the old man struck it with a spell seal, causing its surface to glow with argent light and talisman characters.

“It’s here!” The old man looked at the spell plate for a moment before confirming its location.

“Good!” The scholar then turned to the old Daoist Nun and said, “Ninth Sister, release your spirit beast. We’re descending.”

The nun uttered a brief acknowledgment and a slapped a spirit beast pouch by her waist. A yellow light shot out from it and expanded to reveal a thirty-meter-long, thousand-legged centipede. Green Qi leaked from its mouth in a rather sinister fashion.

Apart from the white-clothed old man, all the Ye Clan cultivators flew onto the centipede’s back.

The nun shouted out a command and a layer of yellow light surrounded the centipede’s body, covering all of the cultivators that sat on it. Then, it dug straight down, disappearing in the blink of an eye.

The old man floated above around for a moment. After seeing no sign that the Ye Clan cultivators would return, he let out a long sigh and flew back.

...

Meanwhile in the sky a hundred kilometers away, there were several blue-robed cultivators wearing red headbands. They were looking at the pillars of light in the distance and exchanged looks of dismay.

A twenty-year-old youth amongst them asked, “What could possible cause such an astonishing scene!”

The tan middle-aged cultivator in charge spoke with a grim expression, “It certainly isn’t ordinary. Junior Martial Brother Yu, quickly report back to the sect. I will bring the rest of the disciples to take a look.”

When he heard this, he flew off on his magic tool.

The others then travelled towards the light.

...

In place further away, there were over a hundred variously-dressed cultivators gathered together on a tall mountain. They all possessed lesser cultivation, with a majority of them at Qi Condensation stage.

Although their cultivation was low, they clearly saw the pillars of light in the distance. They all stood up and gazed in the direction of the light.

...

Underneath a desolate mountain, there stood a plump old man at a half-open stone gate. He was looking at the pillars of light in the distance with a pensive expression.

...

The exposed pillars continued to attract flocks of cultivators from all backgrounds as time passed.

Not long after, information of a grand treasure appearing in the world spread across Nanjiang at a shocking speed.

Several days later, this news spread to the nearby regions, stirring the entirety of Nanjiang with activity.

As this all happened, Han Li found himself standing at the center of a huge teleportation formation within a giant stalactite cave.

He was gloomily looking beneath him, catching sight of the shattered rings that glowed with sparkling red light.

They were the magic tools that were restraining the Silver-winged Nightfiend.

With those rings shattered, he had no idea where the nightfiend could’ve gone.

With that thought, he took a gander at his waist.

There was a jade talisman that glowed luminescent.

It had familiar markings. They belonged to a rarely seen teleportation talisman, one he last saw them in the Scattered Star Seas.

He frowned and flipped his hand to produce a glowing blue medallion: the Greater Teleportation Medallion he acquired long ago.

Fearing that he could be completely torn apart from the spatial pressure, he had summoned the medallion into his hand before the teleportation had finished.

Of course, he couldn't have expected that just as the formation’s light was about to absorb him, a similar talisman would suddenly appear at his waist.

It was unknown if there was something odd about the formation itself, or if the creators had made peculiar arrangements.

Regardless, this formation was quite different from current designs and was worth researching.

As Han Li thought this, he reached for the talisman at his waist, but before he could even touch it, it shattered into specks of light.

Han Li bitterly smiled after a brief moment of surprise.

It was quite painstaking to refine a teleportation talisman, and it would only have enough spiritual power for a single use. It appears this applied to other teleportation talismans as well.

As for the others, he looked nearby to find the Weeping Soul Beast and the two suspended grey cocoons, also attached with now-shattered jade talismans.

As for the Corpse Wolf, it was dead, and the ten-meter-tall Weeping Soul Beast was jumping on top of it and pounding its chest with excitement.

Because of Han Li’s immense spiritual sense, he was able to quickly recover from the dizziness of the teleportation and used the opportunity to lethally injure it with a bolt of Divine Devilbane Lightning.

Then, the Weeping Soul Beast followed up with a snort of yellow mist, absorbing all of the Corpse Qi from the wolf’s body and easily finished it off.

The Silver-winged Nightfiend, however, didn’t seem to care, neither did he had any intention of continuing the fight.

He had finally gained his freedom, and decided to immediately use this opportunity to depart with the wind.

Translator's Thoughts

ed: akiwimain

Chapter 994: Heaven Reaching Mountain

Han Li had no intention of chasing after the Silver-winged Nightfiend in this new place. Without the barrier trapping the nightfiend, he wouldn’t be able to easily slay it with the Triflame Fan. Also...

He turned to look at the Weeping Soul Beast, who was now waving a white object in its hand, and smiled.

Upon closer inspection, it was a small delicate horse with two green eyes and was half a foot tall.

It was the Umbra Yin Horse, the objective of their dangerous journey.

Just as the teleportation began, it concealed itself once more on the Corpse Wolf’s body. As a result, it was captured when the Weeping Soul Beast had used its yellow mist to extract the Corpse Wolf’s Qi.

If Han Li hadn’t noticed and commanded the Weeping Soul Beast to stop, the Umbra Yin Horse might’ve been devoured.

As for the two flying swords that the nightfiend had captured, it paid them no mind after the teleportation, and Han Li was able to easily take them back. Unfortunately for the black-robed woman’s Nascent Soul, the nightfiend had swallowed it before escaping.

The sole thing that left him gloomy was that his crystal flying needle had been captured by the Silver-winged Nightfiend.

Fortunately, the nightfiend shouldn’t be able to erase his spiritual marks in a short time. There could be an opportunity to seize it back.

Having settled these thoughts, Han Li looked around him. It closely resembled the underground cavern they were in, but no Yin winds were present and the air was filled with an abundant spiritual Qi. It appeared this cave was located above a top quality spirit vein.

He then looked at the spell formation he was stepping on.

From his knowledge and experience, he was able to tell that it was clearly a receiving spell formation. In other words, there was no way to return using the formation.

Han Li frowned in thought for a moment before turning his attention to the huge cocoons.

They contained strong pulses of spiritual Qi, clearly indicating that Old Man Fu and Bai Yaoyi were still alive.

Han Li hesitated for a moment before waving at the Weeping Soul Beast and summoning the Umbra Yin Horse into his hand. Then, he placed it in a spirit beast pouch after sticking several restrictive talismans on it.

With that done, Han Li raised his hand and released two dense bolts of golden lightning at the grey cocoons.

An explosion sounded out as the lightning wrapped around the cocoons in a huge net.

This battle between the lightning and the threads lasted for a time.

Without the control of the Silver-winged Nightfiend, the Ghostfiend Threads began to disperse layer after layer within the lightning.

Eventually, the cocoons burst to reveal Old Man Fu and Bai Yaoyi.

The two had pale complexions and unsightly expressions.

After spending so much time trapped by the Ghostfiend Threads, they were certain to have gone through excruciating pain, considering their magic power had been forcefully absorbed by the threads.

Old Man Fu relaxed and saluted him. “Many thanks for your rescue, Brother Han!”

Bai Yaoyi gave a bow and wryly smiled, “If it weren’t for Brother Han’s great abilities, I fear we would’ve all perished. Who could’ve known the Yin Yang Cave was home to a Silver-winged Nightfiend. We weren’t able to defend ourselves when that monster ambushed us. In the struggle, Fellow Daoist Yuan lost his Nascent Soul and perished.”

Han Li faintly smiled when he heard their thanks.

Although the two appeared grateful, Han Li noticed a trace of fear deep within their eyes.

After all, the two were able to clearly sense the battle as they were trapped.

Han Li not only had the power to contend against the Silver-winged Nightfiend, but was even able to force him to flee. The two absolutely wouldn’t stand a chance against him, and given the fact that they were teleported to some mysterious place were no one else was around, they couldn’t help but feel greatly uneasy.

If Han Li possessed malicious intentions, things wouldn’t end well for them.

Without any regard to this, Han Li tossed a spirit beast pouch to Old Man Fu, “The Umbra Yin Horse is in there. If you manage to produce extra pills, give me two of them. Is this acceptable?”

Old Man Fu’s heart relaxed and he said, “Of course. If I produce enough, they are yours.”

Bai Yaoyi smiled, “I also have no objections. I am quite ashamed to have entirely relied on your power. It is only natural for you to receive a higher share.”

Han Li then looked in the direction of the cave’s exit and narrowed his eyes, “Good! Fellow Daoists, you should rest here. I’ll scout ahead and see how it looks outside.”

“Brother Han, please go ahead. We could use the rest.” Old Man Fu raised no objections.

Bai Yaoyi nodded and sat down cross-legged.

Han Li smiled, and azure light glowed from his body before he streaked forward. At the same time, he fully released his spiritual sense in case the Silver-winged Nightfiend was hiding anywhere nearby or if the two cultivators planned on sneaking away. His tracking markers on the two still had a few days before they expired.

As Han Li was no saint, the thought of killing them for their treasures briefly appeared in his mind.

However, he knew too little about the Nascent Nurturing Pill. Even if he were able to acquire the formula for it, his odds of creating it weren’t very high. The two had also given him a favorable impression, so he had no desire to kill them.

As such, he had taken the initiative to release them after a moment of thought.

When he left the main chamber, he found a flight of stairs that went up. He wasn’t able to see where it ended.

Strange, could it be they were deep underground?

Feeling somewhat surprised, he flew directly up.

Not long after, Han Li grew astonished. He had flown up the stairs for a while, but it still kept going.

Although he had only flown for a short time, his speed was quite impressive. If it weren’t for the fact that his spiritual sense was able to clearly see his surroundings, he would’ve suspected he had fallen into a restriction of some sort.

‘How could a passage possibly be so long?’

Han Li had flown several kilometers before finally seeing the light at the end.

When he flew out from the passage, his environment lit up and he found himself in a large paved area. The entire floor which spanned over three kilometers was made of stone bricks. And he could smell the sweet fragrance of plants.

The spiritual Qi was even more dense than down below at the teleportation formation.

However, this all paled in comparison to what he saw when he swept his gaze forward.

At the end of the paved area, there was a tall cliff face, and when he looked up, he only saw a mountain without end.

There was also a tall mountain wall behind him. It appears that he was lying at their valley.

Han Li looked to the sky for a long while only to find a few winding cliffs.

Then without another thought, and he took to the skies.

After flying several kilometers, Han Li eventually flew out from the valley, revealing a sight he couldn't believe. Soon, he hastily shot forward and circled his surroundings before returning to his original place.

The only word that came to Han Li’s mind was “Big”.

Han Li had seen countless mountains over his lifetime, the largest of them being the Heavenly Star Island’s sacred mountain.

The huge mountain before him appeared to be a pillar reaching for the heavens, and what he saw alone could even be divided into eighty-one stories to house a vast number of cultivators to his lowest estimate.

He was currently at the base of the huge mountain, and couldn't make an accurate comparison in size to the Heavenly Star Island’s sacred mountain, though he could take a guess at which was larger.

When he raised his head, he saw a deep turquoise sky without end. The valley he emerged from was nothing but an insignificant crack in the mountains.

But what especially troubled Han Li and rendered him speechless was that the mountain had a huge restriction placed on top of it.

When he looked to the outskirts, he saw a white light-barrier appearing to cover the mountain in its entirety.

Such a massive sight left Han Li in awe; This was definitely the doing of ancient cultivators.

With some hesitation, he hastily flew over and arrived in front of it by the time it took to finish a cup of tea.

He was nothing but a mere speck in comparison to the massive barrier.

He examined it for a long while but flew back, unable to see precisely how thick it was.

‘There is no point in testing its power,’ he thought. Let alone a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator, even a Deity Transformation cultivator wouldn’t be able to destroy it with brute force.

When Han Li looked back at the mountain, he couldn't help but notice the distinct lack of any sound. He couldn't even hear the birds chirping, as if the mountains had no life at all.

This was quite odd with the fiercely abundant spiritual Qi surrounding the mountain, giving Han Li a bizarre feeling.

With a gloomy expression on his face, he returned to the valley and arrived back at the teleportation formation.

Translator's Thoughts

ed: akiwimain

Chapter 997: Splitting the Pills

The cultivators of the Sacred Poison Sect couldn't have possibly known that their Junior Martial Brother Yuan had perished at the hands of the Silver-winged Nightfiend. After they chatted for a moment more, they made haste to quickly hurry on their way.

The sooner they arrived, after all, the better.

Above a small lake in the Puyun Province, there were already several hundreds of various cultivators gathered.

Many of them were flying about in the sky searching around the seven pillars of light.

There were a few cultivators skilled in earth movement techniques that occasionally burrowed into the ground, and excitedly spoke with a few of their companions standing on the surface.

It was clear that these people had already discovered the huge seal underneath.

As for the opening the Ye Clan forcefully split open, they had yet to find it.

But even so, all of the cultivators in the area were extremely excited and sent voice transmission talismans to each of their own clans and sects. There were even those that flew throughout the night to report the matter in person.

Currently, a majority of the cultivators present were at Foundation Establishment stage with sparsely few Qi Condensation and Core Formation cultivators amongst them. Most of them were also vagrants that had unintentionally discovered the pillars of light and rushed over, but a few of them were scouts sent by various powers to investigate.

There were currently no Nascent Soul cultivators.

This was no surprise. The small lake originally belonged to a desolate area with nothing of note nearby. With no large clans or sect present, there was no reason for a Nascent Soul cultivator to be there.

Even the Sacred Poison Sect, who immediately rushed over at first news of this event, was still two days away.

However, when it was discovered that there was a giant seal underground, the more experienced vagrant cultivators all made the decision to wisely depart despite their reluctance. While the seal may reap amazing profits, but the ensuing battle of high grade cultivators that would ensue over them wasn’t something they could participate in. If they continued to stay and the area became a battleground for high-grade cultivators, it would end in disaster.

Of course, there were many younger, more spirited low-grade cultivators rather unwilling to depart. Not only did they want to see what laid beneath, they also had a small hope of being lucky. Their cultivation wasn’t high, but if the opportunity arose, they could achieve grand rewards. It was a gamble they were willing to take.

As such, all sorts of characters gathered there, carrying their own designs and thoughts.

...

In the cave at the heart of a giant mountain, Han Li and Bai Yaoyi were sitting cross-legged, staring at Old Man Fu with complete focus.

Though in reality, they were staring at the sparkling golden cauldron in front of him. It was a meter tall and slowly revolved above the ground.

Old Man Fu spat out thin strands of green Nascent Flame and held his hands in an unknown gesture, occasionally striking at the cauldron with spell seals. With each strike, more of the green flames surrounding the cauldron turned into rainbow light, making for a gorgeous display.

Medicinal scents were already bleeding from the cauldron. The aroma was rich and pleasant.

His face grew solemn and his strikes turned fervent. It was clear that he was in a crucial moment of pill refinement.

Han Li observed with a calm expression, contrary to the nervousness in his heart.

Old Man Fu had successively tossed in the Umbra Yin Horse and other rare materials into the cauldron over the past few days. This was their one shot. A second chance would be near impossible, as some ingredients simply couldn't be found again.

Although Old Man Fu was confident in his refinement of the Nascent Cultivating Pill, Han Li felt apprehensive and concerned as he watched.

Bai Yaoyi wasn’t faring much better, as her eyes glistening with a burning fervor.

Then, the cauldron came to a sudden stop. Hums droned out from it and the medicinal scent grew even denser.

Old Man Fu’s eyes lit up, and his past actions all came to a stop. He then flipped his hand to produce a vermillion gourd that was only five inches tall.

With his other hand, he flicked his finger, sending a speck of white light to strike the lid of the cauldron.

The lid trembled before sliding off.

With the hums coming to a stop, five fist-sized balls of white light shot out with a thumb-sized green pill floating at their center. The pills themselves glowed a glistening emerald.

These wisps circled once above the cauldron before scattering towards different locations.

Old Man Fu was already prepared, and hastily shook the gourd to release a mist from it. Then in a flash, the balls of light were sucked inside.

The old man let out a long sigh and smiled, “Alright! It’s a success!”

Bai Yaoyi shot up and happily said, “Thank you for your trouble, Brother Fu. I didn’t expect that you’d be able to refine five. Originally, I feared that the number of pills would fall short.” Her face had a rosy complexion, adding much to her charm.

“When I gathered together the materials, I had enough to refine about five or six pills. Why else would I invite five fellow Daoists to assist me? It is a pity that my Junior Martial Sister and Fellow Daoist Yuan hadn’t survived.” The old man’s smile then disappeared.

It was clear that the he and the black-robed woman had a deep relationship. Although death was common sight amongst cultivators, the joy of success in creating the medicine pills wasn’t able to overcome such a loss.

When Bai Yaoyi heard him, her smile disappeared as well and she let out a sigh.

Unlike the others, Han Li’s expression remained unchanged, but he did keep silent.

Then, the old man’s sadness quickly faded and he said, “Fellow Daoist Bai, do you have a wood-attributed container? You shouldn’t use any common ones for the pill or it will lose its medicinal potency. Also, the pill will require half a year of seclusion to properly consume, or its effects will be less than expected.”

“Of course I do. And naturally, I wouldn’t immediately take something this precious.” Bai Yaoyi sweetly smiled and with a flip of her hand, she summoned a yellow wooden case.

The old man nodded and silently flicked the bottom of the gourd. Then red mist whirled out from it and released a ball of white light in Bai Yaoyi’s direction.

She caught it with her free hand and quickly placed it within the box.

After she closely examined the pill and clearly sensed its astonishing spiritual power, she put it away with unconcealed joy. Then, she repeatedly thanked him.

Old Man Fu smiled and he slapped the storage pouch at his waist to produce a green wooden box.

He then exacted a pill from the gourd in a similar fashion and put it away. Then after letting out a few dry laughs, he raised his hand and tossed the gourd in Han Li’s direction.

He caught the gourd unconsciously, but his face betrayed surprise. He frowned and slowly asked, “What is the meaning of this, Fellow Daoist? I only asked for two Nascent Cultivating Pills!”

With a stern face, the old man said, “I am not an excessively greedy man. It is only by luck and your strength that I was able to both escape death and create these pills. Now that my Junior Martial Sister has perished, I only have need for one. If Brother Han finds it acceptable, he may take the last three.”

Han Li looked at the gourd in his hand and turned his eyes to the old man. He couldn't help but smile.

He could vaguely guess what the old man intended. It seemed the Nine Serenities Sect Elder believed that his value had greatly reduced now that the pills were finished and that Han Li would suddenly turn hostile. As such, he had surrendered an additional pill.

On one hand, he was clearly showing his goodwill, and on the other, he was giving Han Li less reason to kill him. So long as he wasn’t a ruthless sort, he most likely wouldn’t harbor any further malicious intent.

Since Han Li was being presented with such a valuable gift, he could hardly refuse. And if he did, he would likely cause a misunderstanding.

“In that case, I will graciously accept your offer.” Without further hesitation, light flashed from his hand and the gourd disappeared.

The old man chuckled and relaxed, “There is no need to be so modest, Brother Han. It is something well deserved.”

Of course, Bai Yaoyi came to understand what was happening and she smiled in silence.

With this, the tension eased in the group.

“Since the pills are finished, we should look for a way out. Let’s look toward the base of the mountain. Perhaps we’ll find something there,” Old Man Fu proposed.

Once spoken, the entire cave faintly shook, followed by the sounds of a muffled rumbling. It sounded out from all around them and without end.

The three looked at each other with dismay.

Bai Yaoyi bit her lip and spoke with an astonished tone, “There are others on this mountain?”

“Maybe, but it might be the doing of the Silver-winged Nightfiend as well!” The old man shook his head and a trace of resentment appeared. He had been reminded of his Junior Martial Sister’s death.

After a moment of silence, Han Li indifferently said, “Regardless, let’s be careful on the way out. With our combined might, we shouldn’t have anything to fear.”

Then with a wave of his sleeve, azure mist spread out.

The radiant haze swept across the cave, dissolving all the restrictions and sweeping them up in one swoop. In the blink of an eye, the flags and plates returned to Han Li’s sleeve and disappeared.

“Let’s go! We’ll speak further after we leave!”

With light shining all around his body, he flew towards the exit in an azure streak.

Old Man Fu and Bai Yaoyi exchanged a glance before hurriedly following after, not daring to delay in the slightest.

Translator's Thoughts

ED:akiwimain

Chapter 1000: Phantasmic Air

Though initially panicked, Xiang Zhili immediately remembered something and regained his calm, “Impossible! With the suppression of the two Divine Spirit Treasures, nobody could break free from the Nine-truths Devil Suppression Formation. If Senior had escaped, you would’ve already left the mountain through the opening in the seal. You must’ve had forcibly freed a thread of your spiritual sense to scare me away.”

“You know of the Nine-truths Devil Suppression Formation and the Divine Spirit Treasures? Could it be you are a descendant of the Three Masters of Kunwu Mountain?” Although the woman’s voice was still pleasant to the ear, it now held a cold tone.

“In truth I am not, but there are a few people in this world that also know of this matter. I just happen to be one of them.” As Xiang Zhili spoke, he scrutinized his surroundings with great care.

The woman’s voice snorted, “You won’t find anything. My true body has still yet to be freed, and I won’t let you ruin my chances. How about you obediently stay here for a few months?” With that said, the air above the stone pavilion began to warp and a white vortex appeared, covering the small old man in rainbow light.

“Phantasmic Air!” Xiang Zhili’s expression greatly changed, and silver light shined from his body as he flew out in a streak.

However, the rainbow vortex revolved around him and a huge attractive force firmly held him in place.

Soon, it swept him away and he had completely disappeared as if he was never there to begin with.

“It seems I’ll have to sleep for a moment more. I hope those cultivators will hurry so I can be truly free when I awaken. Those Three Masters of Kunwu will know the cost of sealing me! When the day comes... hehe ...” The woman muttered with a weak voice before letting out a wild fit of sweet laughter.

Seven days later, the Ye Clan cultivators managed to break through the Myriad Cultivator Gate, but they fell into a profound illusion formation. As for Han Li’s party, they were blocked by some strange restriction and were forced to deliberate on a method to destroy it. The outside of the seal, however, was brimming with activity.

Around a thousand cultivators had gathered, covering an area of tens of kilometers. There were even a dozen Nascent Soul eccentrics present.

The most eye-catching of them all were the four Sacred Poison Sect Elders. All of the other Nascent Soul cultivators were lone actors, having been drawn here by rumors.

A blue-robed disciple with a red head scarf was making a report to the elders of the Sacred Poison Sect.

The disciple respectfully said, “Grand Elder, we’ve already examined most of the seal and have a general understanding of it. In an area a dozen kilometers underground, we have detected something hidden beneath an illusion formation. Our disciples skilled in these matters are attempting to dispel it with due haste. Although it was a rapidly placed formation, the creator was extremely skilled so it will take some time.”

The middle-aged man with green marks on his face let out a long sigh, “At least it is good that we have an outline of the situation. Since we’ve already been here for a few days, it would’ve been troublesome if we couldn't find the opening. However, you have best be on guard. Don’t let others discover your actions. Head back and return to us when the formation is dissolved.”

“Yes, Grand Elder!” The disciple shouted with a bow. Then, he took out an earth movement talisman and sank into the ground.

One of the other Sacred Poison Sect Elders said, “Senior Martial Brother Hua, there are no late-Nascent Soul cultivators in Nanjiang. Even if the other sects were to rush here, we have nothing to fear from them.”

Grand Elder Hua gloomily replied, “That may be currently true, but every day we wait, the more high-grade cultivators arrive. There are many sects here that rival our power and if they all hurry to arrive, there will certainly be trouble. Besides, the ten great sects of the Righteous and Devilish Dao will involve themselves in time.”

When the other elders heard this, they either appeared worried or believed the problem to be overstated.

However, Elder Hua let out a yelp as he turned his attention to the sky.

The others soon mimicked him.

A grey cloud loomed over the horizon and was heading in their direction with frightening speed.

When the four elders of the Sacred Poison Sect sensed that fearsome spiritual pressure, their faces all dropped.

In the blink of an eye, it arrived over the small lake before disappearing in a violent rupture. From the ashes, five white silhouettes appeared, each of them unmoving and indistinct.

“The Unbroken Cinque Devils!” Elder Hua’s expression froze.

“The incarnations of the Yin Sifting Sect’s Old Devil Qian?” One of the other sect elders shouted out with a pale complexion.

Elder Hua let out a snort and softly said, “Apart from that old devil, who else cultivates such a devilish art. His true body can possess any of the five incarnations. Apart from killing all five, he is practically immortal.”

“I was wondering who had such understanding of my techniques. So it was the Sacred Poison Sect’s Fellow Daoist Hua. I didn’t expect that your sect would act with such vigor in coming here. Could it be that you know something about what is sealed?” A mysterious voice slowly sounded out from the sky. It was erratic as if each word came from different locations.

Cultivator Hua deeply sighed and forced a laugh. “Brother Qian must be joking. How could we know of such a thing? It is only that our sect was closer so I went ahead to take a look. Nevertheless, may I ask why the esteemed grand elder of the Yin Sifting Sect is here?”

Grand Elder Qian let out a mysterious laugh and said, “Oh, I recall that the closest sect to the location was the Immortal Form Sect! Did yours move? As for me, I was in Nanjiang on business and only happened to come across all of this.”

Elder Hua dryly laughed and asked, “It can’t be easy for someone as famous as Brother Qian to leave his sect. May I ask what stirred you into personally taking action?”

“Just dealing with a few traitors that had fled here, nothing important. I was simply handling the matter quietly.”

“Is that so? It seems I was being too suspicious.”

After that, the two spoke no further. For a time, the air became stagnant.

“I found it! There is an opening to the north. We can enter through there. The Sacred Poison Sect is breaking the entrance as we speak!”

A figure emerged from the side of the lake and shouted as it flew into the distance.

The voice startled all of the nearby cultivators.

Almost immediately, several blue-robed disciples were chasing after the cultivator with alarmed fury. However, he used an exceptional movement technique and was able to escape at great speed.

The Sacred Poison Sect Elder’s expressions all became wretched.

Old Devil Qian bellowed with laughter, “So it was like that! I do hold some understanding of spell formations, and can provide you with some assistance. I’ll be heading down first.” Soon after, his cinque devils flew downward below the lake and disappeared without a trace.

“Let’s go, Old Devil Qian is ruthless. We can’t allow him to harm our disciples.”

With an ashen complexion, Cultivator Hua flipped his hand and summoned a small yellow flag.

With a tremble of his wrist, a yellow cloud covered the nearby Sacred Poison Sect members and brought them all underground in an instant.

Others in the area also began to move and burrow underground as well. In the blink of an eye, nearly half of the them all followed. As for those who remained, they were low-grade disciples that neither possessed earth movement techniques or earth movement treasures.

Over ten kilometers north and three kilometers deep, there was a huge pitch-black area with balls of brilliant light flashing about. Below them was a barrier of unfathomably thick white light. Not only that, but layers of astonishing lightning surrounded it. If anybody were to approach, they would be immediately struck down without the slightest warning.

Those that were lucky could dodge it, but otherwise, they would have their protections flicker out of control, forcing them to stay away for a time.

But what these cultivators were paying attention to was an area in the barrier where lightning wasn’t present, guarded by eight Sacred Poison disciples. They all wore solemn expressions and were standing in confrontation against the others, preventing them from approaching.

Those that were blocked were shouting a torrent of insults, but none dared to take action.

After all, the Sacred Poison Sect possessed a grand reputation in Nanjiang. As most of these cultivators were native to the region, they didn’t dare to rashly stir up trouble.

Of course, there were also those that had no fear of their reputation, and such an example had appeared in a streak of crimson.

“Get lost! I am going to enter.” The person who said this was an old man who spoke with an arrogant tone.

When they saw that a Nascent Soul cultivator had appeared, one of the disciples helplessly said, “Senior, our sect found this first. Our Martial Uncles are nearby, Senior should-”

The old man coldly laughed and said, “Even if Hua Tianqi was here, I would still enter.” He then raised his hand and a blinding red light lit up from his palm.

Translator's Thoughts

Happy 1000~ Couldn't have done it without your support. I'll make an official announcement soon.

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1001: Master Scatterwind

“Is that so? I don’t know what my disciples did to offend you, Brother Zheng Wei, but could you defer their punishment to me?” Before any further action could take place, an indifferent voice sounded out, followed by various-colored streaks of light heading in their direction. In the blink of an eye, the Sacred Poison Sect Elders appeared before them.

The one who spoke faced against the silhouette in the red light.

Much to the surprise of those present, the overbearing cultivator from before chuckled upon seeing their arrival and said, “So Brother Hua actually was here. It seems I’ve been lacking in manners. It was merely a jest towards your sect disciples, how could I truly bully them?” His attitude had changed dramatically.

Wild laughter came from the side, and five white silhouettes suddenly appeared in a brilliant flash. “So it was Fellow Daoist Zheng Wei, the illustrious Master Scatterwind. Now that I see you in person, your reputation is well deserved!”

“The Unbroken Cinque Devils, so it was the Yin Sifting Sect’s Brother Qian!” The cultivator coated in red light spoke out in great alarm.

“You flatter me, Brother Zheng. Your reputation is no lesser than my own!” Old Devil Qian spoke with a cackle.

Those words were true, Master Scatterwind was a famous figure in the Great Jin.

However, his fame wasn’t the result of anything good. He was known as a moralless deceiver as treacherous as they came. When faced with weaker opponents, he would act like an unsensible fiend and take advantage of them.

Such a character naturally offended many. Even a few Nascent Soul cultivators bore resentment towards him. Unfortunately, he was an early-Nascent Soul vagrant cultivator who used an easy cultivation technique to ascend to his current realm. But in the past, he happened upon an ancient grand treasure, the World Flying Boots. When fully used, he can escape even late-Nascent Soul cultivators.

In addition, he later cultivated many strange secret techniques focused on survival and avoided offending any cultivators at mid and late-Nascent Soul stage. As a result, he was able to travel freely despite being one of the most notorious figures in the Great Jin.

The Sacred Poison Sect’s Grand Elder Hua Tianqi had nothing good to say about him, but Old Devil Qian seemed quite interested.

In the face of the Yin Sifting Sect’s Grand Elder, Master Scatterwind smiled and began to slowly retreat like a mouse when faced against a cat.

When Old Devil Qian saw Scatterwind’s meek attitude, he lost interest and instead spoke again to Hua Tianqi with an oddly cheerful tone, “Brother Hua, could it be your sect is guarding this place to bar outsiders from entering?”

Hua Tianqi paused before replying with a flickering gaze, “Brother Qian must be joking. Our Sacred Poison Sect wouldn’t dare to block you, or any other sect for that matter. I merely wished to dissolve the formation covering this area to allow everyone else to head inside. This was to avoid having any Fellow Daoists fall prey to this malicious formation.

Old Devil Qian coldly chuckled and said, “Oh, I do apologize. It seems I’ve misunderstood your sect’s good intentions. However, this mere illusion formation is nothing against me. Do you mind if I head in right away?” As he spoke, his cinque devils slowly moved closer.

Hua Tianqi quickly replied, “It will be no problem. If Brother Qian can make it through, I will not block you.” He waved his hand and indicated for his sect disciples to clear a path.

Although the other sect members felt puzzled by this, they trusted him and said nothing in opposition. As a result, the Core Formation disciples obediently stood to the side.

“Then I will go on ahead.” Old Devil Qian let out a cacophonic and roaring guffaw before his cinque devils shot into the white light barrier. In the blink of an eye, blue light shined out and the colorless silhouettes disappeared into the void.

When the barrier calmed once more, Hua Tianqi turned to the surrounding cultivators as the green marks twisted on his face and he slowly said, “If there is anyone else who wishes to follow, I will not stop them.”

His actions had caused the aggressive group to look at each other in dismay. Even the devious Master Scatterwind now hid amongst the crowd and didn’t dare to accept their offer.

They felt resentment towards the Sacred Poison Sect for monopolizing the opening, but now that there was a late-Nascent Soul cultivator already inside, they hesitated.

Regardless of how quickly the illusion formation can be broken, if they entered and Old Devil Qian was to strike at them, they wouldn’t be able to protect themselves in the slightest.

When Hua Tianqi saw that no one had accepted, he sneered and no longer paid them any attention. He then turned around to his disciples and commanded, “You will no longer be guarding this location, so go ahead and return to the surface. The other elders and I will be heading in first.”

“Yes, Grand Elder!” The eight Sacred Poison Sect Core Formation disciples bowed and tunneled back up.

With a shout, the four Sacred Poison Sect cultivators then entered the illusion formation and disappeared without a trace.

Afterwards, an uproar broke out.

A majority of them didn’t belong to a group. At most, they came in groups of two or three Core Formation cultivators, but none were in nearly great enough force to head in.

As for the lone Nascent Soul cultivators, they all revealed a pensive expression as well.

Now that the entrance was unobstructed, the situation had become awkward.

Master Scatterwind discovered a bulky man in the crowd and said, “Fellow Daoist, how about we head in together.”

“Together? Please excuse my refusal. However, it is a joy to meet you, given your grand reputation!” The large Nascent Soul cultivator rolled his eyes and spoke with a sarcastic tone.

Master Scatterwind didn’t take his refusal to heart and pleasantly said, “Fellow Daoist doesn’t need to be so distant. In addition to us two, there should be three other vagrant Nascent Soul cultivators gathered here. How about we head in together? That way, we won’t have much to fear from the others already inside.”

The large man felt tempted, but Scatterwind’s reputation was far too damaging. He snorted and said, “How about you gather the others first before asking me again?”

“That’s fine, they will be sure to agree,” he slapped his chest in a pledge and flew over to an old man glowing in purple light, much to the bewilderment of the large man.

Before the old man could react, Scatterwind wore a beaming smile, “Fellow Daoist, would you like to head in together? I’ve already come to terms with the other Fellow Daoist to find three more people. Are you willing to join us?”

The old man frowned and coldly glanced at him before turning to look at the large man with a curious gaze.

When their eyes met, he suddenly realized something and he faintly smiled.

Not long after, the five unacquainted vagrants entered the illusion formation together and disappeared from sight.

...

Han Li was currently looking around him with blue light shining from his eyes.

He now found himself trapped in an illusory space where he was surrounded by various colored clouds. Besides these, nothing else existed here.

“This wicked place is far too strange. I can’t fly out, nor can I discover any restrictions. It doesn't seem to be an illusory formation. Could it be that I am truly trapped here?” Han Li muttered with a sour face.

Several days prior, his party discovered a boulder on the side of the stairs with a rare medicinal herb growing on it. Old Man Fu eager went out to pick it, but had stirred up a restriction of some kind. As a result, Han Li saw his surroundings light up before he appeared in this place alone.

The other two were nowhere to be seen.

Although he wasn’t on the same level as a spell formation grandmaster, he had done quite a bit of research on strange ancient formations and wasn’t very fearful at the start.

But it didn’t take long for him to have a change of mind.

He wasn’t even sure if this was an illusion. He only knew that no matter how far he flew, everything remained entirely the same. He had also made extensive use of his Brightsight Spirit Eyes, to no avail.

As for attacks from his treasures, he had used them all, but the strikes traveled incredibly far before disappearing. It seemed there was no use in trying even stronger attacks.

After spending so much time floating here, Han Li hadn’t made the slightest progress and eventually decided to stop for the time being.

He closed his eyes and sank into meditation as the many ancient spell formations he studied appeared in his mind, attempting to find a restriction that was similar to this one.

As time slowly passed by, his figure remained motionless. Eventually, he slowly opened his eyes to glare at the bright clouds that surrounded him.

He wore an odd expression and clicked his tongue, muttering, “So it was like that.”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

I guess Han Li will break out his party members too.

Chapter 1002: A Chance Encounter

Han Li slowly stood up and reached out to a nearby red cloud. Suddenly, a large azure hand materialized in the air and grabbed ahold of it.

He stared at the hand and suddenly formed a strange hand gesture before muttering an incantation.

The large hand trembled momentarily before closing a fist around the cloud.

Azure light brightly shined from the hand and it soon took the shape of a ball.

He then spat out a thread of blue Nascent flame and had it wrap around the ball before quickly submerging it in an inferno.

Han Li then ceased casting spell seals and expressionlessly looked at the ball of light in silence.

After an unknown amount of time, the corner of his mouth twitched and he shook his sleeve towards the blaze and swept it away, revealing a faint red pearl.

“So I was right! Such brilliant transformation concealment methods can only be accomplished by ancient cultivators. Even then, there could only be a few cultivators that knew how to do this even during ancient times. It is fortunate that Xin Ruyin [1] mentioned a similar restriction in the jade slip she gave me long ago or I would truly be at a loss. It seems I’ll have to continue reinforcing my spirit eyes in the future. If I continue to use the Brightsight Spirit Water for another hundred years, I should be able to see through even top grade illusion transformations.” Han Li sighed, feeling somewhat gloomy that he wasn’t able to see through it.

He no longer paid any attention to the red pearl floating in the air and looked around him before a blue cloud caught his eye. Then, he reached out for it and began to envelop it in Nascent flames.

This time, the cloud disappeared in the blink of an eye.

Han Li didn’t appear surprised and simply reached out for another one.

After two more failures, he eventually came into possession of a blue pearl.

Half a day later, he acquired a yellow, azure, and gold pearl.

He solemnly raised his hand to these pearls and had them fly high into the air.

He then pulled his hands at them and had them slowly revolve, gradually accelerating them until it formed a ring of rainbow light.

Han Li raised his brow at the sight and softly shouted, “Go!”

He stopped his fingers and the rainbow ring scattered, flying off in various directions at a profound trajectory.

In the blink of an eye, they flew to seemingly unrelated points and revolved in place, pulsing in size as they underwent a strange alteration.

He was forced to narrow his eyes from the blinding eruptions as the balls now were more akin to five blazing suns.

They converged together and the world began to blur around him. Soon, light surged and Han Li found himself back at the stone steps next to the huge boulder.

“Fellow Daoist Han!”

“Brother Han!”

Bai Yaoyi and Old Man Fu shouted out in alarm when they saw him. The two stood ten meters away, and the distress on their faces quickly turned to delight.

“So you two were also trapped?” Han Li asked.

“It must’ve been Brother Han who broke through that bizarre restriction. I’ve never seen such a fearsome spell formation before. I thought that I would be trapped in there until I perished,” Old Man Fu spoke with lingering fear.

It was clear he had suffered much in this time. Both his magic power and spirit had been damaged in his attempts to escape.

With a trace of appreciation on her face, Bai Yaoyi wryly chuckled, “My circumstances were about the same. Many thanks to Brother Han for breaking the restriction.”

Han Li smiled and said, “It was nothing. I have only heard about similar restrictions by chance and was able to dispel it. These types of ancient restrictions are truly rare. If I am correct, that spiritual herb Brother Fu grabbed should’ve been a transformed magic tool. I’m afraid you’ve been tricked.”

“That can’t be. It was clearly a- Yi! What’s this?” Old Man Fu doubtfully took out a jade box and opened it to reveal an ordinary jade scepter.

He was immediately dumbstruck by the sight.

“In truth, we were already in the illusions grasp when we approached the huge stone. Fellow Daoist had only activated the most fearsome of the restrictions upon grabbing the ‘spiritual herb.’ How about we take another look at it?” Han Li then pointed in the direction of the rock.

The other two looked over and saw a plant with purple berries growing on it.

“Those ancient cultivators are truly devious to put such a trap here. What were they thinking?” The old man flusteredly said.

Bai Yaoyi curled her lips in amazement.

“There’s no need to be so amazed,” Han Li indifferently spoke, “This ancient restriction needed to be activated by those who entered it. It is only natural for its appearance to change. However, it was only dissolved and not completely destroyed. We only have a limited amount of time.”

“This mountain is unlike its reputation as the Immortal spirit mountain. It’s more like a dragon’s lair!” Old Man Fu appeared resentful at having been tricked.

Han Li’s eyes flickered and he said with a deep voice, “Let’s be more careful. This place isn’t just an old ruin. I only managed to dispel that restriction out of luck. I’m not certain I’ll be able to next time, so let's avoid stirring up any calamity.”

Old Man Fu let out an embarrassed laugh, “I’ll be sure not to act so rashly in the future.”

Bai Yaoyi pensively nodded.

“Since Fellow Daoists understand, let’s head on our way. The noise ahead has already come to a stop. Over the past few days, they might’ve already arrived at the top.” Han Li looked at the top of the mountain and set off up the stairs.

The other two closely followed suit.

Several hours later, the three flew past several huge cliffs, eventually arriving at the stone pavilion where the Ye Clan had rested previously, and where Xiang Zhili had disappeared.

When they saw the site, Han Li sighed and the three stopped, looking at the pavilion from a distance.

Old Man Fu and Bai Yaoyi both couldn't help but look over, having also noticed something off.

There were shallow footsteps in the loose dirt surrounding the area. If someone wasn’t paying attention, they could’ve easily missed it.

Bai Yaoyi tensed her brow and said, “Others have been here already.”

Old Man Fu muttered to himself for a moment and pointed to an object at the side of the pavilion, “Take a look at that stone as well!”

There was a deep, narrow groove scathed the surface that was ten meters long. One could easily tell it was the mark of an incredibly sharp sword Qi. It had been unintentionally left behind by the Ye Clan’s Seventh Uncle during their battle with the Lion Hawk.

Bai Yaoyi’s eyes lit up, “This mark is new. It seems that something else had attacked them. Could it have been the Silver-winged Nightfiend?”

With exceptional calm, Han Li said, “Perhaps, but in any case, they made their way up. It should save us some trouble.”

When Old Man Fu heard this, he smiled and thought to say something, but was interrupted by a sudden flash of white nearby, followed by the appearance of a colorless screen. A bleached silhouette emerged and could clearly see the three.

Han Li and Bai Yaoyi both rejoiced as they had found the exit they longed for.

However, Old Man Fu lost all the blood in his face when he saw the figure, shouting, “The Unbroken Cinque Devils? Those are Old Devil Qian’s incarnations!”

When Han Li heard this, he was stunned. He felt as though he had heard of them before and of the name Old Devil Qian, but before anything came to mind, he noticed Bai Yaoyi’s face had blanched as well.

With several puffs, five similar white silhouettes emerged.

These indistinct silhouettes appeared abreast in a line. Their statue gazes all focused on Han Li and then his companions.

‘The Grand Elder of the Yin Sifting Sect!’ When Han Li finally recognized the five strange beings, his expression instantly turned unsightly.

“So it was Fellow Daoist Fu, what a coincidence! It is no wonder why I wasn’t able to find you! So it turned out you had entered here first. And from this woman’s strange attire, she should be a cultivator from North Night Palace. I can be considered old friends with your palace’s Madam Liu. As for this last Fellow Daoist, tch tch , could it be Brother Han from the Heavenly South? You’ve had both my sect and the Endless Sky Temple search long and hard for you!” Old Devil Qian’s voice was amazed at first, but then it slowly broke out into wild laughter.

[1]. Xin Ruyin was a female Qi Condensation cultivator that was introduced in Chapter 277: Xin Ruyin. She was a spell formation master who later gave Han Li the accumulation of her knowledge in exchange for the vengeance of her deceased husband.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1008: Master Sable

Deep underground in Nanjiang, there were several hundreds of cultivators gathered around the opening of the seal to Kunwu Mountain.

Because of the illusion formation’s explosion, the ten-meter opening was rendered unstable. Silver light continuously flowed from it as if waves were wandering across everything around it.

There were many vagrants and those from minor sects that were watching what was happening from a distance, but more importantly were several groups that had gathered near the opening in a deadlock.

Among them were a party of women who had youthful and beautiful appearances. Their emerald-green robes and adornments revealed them to be natives to Nanjiang. One of their elders possessed mid-Nascent Soul cultivation with an ordinary appearance, and their other elder possessed early-Nascent Soul cultivation though younger and more beautiful.

The women were facing a group of men that appeared in their thirties. Strangely enough, a portion of them wore black robes and the other white ones.

Leading them were a group of five Nascent Soul cultivators. Ge Tianhao and the Endless Sky Saintess Lin Yinping were among them. But the most notable of all was an elegant youth that stood at the saintess’ side. From his spiritual Qi fluctuations, he was clearly a late-Nascent Soul cultivator. He was the Endless Sky Plains’ Grand Immortal Xu.

As for the last group, they were the smallest, consisting of three azure-robed cultivators, headed by an old white-haired Daoist with an otherworldly bearing. He was a late-Nascent Soul cultivator known as Master Sable.

Master Sable looked at the green-robed mid-Nascent Soul woman with a stern expression and said, “Lady Mu, there is no need for your esteemed sect to join the fray. I don’t hold you in contempt, rather I fear your Immortal Form Sect would be greatly damaged if anything were to happen during this dangerous trip. Due to our past friendship, I am doing my best to dissuade you.”

It was clear from his tone that he was rather affectionate of the woman.

Lady Mu indifferently replied, “Master Sable, even if the High Zenith Sect is the top sect of the Righteous Dao, you can’t be this overbearing. The seal is clearly within the range of my sect’s authority. How can you prevent me from entering? My sect cares not for the danger either.”

The group of women belonged to the largest sect nearest to the seal, the Immortal Form Sect.

Their fame was even greater than that of the Sacred Poison Sects. A majority of its disciples were women. But most of its fame came from the resounding, sinister power of its unblockable curses. It is said that they were capable of killing someone thousands of kilometers away.

There would often be news of the death of someone who offended their sect, no matter how far they fled. This inspired fear in the cultivation world and none dared to rashly offend them.

One of their famous figures was Lady Mu, who was said to have killed three similarly-ranked cultivators in a single day, all at different locations. From actions of the past, she also had a mutual grudge of sorts against Master Sable.

Even so, Master Sable had no choice but to act with the utmost politeness despite being amongst the most powerful figures in the Great Jin.

After this was said, Ge Tianhao then interjected, “Fellow Daoist Sable, I won’t mention the circumstances of others, but our Yin Sifting Sect will be heading in.”

Ge Tianhao accompanied the cultivators from the Endless Sky Plains and had the company of two elders from his own sects. When he found out about the matter of the seal, he had hurried over. Now that he understood that the strength of his own party rivaled that of the High Zenith Sects, he wasn’t about to easily back down.

Master Sable wasn’t angered by their words, and instead turned to look at the silver light emitting from the seal’s opening. He then nonchalantly said, “If Fellow Daoist Ge wishes to head in, I will not block you. In truth, I had acquired secret information that the opening of this seal was man-made. Although I don’t know what’s inside, I can’t imagine it to be good. Besides, even without me blocking the way, the opening has become unstable.”

Lady Mu and Ge Tianhao turned silent. This problem wouldn’t be easily solved.

The violent fluctuations of energy at the opening would make it extremely dangerous to enter.

Lady Mu swept away a strand of hair from her forehand and slowly said, “Our Immortal Form Sect had acquired a Sun Moon Shuttle recently. It can be considered a rare treasure that can be used in both attack and defense. My Junior Martial Sister and I are willing to join hands and make an attempt.”

Master Sable spoke with surprise, “You actually acquired the Sun Moon Shuttle? It’s one of the three great shuttle treasures.”

“It was only something we acquired in passing,” Lady Mu said with indifference, “I was thinking of having it become a legacy treasure of our sect.”

Master Sable nodded and said, “In that case, I won’t say anything further. You are free to do as you wish. As for me, I will wait another two days before entering.”

“Two days? Didn’t you say you weren’t going to enter?” Ge Tianhao asked with a trace of doubt.

Master Sable twirled his beard and said, “I said no such thing. In two days time, the Heavenly Devil Sect’s Brother Sevenwonders will come. With his Spirit Tortoise Carriage, we won’t have trouble entering the seal.”

“Daoist Sevenwonders is on his way?” Ge Tianhao spoke with alarm.

Master Sable leisurely said, “Correct. I’ve received a secret report that this matter involves both the Righteous and Devilish Dao. Fellow Daoist Sevenwonders and I have taken charge and we’ve investigated separate matters near Nanjiang. I’ve managed to find clues and have requested Brother Sevenwonders to give me some assistance. If the report is true, I believe it will be far too dangerous for me to tackle this alone. “

When he heard that Daoist Sevenwonders was coming personally, his expression turned unsightly. After a moment of gloomy silence, his lips stirred as he sent a voice transmission to the Endless Sky Saintess and Grand Immortal Xu.

Grand Immortal Xu’s expression remained unchanged but the Endless Sky Saintess tensely frowned.

When Ge Tianhao saw this, he hastily sent a few more messages and Immortal Xu eventually nodded. As for the Endless Sky Saintess, she hesitated for a moment before deciding to remain silent.

Ge Tianhao’s expression relaxed and he decisively said, “From Fellow Daoist Sable’s tone, there seems to be a significant problem with the seal. However, the grand elder of my sect has already entered, I cannot stand idle. Although I don’t have treasures on the level of the Sun Moon Shuttle and the Spirit Tortoise Carriage, I will have to make an attempt.”

Master Sable glanced at the Grand Immortal Xu for a moment and chuckled with a calm face, “I can understand that you are confident and am I not so classless as to obstruct you. If you have the ability to pass through, then please go ahead.”

It seemed the old Daoist knew the identity of the Endless Sky cultivators in their party.

“In that case, I won’t refuse.” Ge Tianhao chuckled and turned to his side, “Fellow Daoist Xu, I’ll have to trouble you.”

“Since Brother Ge made the request, I’ll give it a try.” Immortal Xu slapped the spirit beast pouch at his waist and light swept out from it to reveal a rainbow peacock. It was a meter tall and had rings of light spread out across its feathers, making for a dazzling sight.

“A Keen Spirit Peacock!” Master Sable narrowed his eyes with a trace of surprise.

“That’s right. Its innate rainbow light is capable of isolating worldly spiritual Qi. We’ll be using that to enter. If you would excuse us, we’ll be heading in first.”

The peacock let out a clear cry and charged into the silver light released from the seal’s opening. Then, the party each released their own protective magic treasures and rushed in without any hesitation.

In the blink of an eye, all that remained behind were the low-grade attainers and disciples.

After witnessing that they all entered without a problem, the rest of their group quickly left, following the orders they were previously given.

A short moment later, all that remained were Master Sable’s group and the Immortal Form Sect.

Lady Mu pondered for a moment and turned around to give a few commands. The female disciples then scattered.

After they departed, Lady Mu turned to her junior martial sister and nodded, “Release the Sun Moon Shuttle!”

“Understood!” The young woman slapped her storage pouch and tossed a dazzling silver shuttle into the air.

During that same time, Lady Mu waved her sleeve and released a golden streak.

Suddenly, the silver and golden streaks flew out and interweaved through the air before fusing as one, turning into a huge three-meter-tall gold-silver shuttle that possessed an astonishing aura.

“Go!” She let out a shout and soon after, the two women streaked forward and disappeared into the huge shuttle.

It then glowed and twirled through the air before shooting into the seal opening.

Master Sable wore an odd expression after seeing them enter and muttered, “Despite what I’ve said, you still insist on entering. Don’t blame me if anything happens to you!”

Soon after, he waved his arm to the two Core Formation cultivators standing behind him, and the three sat down to rest.

With a late-Nascent Soul cultivator guarding the opening, the others in the distance wore an expression of dismay.

...

At the top of Kunwu Mountain in the gloomy air, an incredibly huge object floated motionlessly in the air. There were countless restriction talismans slapped on top of it in addition the dense coils of chains restraining it.

These talismans all glowed with great radiance, revealing themselves to all be vastly powerful. As for the chains, they shined with a black light and faintly seeped traces of blood.

Translator's Thoughts

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1011: A Huge Cauldron

Red mist raged within the spacious hall, and a dozen pillars of flame stood within, each one with a scarlet dragon coiled around them. They all spouted streams of the red mist, completely enveloping a huge cauldron at the center.

The cauldron itself was twenty meters tall and appeared simply decorated. It was among the largest furnaces he had ever seen.

But what astonished Han Li was that the red mist scorched it red, completely erasing all trace of its original color. Even from a hundred meters away, he could feel its volcanic heat.

Ever since he entered the hall, his mouth grew as dry as sand and his skin felt as if it was being assailed by burning needles. If it weren’t for the protective light instantly forming a barrier around him, he would’ve suffered immensely.

However, this left him overjoyed. His gaze swept past the inferno to immediately focus on the cauldron.

It was completely still and let out pangs of thunder. From his tool refinement experience, he could tell it was in the process of refinement.

He now knew he wouldn’t be returning empty-handed.

Taking a shallow breath, Han Li nimbly slid through the streams and easily made his way towards the object.

Twenty meters away, he slowed his steps and slowly skirt around it, sensing its astonishing fire-attributed spiritual power.

Regardless of whatever was inside, it was certain to have gone through some unknown changes given the number of years it spent in refinement. He was quite curious, but didn’t intend on recklessly opening it.

After encircling it a dozen times, he began to pensively glance at other areas of the hall.

Given the innumerable years the pillars and cauldron had been active, there had to be an eternally active spell formation. So long as he located the controlling mechanisms and destroyed it, the flames should come to an end and allow him to take the treasure.

Because the restriction’s purpose was control over the hall, it wasn’t concealed in the slightest.

Paying further attention to the cauldron, he raised his hand, releasing a three-meter-long streak of gold at an unremarkable corner of the hall.

With a loud boom, the corner erupted in golden light and the pillars briefly wavered before their streams came to a halt.

When the light faded away, a three-meter-large hole came into view. A few formation plate fragments surrounded it and a small golden sword was lazily floating above.

Han Li smiled and waved his hand, retrieving the flying sword into his sleeve in a shriek.

Without replenishment from the pillars, the red mist gradually disappeared.

He didn’t immediately take notice of the huge cauldron and instead concentrated his attention on the ground. Blue light flashed from his eyes, and surprise on his face.

With the spell formation no longer in place, he noticed that a mass of red laid a hundred meters below. The entire hall was constructed over an immense pool of earth-fire. It was no wonder why they were able to continue such an operation for so long.

Still using his Brightsight Spirit Eyes, he turned his gaze to the cauldron and decided to first see what was inside.

He was momentarily stunned by it. Whatever was in there was an even harsher red than the pool of earth-fire below. But before he could clearly identify what it was, the cauldron suddenly began to tremble. Followed by a crackle, a layer of scarlet blaze flared around the cauldron once more.

Han Li opened his mouth in astonishment. After a moment of thought, it shifted to one of pleasant surprise.

After passing through untold years of refinement, it absorbed the essence of the earth-fire to a fearsome degree, changing what was originally an ordinary magic tool into a grand fire-attribute treasure.

Repeated exposure to elemental Qi over a long period of time was known to cause such an effect, but it was a matter of coincidence and sheer luck for this to occur.

In the past, a few sects attempted to use this method in an attempt to create some high-grade treasures, but it didn’t take them long to abandon the effort.

This method didn’t simply take up too much time; it would take the continuous effort of many successive generations. Even then, the odds of success would still be pathetically low. Even in the case of success, the boost in strength was negligible compared to the time and resources spent.

As for the cauldron here, he was certain this wasn’t intended by the ones who placed it there. It was most likely that the cauldron was in a crucial point in its refinement process, and the cultivators in charge weren’t able to stop it. Lacking any better choice, they activated the spell formation to allow it to continue operations before evacuating the mountain.

They probably harbored the thought that they would be able to later return. Of course, such an event never came to be.

Han Li’s eyes wandered as he pondered about the circumstances. At the same moment, the spiritual light protecting his body brightly glowed in order to better protect himself against the increased scorching temperatures.

Shortly after, he slapped his storage pouch and summoned a bundle of blue formation flags into his hand.

His figure blurred and the flags shot at various corners.

He then appeared in front of the cauldron and examined it several times before muttering an incantation, creating a barrier of blue light around him and the cauldron.

Within the ice-attribute barrier, the scorching air was greatly cooled.

In addition, he released his spirit beast pouch and summoned his dozen Six-winged Frost Centipedes.

They nimbly circled around and eventually converged together above the cauldron, gesturing threateningly as they accumulated their power.

Han Li relaxed when he saw this and slapped his hands together to cover them in a layer of purple flames before reaching out to the cauldron.

A large purple hand appeared above it and bluntly grabbed its lid.

It trembled and the inferno around it surged several times in height. In the blink of an eye, it condensed into a bird that shot towards the purple hand.

A curious boom sounded out when they made contact and scarlet-purple light flashed together. The bird blocked the hand for the time being.

When he saw this, an odd expression appeared and he gave a soft command.

When the centipedes heard this, they promptly spat out a stream of white Qi, covering the flame bird, the cauldron, and the purple hand all at once.

Meanwhile, he raised his arm to the fist made from his Purple Apex Flames and struck it with a spell seal, causing it to surge twice in size. With the surrounding glacial Qi increasing in strength, the hand was able to crush the flame bird and move on to grab the cauldron.

Masterless, it couldn't offer any further resistance. A soft bang sounded out as its lid was easily struck ten meters into the air, and red light shined from within.

Just as Han Li thought to check, he immediately heard an unpleasant screech, followed by a scarlet light bolting out from inside. It shot to the very top of the hall with immense speed, forcibly passing through two of the centipedes before they could even react.

With a thump, the scarlet light struck the top of the blue light barrier. In a mere moment of pause, it quickly melted away an opening.

He was greatly alarmed and immediately moved to prevent the light from escaping, flicking his fingers and releasing a dozen azure swordstreaks towards it with complete precision.

They all struck true. Each wave caused the scarlet light to dim, eventually causing it to sway on the verge of collapse.

It knew matters had turned for the worse and trembled in a different direction.

But suddenly purple light flashed from behind it and a large hand grabbed it with lightning speed.

Then, it returned to Han Li with what it’s captive.

The cauldron seemed to have lost the power to resist. Not only did thunder stop ringing but the flames had disappeared as well. With the centipede’s glacial Qi, it was turned into a block of crystalline ice.

However, Han Li was more interested in the light that his purple hand managed to catch.

He stared at the item brought before him and astonishedly muttered, “Greatsun Essence Fire!”

However, he also heard a sweet and familiar voice ring out through his mind, “It isn’t Greatsun Essence Fire, but its equally famous counterpart: Great Yin Trueflame. One of the three true spiritual flames of the mortal world!”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1014: Elemental Sanctuary Wall

Hua Tianqi quickly glanced at the Ye Clan Elders trapped in the Yin Qi before turning his eyes to the exit on the other end of the hall. With a resolute tone, he shouted, “Go!”

He flipped his hand, producing a small green flag. In a blur, a ball of emerald light immediately ruptured and swept the four up in its light before rushing them towards the other side of the hall.

“You dare?!” The large-headed eccentric furiously yelled when he saw this and immediately released countless yellow swordstreaks from his body, shredding the Yin Qi surrounding them in an attempt to break free.

After the eccentric’s party managed to escape, white light suddenly shined from the exit to reveal a dense wall of sparkling crystal.

Without another thought, he raised his hand and shot a ten-meter-long swordlight towards the wall. As a result, rainbow flashed and the swordlight was engulfed.

After examining it with shock, he cried out in fury, “An Elemental Sanctuary Wall!”

The old man astonishedly said, “Indeed. Isn’t this a signature treasure of the Buddhist Sanctuary Sect? How could it fall into their hands? Ah yes, it is said they have a relationship of some sort. After all, they are both great powers in the region.”

“The treasure is quite famous.” The Elder Devil frowned.

The eccentric stared at the wall with a pale complexion, “How troublesome. From how recklessly they acted, it appears there truly is a Divine Spirit Treasure at the bottom.”

The Elder Devil coldly laughed, “Brother Ye doesn’t need to be so anxious! It is good that they went down first. The treasure might not even be on the next floor and the monsters that are imprisoned there are sure to be even more deadly. They’re only asking for trouble to rush ahead. Let’s deal with the wall after we put this ghost monarch in order.”

After some thought, the eccentric relaxed and smiled, “Brother Han’s words are reasonable. I was too worried over the treasure!”

With that said, a cold glint flashed from his eye when he turned his attention to the ghost monarch suppressed by the silver pitchfork.

At the other side of the crystal wall, Hua Tianqi let out a long sigh. One of his fellow sect elders immediately grumbled, “Senior Martial Brother Hua, that was far too dangerous. Although the Elemental Sanctuary Wall will stall for some time, I fear we caused a great offense. How will we deal with them in the future?”

Hua Tianqi glanced at his fearful junior martial brother and sullenly said, “You still think that we can peacefully coexist with the Ye Clan? Ye Yuesheng feigned death in the past to escape execution from the ten great sects. Let alone offending them, now that we’ve encountered them, they will not leave us be. And since this treasure was the obsession of our sect founder, it can’t possibly be anything but a legendary Divine Spirit Treasure. What is there to fear with a bit of danger?”

Another sect elder fearfully asked, “If it truly is something as heaven-defying as that, we will have to brave the risk. However, Ye Yuesheng and the others will be guarding the outside. Even if we manage to acquire it, how will we leave?”

Hua Tianqi chuckled, “Did you think I’d take the risk without a plan? Before we came, I brought the Poison Dragon Pearl. I’ll swallow the pearl and have the power to contend a late-Nascent Soul cultivator for a short time. There should be no problem in getting away.”

“So Senior Martial Brother had made preparations. In that case, we have little to worry.” The other three relaxed.

“It is a pity that Junior Martial Brother Yuan isn’t here. Then we wouldn’t need to use the pearl to contend against them.” Having suddenly recalled his Junior Martial Brother, a trace of sadness appeared on his face.

A nearby elder smiled and said, “That is so, but Senior Martial Brother Hua already left a message behind. He might even be on his way as we speak. In that case, things will be much easier when we leave.”

“I hope that is the case,” then with a stiff expression, Hua Tianqi solemnly said, “Everyone, be careful. Given how difficult the ghosts on the seventh floor were, they will be even more fearsome on the eighth and ninth. However, the Devil Suppressing Pagoda is truly deserving of its name. If the Ye Clan hadn’t cleared the way for us, we would’ve spent a great amount of strength.”

The other three called out in acknowledgment.

Afterwards, the party made their way further down. From what they had seen earlier, they should head down to the next floor after walking for a hundred meters.

But this time, they only walked for thirty meters before their surroundings lit up, finding themselves facing a small stone room. The walls were completely bare, but there was two teleportation formations on the ground: a black one and a white one.

“This is...” Hua Tianqi frowned.

The others looked at each other with dismay.

They walked inside. Hua Tianqi held his hands behind his back and gave a cursory glance.

He turned his head to an old man with thick eyebrows and said, “Junior Martial Brother Miao, you’re skilled in ancient spell formations. Take a look and see if they’re short-range teleportation.”

“Understood,” the old man immediately replied. He then walked in front of one of them and began to inspect it. The others curiously followed after.

A moment of silence later, the old man confirmed, “It is truly a short-range teleportation formation, one that won’t exceed fifty kilometers.”

A cold glint flashed in Hua Tianqi’s eye, “Then it should lead us to the eighth floor, though it is quite unordinary to use teleportation for one floor. Do these formations work both ways?”

The old man rubbed his chin and doubtfully said, “Of course. Normal short-range formations are bidirectional. But it is strange for there to be two. Could it be the eighth floor is divided into two?”

“Perhaps, but we’ll have to take it to be sure. Let’s first take the white one. The other one gives me a sense of dread.” Hua Tianqi then walked to the white formation without hesitation.

When the other three looked at the black one, they felt a sense of dread and quickly made their way to the white formation, if only to get away from it.”

After Hua Tianqi struck it with a spell seal, white light flashed, followed by their disappearance.

A moment later, they felt a sense of vertigo and found themselves in a land resembling paradise.

There was a blue sky with white clouds and spiritual plants of all kinds surrounding them. With each breath, they felt a wave of overwhelming spiritual Qi.

But what was most eye-catching, was a small palace regally decorated in gold and jade. It was located at the center of a giant spell formation. There were altars that surrounded it, each enshrined with a giant stone statue carrying a huge golden blade. These statues were crude and carried an indescribably savage aura, and they all faced the palace at the center.

The scene was so bizarre that Hua Tianqi found himself at a loss as of what to say.

...

Han Li was currently standing in the white jade plaza, facing a group of cultivators that were leering at him with unrelenting malice.

‘Perhaps staying at the Spirit Metal Hall would've been the right choice,’ he thought, or if he had delayed himself for a moment, he wouldn’t have had such a warm welcome.

Just as he returned and thought to take another stairway, a group of people emerged from the trees at the side of the plaza. Rather than going up a stairway, they had concealed themselves nearby. Because spiritual sense was restricted in the area, he wasn’t able to detect them and fell into their trap.

A gorgeous white-robed woman was frigidly glaring at Han Li. Through her gritted teeth, she said, “Fellow Daoist Han, I didn’t expect to see you here. You’ve been quite hard to find.”

The person standing at her side was someone he found to be familiar, a white-robed youth. As for her other three companions, they were Ge Tianhao and two black-robed old men.

They surrounded him in a half circle and blocked the way down the mountain, fearing he would escape.

Han Li sighed. He recalled the detection tool he made specifically to avoid her, but now that several years had passed, it had lost its efficacy. It would’ve been an entirely different story if they crossed paths two years ago.

“I also didn’t expect to find the Saintess here. It is truly a fortunate meeting.” With a calm expression, he saluted the Endless Sky Saintess, Lin Yinping, and turned his head to the white-robed youth, “And you must be a Grand Immortal, I’m honored!”

In Han Li’s mind, this person was the greatest threat amongst them: a late-Nascent Soul cultivator. Although he was surrounded, most of his attention was focused on him.

Grand Immortal Xu expressionlessly examined Han Li and spoke with great deliberation, “I am indeed one of the four Grand Immortals of the Soaring Tribe. I’ve only seen you from a distance, and it is a pity you hadn’t the mind to compare pointers with me. Would you be free to do that now?”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1015: A Fan Inspiring Fear

“If that’s the case, I would be honored to spar with Brother Xu. But right now?” Han Li looked at Ge Tianhao and the others and shook his head with a mysterious smile.

Grand Immortal Xu, the white-robed youth, maintained his calm and coldly said, “Oh? From Brother Han’s tone, you seem quite confident. I heard you killed a Yin Sifting Sect Elder at the peak of mid-Nascent Soul stage, is that true?”

When the Yin Sifting Sect Elders heard this, their expressions shifted.

Han Li pursed his lips, “What more is there to be said? I did kill a Yin Sifting Sect Elder in the Heavenly South. Could it be that that Fellow Daoist Xu plans to act on behalf of their sect?”

After staring at him for a while, Immortal Xu said, “Your abilities must’ve been unordinary to kill someone at the peak of your cultivation grade. If it weren’t for the vicious grievances between us, I would’ve wanted to befriend you. I heard you used a bizarre cauldron to seize the doppelganger of our holy beast and our legacy cauldron. So long as you hand over your cauldron to me, I am willing to mend the relationship between you and our temple. Of course, if you also agree to return the Ghost Sifting Banner, I am willing to resolve any grudges there as well. What do you think?”

“What are you doing, Brother Xu? He...”

Just as Lin Yinping[1] was about to say something else, the white-robed youth waved his hand and interrupted her, “The Saintess doesn’t need to meddle in this. This is what I’ve decided!”

Ge Tianhao and his fellow elders glanced at each other in alarm and also kept silent.

When he heard them mention the Heavenvoid Cauldron, Han Li refused without a thought, “ I can’t even consider handing over my cauldron. You can go ahead and attack.”

“Since Fellow Daoist Han rejected my kindness, do not blame me for being merciless.” A trace of resignation appeared on Grand Immortal Xu’s face and he sullenly trembled his sleeve, suddenly producing a green jade scepter into his hand.

With a wave of the scepter, it brightly glowed with green light, and he resolutely glared at him.

Han Li formed a hand gesture in response and thunder suddenly rang out from his back, followed by the emergence of a pair of silver wings. Then with a flick of his wrist, a feather fan appeared in his hand, shining with gold, silver, and red light.

When faced against so many opponents, Han Li couldn't hold back and would have to use his most formidable treasure from the start.

Grand Immortal Xu almost immediately noticed the fan was unordinary. Its fearsome spiritual pressure alone caused his face to sink.

Ge Tianhao also saw that the fan was something grand and hastily said, “Fellow Daoist Xu, let’s attack simultaneously and capture him.”

Afterwards, he waved to his two fellow sect elders before waiting for a reply from Grand Immortal Xu, and the three prepared themselves, releasing their own treasures: two weirdly-shaped flying swords and a bone saber that flickered with flame.

With a change of expression, Lin Yinping waved her sleeve and summoned a cloth with an embroidered silver sash of silk into her hand.

Grand Immortal Xu frowned when he saw this and silently stared at Han Li’s Triflame Fan.

In the blink of an eye, the five were prepared with a joint attack.

However, Han Li wasn’t about to be drawn without his own say. With a ring of thunder, he disappeared in a flash of silver and reappeared at a stairway over thirty meters away.

When they saw this, the Yin Sifting Sect Elders immediately set off as two blue streaks and a green streak, followed by a mass of silver threads that filled the air from Lin Yinping.

However, Grand Immortal Xu was already ahead of them. His robes calmly ruffled as he appeared over thirty meters ahead, no slower than Han Li’s lightning movement. The jade scepter in his hand grew vague and released an unknown beast with a horse’s head and a serpents body in a flash of green.

Han Li sighed and his expression suddenly turned cold as he waved the fan towards them.

A regal cry soared through the sky, and a phoenix appeared from the fan in a burst of gold, silver, and red. It unfolded its wings and fiercely charged forward.

A massive explosion erupted. A bright halo of tri-colored talisman characters appeared, filling the plaza with soft light and a colossally suffocating pressure.

In the face of it, Grand Immortal Xu muttered, “Not good,” before waving his scepter in front of him. The strange creature immediately shot out and circled around him, producing a green barrier.

The two flying swords and the bone saber were too slow and were drawn into the halo. The dense barrage of silver threads Lin Yinping produced from her embroidered cloth immediately dissolved as well upon contact. However, the halo didn’t stop there, pulling back for just a moment before violently expanding in an instant, shattering nearly half the plaza in its brilliant radiance before melting the white jade stone.

Such power and aura could only be described as world-shattering.

Han Li ignored this as he had no further intention of staying. With a flap of his wings, he shot up the stairway in several flashes of silver lightning. Along the way, he took out a small bottle and poured a drop of Myriad Spirit Milk into his mouth.

Although the Triflame Fan’s might was astonishing, he didn’t believe that a single strike could exterminate the lot of them. He reckoned that he would catch them unprepared at most and caused them a bit of suffering. Since he was outnumbered, he planned on evading them for the time being.

Just as it so happened, the closest stairway to Han Li had been the one leading to Kunwu Hall. He did feel somewhat apprehensive by this, but there wasn’t much of a choice. Although Old Devil Qian was ahead of him, so long as he drew support from the mountain’s restrictions and features, he should be able to shake off his pursuers.

He then quickly made his way to the top of the stairway.

...

The huge tri-colored halo only lasted for a moment before completely fading away. The group had all been driven to the edges of the plaza and were worse for wear.

Ge Tianhao, in particular, made for a sorry sight.

Although the bone saber wasn’t his bonded magic treasure, he had spent much effort into refining it and was connected with his spiritual sense. As a result, his soul was wounded when the saber was disintegrated, despite managing to mostly escape the range of the halo’s influence.

But even so, that power still swept across him and immediately scattered his protective light, scorching his arm black.

As for his fellow sect elders, they were somewhat better off. They quickly severed their mental connection to their flying swords when they saw things had turned amiss. As such, they were completely safe from the attack apart from burnt hair and clothes.

Lin Yinping had been standing the farthest away, and her embroidered cloth hadn’t suffered much damage apart from a loss of spiritual Qi. Additionally, a large black shield had appeared in front of her, completely blocking her from view.

As for the Grand Immortal Xu, he had been the closest, but the barrier his green scepter made allowed him to escape the blast unharmed.

However, the youth was wearing an unsightly expression as he looked at the mess he tightly held in his hand.

The treasure was fractured and let out a crisp ring before shattering into sparkling fragments.

The scepter was thoroughly destroyed by the tri-colored halo before it could display its true might.

“Just what was that fan? Could it be a Divine Spirit Treasure?” As Ge Tianhao spoke with furious alarm, he took out a salve for his wounded arm.

As for the two old black-robed men, their complexions were pale with trepidation.

Grand Immortal Xu stared at the distant stairway with a hazy expression and snorted, “I fear you wouldn’t be alive if it was. It should be a replica. With that treasure in his hand, it is no wonder he was so calm when facing us.”

Ge Tianhao astonishedly said, “That was the power of a replica?”

Grand Immortal Xu asked, “What’s so strange? This should be expected.”

A black-robed old man said with wavering eyes, “With such a powerful treasure, he will be far more troublesome than we anticipated. Should we continue our pursuit?” It was clear the fan’s power had shaken him.

Grand Immortal Xu calmly replied, “Fellow Daoist, relax. Given how powerful the fan is, it must consume a significant amount of magic power. That was why he fled. So long as we give chase before his magic power has a chance to recover, he won’t be able to use it again. This is a prime opportunity to kill him.” Then, he slapped a pouch at his waist, releasing the Keen Spirit Peacock in a glow of rainbow light.

He deeply sighed and coldly shouted, “We go up the mountain! If he escapes, there will be no end to the trouble!”

He then led the way up with the rainbow peacock closely flying after him.

[1]. TL Change: From now one, the Endless Sky Saintess will be more often referred by her name Lin Yinping rather than her title.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1019: Goldweight Spirit Wood

“We’ll follow, but keep your distance,” Lady Mu said, “Fortunately, the mountain’s restrictions limit spiritual sense, or we couldn’t shadow a late-Nascent Soul cultivator.” Then, the two flashed with white light and stealthily flew out from the stone pillars and followed after them with a secret technique.

Not long after, a green light flickered from where the woman was hiding a moment ago to reveal a huge green silhouette. It coldly watched the direction the two women left with a pair of icy crystalline eyes, only to strangely warp from sight a moment later.

When Old Devil Qian and the others arrived in front of the mountain gate, Han Li was already halfway through the path to the enormous palace. He managed to stand up and was slowly walking along the small road, but each step drew enormous strain on his body, enough to make him pause.

At that moment, azure and gold clashed as the lightning and light were coiling around his body along with a layer of beautiful purple flame. He even used the Spirit Subjugation Talisman to partially take the form of a flood dragon. When the others saw him, they were astonished.

A black-robed old man couldn't help but ask, “What sorcery is that? How could he undergo such a transformation?”

With a harsh expression, Ge Tianhao said, “Regardless, he seems to be under the effect of a restriction. This is a prime opportunity to dispose of him.” Then, he quickly waved his hand and released a fire-red halberd.

He was very bitter over the loss of his bone saber, utterly destroyed by the attack of the Triflame Fan. Now that an opportunity arose, he wasn’t about to easily let it go.

But when his halberd flew thirty meters away, it violently smashed into the floor and left a deep hole in the ground. It was still and incapable of being moved in the slightest.

“What?!” Shocked, he hastily channeled his magic power and willed the halberd to return, but it remained still.

When Lin Yinping saw this, she shouted, “Greater Suppressive Power?”

The Silver-winged Nightfiend glanced at the trees to either side and indifferently said, “Rather, it’s Goldweight Gravity. The Goldweight Spirit Trees lining the path have created a natural restriction. Anyone that steps into it’s range will have an immense force pull down on their body, rendering them immobile.”

“Then how is that youngster Han moving?” Grand Immortal Xu coldly laughed and took a glance at Han Li’s rear figure.

The Silver-winged Nightfiend glanced at him and scoffed, “Are you ignoring his transformation? In his current form, his cultivation is raised by nearly half. With cultivation at the peak of mid-Nascent Soul stage and the Divine Devilbane Lightning and those purple ice flames, he is displaying great power. If you were to proceed, I suspect you wouldn’t handle the weight nearly as long as him!”

Expressionless, Grand Immortal Xu asked, “Is that so? From your tone, I see that you’re quite familiar with that Youth Han. Do you recognize him?”

“It doesn’t matter, there is no relation between us.” The Silver-winged Nightfiend smiled in response to his probing.

Grand Immortal Xu’s bearing remained indifferent, but the response angered him greatly.

He frowned and said, “Aren’t those Goldweight Spirit Trees? The ancient tree also known as Treasure Fall Trees? They’ve long been extinct in the outside world, and it was said that metal-attribute treasures are completely restrained by them. It is no wonder your halberd had fallen to the ground. Furthermore, the tree has an innate gravitational power that even spiritual sense cannot detect.”

The square-faced cultivator solemnly said, “So it was like that. The trees release a harsh gravitational power that can be superimposed to increase the pressure several-fold. From the sheer number of them and the dense groups, I fear we’ll be under the effects of five simultaneously as we march forward. I don’t know about any of you, but I know my body wouldn’t be able to support such pressure.”

“Hmm, I’m not sure myself, so I’ll be giving it a try.”

When Lin Yinping saw Han Li’s figure slowly treading forward, her expression dropped and she slapped a spirit beast pouch at her waist, releasing a strange lizard.

It was covered in dense scales and had a pair of wings that consisted of thick flesh.

“Go!” Lin Yinping shouted and pointed at Han Li in the distance.

The serpent promptly covered itself in a layer of yellow light before shooting through the mountain gate.

Under everyone’s watchful eyes, the winged lizard flew for forty meters before crashing down right next to the halberd.

However, the lizard was extremely tenacious and through sheer force managed to struggle itself off the ground with its legs. At the same time, it flapped its wings with all its might in an attempt to fly.

When she saw this, a trace of happiness was betrayed from her face.

However, this soon disappeared with a muffled explosion. The serpent had ruptured; its flesh turned into mincemeat.

Lin Yinping’s complexion paled with disbelief. “How is that possible? Is the pressure truly so fierce? What did he do to withstand a pressure that even my lizard couldn't endure?”

“Don’t dwell on it,” Old Devil Qian calmly said, “I am able to sense a faint demonic Qi from his body. He used a secret technique of some sort to temporarily possess the strength of a demon beast. That is what caused his body to become unreasonably durable. However, it is clear that his abilities are quite outstanding as well. Without any magic treasures, he is using three different kinds of power, a feat that I am not capable of.”

With his words, Lin Yinping came to a sudden understanding, “With such techniques, he must have much understanding of heretical Daos!”

“Enough gibberish”, the horned woman impatiently chided, “Keep on speaking and he’ll already be inside Kunwu Hall.” Her voice sounded as harsh and unpleasant as a broken gong.

“Don’t worry,” Grand Immortal Xu calmly said, “The hall’s restrictions aren’t limited to the road. There will certainly be more formidable ones waiting for him. Since we know about the tree’s origins, it shouldn’t be very difficult to break through. So long as we use magic treasures void of metal-attribute materials, we should be able to easily break through.”

“Is it so simple?” The horned woman doubtfully said.

“The Goldweight Pressure is only effective on someone who is caught off guard. It shouldn’t matter to us,” Grand Immortal Xu said. He raised his arm and released a small yellow sword, striking at the nearest tree without reservation.

A huge boom sounded out and faint gold flashed from the trees around them. The flying sword left behind a gash, but it was nowhere close to cutting down the tree.

“ Yi! ” Grand Immortal Xu yelped in surprise.

“It seems that Fellow Daoist Xu has forgotten that the Goldweight Spirit Trees were as hard as metal to begin with, and with countless years of nourishment from Kunwu Mountain’s spiritual Qi, they are beyond what should be expected. I fear that destroying these trees won’t be an easy task and will take us quite a while. Let’s attack them together.” After Old Devil Qian finished, his huge white silhouette opened its mouth and spat out a white crystal orb. As it spun in the air, it smashed against one of the huge trees.

Ge Tianhao and the others exchanged a quick glance before taking out various wood and jade treasures and striking at the trees to either side of them.

For a time, various colored light brilliantly flared, bringing down several trees from either side.

Unbeknownst to them, when the three beasts saw them cutting down the trees, they inwardly rejoiced. Although they spat out their own treasures and joined in, their attacks had minimal effect. However, the great force used managed to cleverly mask this, and the cultivators were none the wiser.

As Han Li strenuously made his way forward, Silvermoon sighed and said, “How foolish! I didn’t expect that these cultivators would chop down the Goldweight Spirit Trees!”

Han Li indifferently replied, “It is no wonder Old Devil Qian is so negligent. After all, they don’t have eyes like mine. I was able to see through the core of each of these trees and noticed the Devilward Talismans inscribed inside. If you hadn’t warned me, I wouldn’t have noticed anything strange. Who would’ve thought that the ancients would’ve carve a talisman inside a tree.”

Silvermoon hesitated for a moment and asked, “In that case, the three demons will be able to make it to the hall without resistance. Shouldn’t we warn them?”

Han Li smiled, “What is there to warn? Apart from the Ye Clan cultivator, the others are just passersby, so it’s good that those three have come to impede them. And if it wouldn’t have taken so much time, I would’ve definitely cut down the trees as well.”

Silvermoon chuckled and said, “Is that so? However, Master had best enter the hall as soon as he can. So long as the treasure is yours, you’ll be able to escape without any harm. Afterwards, we can just hide on the mountain for a few days and wait for the opening to clear.”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1023: An Ambush

Having escaped the range of the Goldweight Spirit Trees, the two demons climbed off the tortoise’s back and she immediately returned to her human form. It appeared that passing through the trees had taken a toll on her as her complexion was now bloodlessly pale.

Then, their bodies blurred and they quickly made their way towards the hall.

Old Devil Qian’s crimson incarnation was one step ahead of them. The three saw the mass of silver threads tear the silhouette to shreds as it passed by, but at the same time, blinding crimson light erupted from its body and continuously mended it.

As this happened, the silhouette vanished behind the Greathnorth Essence Lights.

The three didn’t dare to delay at the sight of this. In a practiced fashion, the Lion Hawk blurred and appeared in front to widely open its mouth to silently release a golden soundwave. As a result, a small gap from the silver threads began to split.

Immediately after, the Silver-winged Nightfiend unfolded his wings and produced an azure wind as well, blowing away the fractured silver threads.

With continuous alternation between the two abilities, a gap had finally opened and the three quickly rushed in before slowly exploring the hall.

Still outside, Lin Yinping’s expression turned unsightly. So rapidly, their party had been reduced to five.

She gritted her teeth and tensely frowned. She turned her head to Grand Immortal Xu and said, “Brother Xu, we...”

As the Grand Immortal continued to chop at a huge tree with a jade sword, he calmly interrupted, “The Saintess need not worry. Our main goal is that Han fellow, not the treasures. With so many people entering, they won’t be easy to contest either. Let us rid ourselves of the remaining trees and guard the gate.”

Ge Tianhao grinned and said, “Ah hah! Brother Xu’s words are reasonable. Even if the others acquire the treasure, they must also leave through here. Although we aren’t able to pass through the Greatnorth Essence Lights, they won’t be able to get past us once they leave.”

Lin Yinping glanced at the deceptively lethal silver strings and nodded after a moment of thought.

The two black-robed old men also found this plan to be reasonable. Although they worried about the lost opportunity for profit, they continued to chop away at the huge trees.

In the blink of an eye, an explosion sounded out and a thirty meter tall tree fell down.

...

Han Li stood in front of Kunwu Hall and breathed out a long sigh. He glanced behind him and saw a dense mass of silver threads.

“Those ancient cultivators are quite cunning to intentionally place an illusion formation inside the Greatnorth Essence Lights. If it weren’t for my Brightsight Spirit Eyes, it would’ve proved quite troublesome,” Han Li muttered.

He turned around and found himself in the rear section of Kunwu Hall. It couldn't be considered large, but there were two rows of a dozen variously-styled wooden chairs that formed an official affairs hall.

At the end of these rows, there was a faintly golden chair between them with a three-meter-tall table standing to its side.

The chair was made from common Goldstring Spirit Wood, but the table was made from a single piece of glistening marble. Its entire body was unordinary and filled with spiritual Qi. At the moment, a green barrier covered it, but he could faintly see a few items laying on it.

These should be the treasures of Kunwu Hall!

Han Li raised his brow and looked around to see that the hall was completely empty and void of anything else eye-catching. He then turned around and looked above him.

Behind the faint golden chair, an unremarkable painting hung on the wall of three men looking at the moon.

A Buddhist, a Daoist, and a Confucian stood inside a bamboo forest and were speaking vigorously about something as they gazed at full moon.

Because the image was only a foot tall and faded from the test of time, Han Li hadn’t taken note of it at first. But now, it caught his eye and he looked at the painting with scrutiny.

A long while later, Han Li lowered his head and mulled over his thoughts.

He wasn’t able to see anything strange from the painting, spiritually or physically. His intuition, however, gave him a distinctly odd feeling. How could such an ordinary item exist in a place like this?

As his expression wavered, Han Li suddenly swayed his hand with resolution. A three-meter-long streak of golden light shot out and rend the painting.

In a flicker, the painting was torn to shreds and the pieces fell to the ground.

‘Could it just be my imagination?’ Han Li puzzlingly thought.

But since he had already started, he wasn’t about to leave matters unfinished.

With a casual wave of his sleeve, several fist-sized fireballs appeared in front of him and he prepared to incinerate the remains of the portrait.

“Master, be careful!” Silvermoon cried out.

In his alarm, his figure blurred into eight exact copies of himself before he even realized what was happening.

Just then, a large stone burst from the ground three meters behind him. Spiritual light shined behind the rubble and several blinding streaks of gold and silver struck at Han Li’s copies from behind. A crisp clang sounded out as one of them was blocked, revealing a gold-silver shuttle.

Han Li tumbled from the strike and blurred twenty meters away. He then turned his head around and wore a face full of furious alarm.

Were it not for the Silver Tailstar Shield he had prepared ahead of time, he would’ve likely been gravely injured.

His normally stoic face now held shock and fear with rage burning in his heart. He suddenly flipped his hand and recovered the shining small silver shield into his hand. He flicked his other arm to summon over thirty small golden swords, cleaving at the mound of rubble in front of him.

Then, a woman’s laugh rang out in a flash of light to reveal a huge gold-silver object. Although so many swordlights moved to attack the object, they all strangely fell to the ground.

When he saw this, his heart trembled and a majority of his fury vanished. He immediately looked over.

The gold-silver object was actually a ten-meter-tall textile shuttle. Its surface shined like a golden mirror. It was the same shape as what had attacked him earlier, but those shuttles were many times smaller.

“Fellow Daoist must be quite vigilant for that strike to fail. Tch tch , could you tell me what techniques you cultivate?” The small shuttles that attacked him earlier appeared at the huge shuttles side. They revolved around it once, before entering inside. The young woman’s voice had come from within the shuttle.

Han Li gloomily recalled his flying swords and thoughts quickly flew in his mind. Spiritual light flashed from his entire body and he shot towards the nearby table in an azure streak.

Since there were others here, he planned to first grab the treasures and handle the rest later. The longer he was tied down, the more people who would be able to make it past the Greatnorth Essence Lights, decreasing his chances of acquiring treasures as well.

But just as he took off, he felt that there was something odd and found the woman’s voice to be unfamiliar. She definitely wasn’t one of the demons or humans he saw up to now. Could it be there were more that entered Kunwu Mountain at an even greater speed than them?

The young woman suddenly shouted out in alarm. Han Li was over sixty meters away and had arrived above the table.

But then, the air above him suddenly warped and an azure scarf appeared above his head before falling onto him.

It was nearly twenty meters wide and appeared right next to him when he least expected it. Even with his vast abilities, he was helpless to act as it covered him. He had become completely trapped!

Azure light shined everywhere he looked and he hastily produced the Silver Tailstar Shield as he cursed in his mind. A layer of white mist then surrounded him.

A woman strangely appeared on the surface of the azure scarf, the Immortal Form Sect’s Lady Mu.

Having witnessed the power of Han Li’s Triflame Fan, she naturally knew that the scarf wouldn’t be able to hold him down for long. But with the success of her attack, she didn’t dare to delay and shot towards the table.

She raised her hand and produced a silver command medallion. Then in a flash, it struck the green light barrier covering the table with a mist of silver light.

Under the shine of the silver light, the seemingly formidable barrier melted away and revealed the true appearance of the treasures that lay there: four crimson wooden tiles, a small purple sword, a palm-sized monk staff, and a scroll brimming with red light, and a dark green block seal with the imprint of a life-like five-clawed dragon.

Lady Mu rejoiced when she saw these items and her gaze dropped onto the dark green seal. After a moment’s pause, she waved her sleeve, intending to take all of the items at once.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1025: The Might of the Yang Ring

Just as an overwhelming sight bloomed in front of Han Li, the vajra barrier within his body suddenly began to pulse in size.

In his alarm, he hastily concentrated his magic power to the barrier and suppressed it. He then took a deep glance at the lotuses in the distance before beating his wings and disappearing from sight.

In the next moment, he reappeared at the edge of the Greatnorth Essence Light and flew in as an azure streak.

In his eyes, stealthily running away was the wiser action with the sudden appearance of this immensely powerful jade ruler, whose might was no lesser than the Triflame Fan, even if its abilities were inclined to illusions and restriction. It was most likely a Divine Spirit Treasure replica of some kind and since he already managed to acquire two treasures, why should he put himself at greater risk?

Although he felt vengeful towards the ruler’s master for her initial ambush, now was not the time to settle debts. After all, Old Devil Qian and the Nightfiend wouldn’t prove easy opponents. No matter his confidence in his powers, his life would be at risk if he were attacked by them all at once.

The beautiful woman stowed inside the huge gold-silver shuttle clasped her hands in an incantation gesture and controlled the white jade ruler with a strained expression. Although she saw that Han Li had withdrawn, she was too busy to pay him any heed. After all, he hadn’t taken away the vital Dragon Call Crest.

Lady Mu saw her junior martial sister trap Old Devil Qian and the others in the huge rainbow lotus. After hatefully glancing in the direction Han Li had escaped, she entered the illusion.

Due to her junior’s control, she was free from any influence of its power, and easily grabbed ahold of the Dragon Call Crest.

But when she reached out for the small purple sword next to it, the Buddhist light flashed and a portion of the lotus above her began to collapse. Old Devil Qian and the two demons were able to escape the restriction and reappeared to glare at Lady Mu with an ominous gaze.

The magic power of her junior martial sister had been exhausted and the Four Skies Ruler lost effect.

The woman paled.

...

Not long after Han Li charged back through the Greatnorth Essence Light, he ran into the horned woman - the human form of the Vast Cliff Tortoise.

She was clad in a strange green armor that seemed to completely repel the silver strings. But strangely enough, the horned woman walked slowly as if she were incapable of any movement techniques.

It was no wonder the other two had left her behind and arrived in the hall first.

When Han Li appeared before the demon, the horned woman glanced at him and paused in surprise. Then with a wary expression, she held a pitch-black rod in front of her and began to prudently observe him.

Maintaining a calm expression, Han Li promptly flew to the side and walked around her.

There was no grudge between them to the best of his knowledge. And while they were restricted in such a dangerous area, there was no reason for them to take action.

But he had been mistaken. As soon as he swept past her, her expression stirred and she rigidly turned to watch Han Li with terror.

This had greatly alarmed him and he unconsciously came to a stop, bafflingly staring back in turn.

“Hand over the items you took from the hall!” The woman shrieked. Then, she pointed the black rod at Han Li and had it extend ten meters long. It blurred, producing countless copies itself to form a small mountain above him.

The mountain’s sudden appearance caused Han Li’s heart to tremble, and the woman’s crazed expression and words had left him baffled, but he didn’t reveal any fear in the slightest. He simply raised his hand and released a black ring to the rods above him.

When the woman saw this, she rejoiced.

The rod in her hand was something she had refined from the materials around her while she was trapped. Along with continuous tempering for tens of thousands of years, she created a grand treasure. Although the mound of rods appeared unremarkable, each one weighed nearly a ton. She was completely confident this would be enough to crush Han Li.

With that thought, killing intent flashed through her mind and she roused all the might in her body to pour copious amounts of spiritual power into the rods, causing them to swell.

It wasn’t difficult for him to immediately guessed what she was doing. Although he didn’t know why she was trying to kill him, this inspired him to do the same.

He then expressionlessly pointed to the black rods above him.

As soon as the ring touched the mass of rods, it released a hum, causing all the nearby silver strings to hum in chorus. They immediately trembled and densely weaved together around the rods with incredible speed. In the blink of an eye, they had completely disappeared from sight.

“You can control the Greatnorth Essence Lights!” The horned woman shrieked with complete disbelief.

The Heaven-Earth rings were a set of two: one Yin to protect against the essence lights and one Yang to control them.

Han Li snorted in contempt. If they were outside the lights, he would be greatly fearful of a late-Nascent Soul stage demon as he would hardly be capable of killing her. Their current circumstances, however, was a different story.

Since she took the initiative to court death, he decided to spare no effort in fulfilling her wish. Although he couldn't make out what creature she was, her body and soul should prove to be incredibly rare top grade materials.

With that in mind, Han Li tossed aside any intentions of a peaceful resolution and struck the ring above him with a spell seal.

It circled in the air and lit up with a hum. It radiated a mysterious dark light and took control of the silver strings a hundred meter around it. Then with a mere mental command, they immediately lined up together to form a huge silver wave and rippled in the horned woman’s direction.

The woman screamed out in alarm and didn’t dare to further tangle with Han Li. She hastily spat out a ball of black-red blood essence and held her hands in an incantation gesture, commanding it to form a mist around her armor and turning to blood-red.

At that moment, the silver wave collapsed on top of her and completely engulfed her like driftwood before the tide.

Green and red light flared from her armor, followed by the deafening clangs of metal.

Although she had used a secret technique, the armor could barely resist the Greatnorth Essence Light to begin with. Now that there was a great quantity that attacked in full force, her armor was littered with holes in the blink of an eye.

The woman screamed with twisted pain on her face and she pressed her hands on the armor, producing multiple layers of grey light to condense into a stone-like material as an additional layer of defense, and slowing the erosion of her armor from the assault of silver strings.

The stone just as quickly turned to rubble underneath the assault, forcing the woman to use her true essence to continuously replenish it. At a glance, it was only a matter of time before it was completely destroyed.

However, Han Li was fully intent on killing the demon and promptly struck the Yang Ring in his hand with several spell seals. The ring revolved once in the air and pulled in the Greatnorth Essence Light from a distance to form another wave with overwhelming momentum.

Her face turned as pale as the grey light shining around her armor upon seeing the incoming attack; there was no time for her to react. It struck and her armor was completely shattered. It would only take a moment before it collapsed in its entirety.

With complete fright, her eyes frantically darted around her and she shouted, “Stop, Fellow Daoist! Please spare my life! I am willing to recognize you as my master and become your spirit beast!”

The light had penetrated a portion of her armor and mashed her arm to a pulp.

Given the many years she’s lived, how could she be willing to die in a place like this?

“Become my spirit beast?” Han Li’s expression stirred and he temporarily paused his attack. Staring at the woman trapped underneath the silver tide, he calmly said, “Do you believe me to be a child? Soul restraint techniques have no effect on demons of your caliber. How could you possibly become my spirit beast?”

If the woman didn’t quickly reply, he would immediately kill her without any hesitation. He wasn’t about to let her buy time for anything to save her.

Seeing that his killing intent had yet to fade away, she fearfully said, “There is no need for me to explain in detail. You acquired a wooden tile from Kunwu Hall: my Soul Binding Tile. Until I finish cultivating the Great Dao, I will be restricted by it.”

Translator's Thoughts

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1027: An Ambush

Near the rear section of Kunwu Hall, a huge textile shuttle was flashing forward like a dragon made of lightning. A silver ball, a purple mist, and a crimson silhouette were closely chasing after it.

Various-colored light wildly flared as attacks pelted the shuttle, but its surface brightly shined and repelled them all.

The Sun Moon Shuttle was well deserving of its title as one of the three great shuttles of the cultivation world. For the time being, no attack had any effect.

Lady Mu was in the shuttle’s interior and driving it at full speed, attempting to avoid the incoming attacks with all her might. To the side, her beautiful junior martial sister was tightly grasping the Four Skies Ruler, but her face was completely pale and her eyes half-shut.

It appeared that forcefully using the Divine Spirit Treasure replica had taken a toll on her.

“Fellow Daoist Qian, you truly wish to join hands with those demons? The treasure we acquired is for the purpose of resealing the mountain for the safety of our world.” As Lady Mu’s cultivation was far inferior to the three, her magic power was quickly depleted trying to evade them.

Old Devil Qian’s cold voice chuckled from the crimson silhouette, “Cease your rambling. Do you believe me to be a child? Besides, I’m not allied with these demons. I’m merely angered by your attack. A meager sect like yours dares contend against me?If you want to be sensible, obediently hand over the treasures you took — and that Divine Spirit Treasure replica as well.”

When she heard this, she sighed and spoke little else. After all, their sect’s standing was irrelevant in the eyes of the great ten sects.

Under their combined assault, the Sun Moon Shuttle eventually began to dim as it was slowly pushed to a corner of the hall.

Old Devil Qian wore a malicious expression and prepared to deal a fatal blow when he suddenly heard a Buddhist chant sound out from the shuttle. Soon after, white lotuses began to blossom and a ruler shot out.

“Not good!”

Be it the demons or the old devil, they all backed away as quickly as they could. Having already suffered an illusion once before, they wouldn’t dare tangle with its attacks again.

With that single moment of delay, the shuttle immediately disappeared as soon as the white ruler returned inside. Then, it reappeared behind the three and directly shot towards the exit.

The white lotuses silently dispersed, only having been empty illusions.

Old Devil Qian and the demons were enraged, having realized they were duped, and immediately set off in pursuit.

However, they were too late as the shuttle had already charged into the Greatnorth Essence Light. Several of the light's silver strings had shot towards the treasure, but had been repelled by the light on the shuttle’s surface.

As the shuttle continued forward, Lady Mu held her hands in an incantation gesture with a solemn expression.

She was controlling a shining silver medallion in her grasp. It released streams of light that covered the shuttle in a silver barrier. Her junior martial sister was now on the verge of collapse. Her use of the Four Skies Ruler had left her in a ruined state unable to even raise her hands.

Completely occupied, she could only steal glances at her with deep worry written on her face.

The young woman lightly smiled, “Senior Martial Sister doesn’t need to worry. With a few years of rest, I will be fine.”

“I hope that’s the case. It’s too difficult for you to use it so much at your current cultivation,” Lady Mu spoke with a helpless tone.

“It was the only way to take the Dragon Call Crest from those great enemies. But if it weren’t for that cunning Daoist Han, we would’ve been able to simply take the treasures and leave.” The young woman resentfully said.

Lady Mu could only offer a bitter smile in response, but she inwardly shuddered at the thought of the Triflame Fan.

Then, light streaked behind the shuttle as the other three closely pursued them into the light.

Given their poor condition, they would’ve already fallen were it not for the profound Sun Moon Shuttle; Old Devil Qian and the other two knew this as well and relentlessly pursued them as a result.

However, they immediately felt something was amiss after they entered the Greatnorth Essence Light.

With the assistance of the silver medallion, the two women were able to activate the illusion restriction within the Greatnorth Essence Light. Although the formation didn’t pose much of a threat to them, it delayed them enough for the women to escape.

Old Devil Qian was thrown into a fury as a result. As for the demons, they began to take measure of him with unkind eyes.

When Old Devil Qian sensed this, he immediately grew wary and returned their leers, “What, do you plan on attacking me?”

The nightfiend hesitated. In a brief moment, he came to the conclusion that the two wouldn’t be able to easily take him down, and instead replied with a chuckle, “Of course not. We wouldn’t dare to do something so foolish against someone of your abilities.” Afterwards, he called for the Lion Hawk and the two immediately departed.

Since they had their lifesoul tiles on hand, their objective was complete and decided not to needlessly tangle themselves with other matters.

When he saw the two disappear from sight, he coldly laughed and had his crimson silhouette fly off in a different direction.

The red mass passed through the countless silver strings without the slightest obstruction, weaving left and right until he managed to leave the illusion.

Relieved, the old devil was about to make his way out of the area, when he came to a sudden stop and his eyes glistened with deep crimson light.

“Whoever’s there, get lost!”

“As expected of the Grand Elder of the Yin Sifting Sect, Brother Qian’s cultivation is truly profound.” A calm man’s voice echoed from a stone pillar in front of him, and he revealed himself in a blur with a barrier of black light surrounded him.

“Han Li!” Old Devil Qian narrowed his eyes.

The man’s cheek twitched at having seen how easily Han Li blocked the Greatnorth Essence Light. He gloomily said, “You’ve must’ve been here for quite a while. Were you waiting for me?”

“You’ve guessed it — my business is simple. Could Brother Qian give me a copy of the incantation to dissolve the Soul Seal Curse?”

“The Soul Seal Curse?” Old Devil Qian repeated with a trace of surprise. Then after a moment’s thought, he howled with laughter.

“Although I don’t know why you’d want the method to dispel the curse, did you think I’d actually tell you?"

Han Li sighed and muttered, “I knew that was a waste of breath, but I figured I'd give it a try regardless. After all, it would be difficult to remain in the Great Jin for much longer if I were to refine the soul of a grand elder from the ten great sects.”

When Old Devil Qian heard this, he glared daggers at Han Li.

“You want to refine my soul?” Old Devil Qian calmly asked. “Let’s see if you have the skill. Call out for whoever is helping you. A lone mid-Nascent Soul cultivator like you wouldn’t dare to speak so arrogantly.”

“In that case, please come out, Fellow Daoist Gui.”

With that said, a pillar at Old Devil Qian’s side flashed, revealing the horned woman in crimson armor holding a black rod.

“You?” The devil quickly shifted his eyes, “What did that fellow offer you to join hands together? I can raise it.”

Gui Ling snorted and pounded the ground with the rod, “It’ll be enough if you hand over your life to me!” Sullen at having no choice but to serve, she wasn’t about to humor him.

Old Devil Qian was enraged by her words, but his face hadn’t displayed the slightest change. He quickly swept his spiritual sense around him and found nobody else nearby, much to his relief.

If it was just these two, he wouldn’t have a problem escaping.

With that in mind, he said little else as his body flared crimson and he flew off in a streak, showing no intention of retaliation.

Han Li, having already expected this to happen, produced a black ring with a wave of his hands.

Suddenly, the winds began to stir, and the Greatnorth Essence Light a hundred meters around him let out a clear ring and began to amass, forming a dense wall.

The red devil incarnation was admittedly powerful and near invulnerable, but when he saw the Greatnorth Essence Light densely gather together, he suddenly stopped in alarm.

In that moment of delay, Gui Ling waved the black rod and summoned unending copies of it above Old Devil Qian’s head.

But before the rods fell upon him, he suddenly felt his entire body tighten as if there was an invisible force holding him in place.

The old eccentric felt his heart tremble.

At that same moment, Han Li pointed at his Yang ring and had countless silver strings form a net around the old devil.

Greatly alarmed, Old Devil Qian let out a fierce shout.

The crimson silhouette glowed with spiritual light and its abdomen suddenly swelled. With a muffled bang, his body erupted, scattering crimson threads in every direction. The mass of rods and the net of Greatnorth Essence Light had both failed to strike.

The crimson soon gathered in the air thirty meters away and began to weave back its shape.

In the blink of an eye, Old Devil Qian’s crimson incarnation returned to its original form without the slightest damage.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1031: Devouring Backlash

The light appeared ordinary at first, but in a brief flash it had appeared behind Old Devil Qian’s cloud of black Qi.

Under the radiance of a thousand rays of light, Old Devil Qian roared in anguish. The devilish Qi dissolved to reveal the crimson Nascent Soul and the Ghost Sifting Banner beneath.

A short moment later, countless threads of azure mist tightly bound his soul. No matter how much resistance he raised with violent flashes of green light and roaring crimson flames, he wasn’t able to escape them.

Rapidly, Han Li arrived next to Old Devil Qian’s Nascent Soul in a flash of silver. He smiled and raised his hand.

Spatial fluctuations appeared above the both of them, followed by the appearance of the Heavenvoid Cauldron.

After it dropped into his grasp, he looked at the captured Nascent Soul.

Old Devil Qian’s Nascent Soul writhed with terror and his heart dropped when he saw Han Li look at him with hostile intentions, but soon, a vicious resolve was born in his heart and he bit to the tip of his tongue with a grimace.

Han Li’s gaze turned cold.

With two pops, talismans were stuck onto the soul’s body, one gold and one silver, freezing his magic power and dissolving the suicidal attack he was about to launch.

Right after, the yellow-robed middle-aged cultivator appeared behind Old Devil Qian in a flash of light, it was the late-Nascent Soul puppet. It had silently arrived there at an unknown time. Han Li wore a mysterious smile following its appearance.

At the start of the ambush, Han Li had the puppet conceal itself in the direction of the palace gates If the old devil was truly as cunning as he believed, he would flee without a thought. And since the puppet wasn’t alive, its aura was concealed with extreme ease. Apart from seeing it with one’s own eyes, one would be incapable of detecting it.

As a result, Old Devil Qian ended up ambushed by the arrow of Golden Lightning Bamboo while he made his escape, and was forcibly pushed back deeper in the hall.

But because Han Li needed to capture his Nascent Soul alive, he used Divine Devilbane Lightning to scare him away after he destroyed the Blood Devil Pearl using the dagger refined from the Devil Essence Diamond. Then as he fled in a panic, his puppet sneaked behind him and used its witch eyes refined from the Brilliant Glow Gem to entrap him in a bewitchment technique.

Having experienced the fearsome might of its witch eyes for himself, Han Li was confident it would be able to disable the old devil momentarily, no matter how powerful his spiritual sense may be.

And when the eccentric lost consciousness as he expected, he used the opportunity to deploy the Heavenvoid Cauldron to easily restrain him.

Following those thoughts, Han Li turned his attention to the small cauldron in his hand. Because he had only refined the first layer of its Artifact Imprint Technique, he was only capable of commanding it to release a bit of its light. If he truly wished to open the cauldron, it seemed he would have to first reach late-Nascent Soul stage.

“Fellow Daoist Han, what should I do with these devils?”

As Han Li was basking with joy, heavy footsteps sounded out from behind him. Gui Ling released a cloud of black-white Qi from her hand, containing five pure white skeletons that were reduced to a foot-tall.

Having lost the connection to Old Devil Qian’s Nascent Soul, the cinque devil incarnations had dropped dead onto the ground, allowing Gui Ling to restrain them.

“Those five...”

Han Li was about to continue when the five black skulls biting onto the old devil’s Nascent Soul suddenly released their bite and screamed, turning around and returning to the five skeletons nearby.

Not only were their screams incredibly loud, but it also inspired a blood-chilling fear that pierced the mind.

Then, the trapped skeletons suddenly sensed something and their eyes violently flickered with crimson light , filling the air with the stench of blood.

The skeletons all opened their mouths and simultaneously struck a single point in the black-white mist using a deep-green devil flame.

An explosion sounded out. Caught off guard, Gui Ling’s restriction had been destroyed.

The five shot out in streaks of white Qi towards their jet-black skulls, but when Han Li saw this, he coldly snorted and waved his hand at the small cauldron.

The azure mist poured out from it and instantly formed a wall to block the five streaks.

He then commanded a portion of the azure mist to wrap around them, preventing the foot-tall skeletons from reaching the skulls.

The skeletons were then thrown into a crazed frenzy.

Although the threads held them firm, their limbs struggled with all their might. They relentlessly spat emerald flame wisps at the azure strings that bound them.

When Old Devil Qian’s Nascent Soul saw this, a trace of fear plagued his face and he suddenly yelled, “No! You... quickly release them!”

When Han Li swept his gaze over across them, he felt somewhat baffled, but he wasn’t about to listen to him. The result that followed astonished him.

The skulls suddenly let out a sharp hiss and returned back towards Old Devil Qian’s Nascent Soul.

Right after, the skulls didn’t simply gnaw on the Nascent Soul, but their mouths began to bear down with strength, clearly intending on devouring him.

“Devil backlash!” Han Li’s heart jumped when he realized what was happening.

Because Old Devil Qian’s magic power had greatly decreased, he had momentarily lost control and the obedient cinque devils suddenly turned savage towards their master.

However, Han Li had no intention of allowing him to perish. He waved his hand at the small cauldron without another thought.

A series of clear rings rang out from within and countless azure threads shot out from the light covering its surface, firmly binding the skulls and forcibly dragged them away from the Nascent Soul. Even so, the skulls still bit at the air with wild strength born from insanity.

He didn’t pay the skulls any further head and instead focused on the old devil’s Nascent Soul.

Although it had only taken a moment, the soul’s body was reduced to less than half its original size and was on the verge of death. But in his gaze, it made no difference so long as it was still present.

Then with a deep breath, Han Li grabbed the Ghost Sifting Banner at the old devil’s side and quickly examined it before placing it in his storage pouch. Soon after, he swept his gaze to a place in the distance.

The human puppet stirred and flickered from sight before returning to Han Li with a black storage pouch in hand.

It had dropped to the ground when Old Devil Qian’s Blood Devil Pearl was destroyed.

He paid no further attention to the items in the storage pouch and turned his head to Gui Ling, “Fellow Daoist Gui, deal with the cinque devils for the time being. I will be handling this Nascent Soul.”

He didn’t wish for any others to watch while he was in the process of soul extraction.

“Please go ahead. I’ll deal with the cinque devils,” Gui Ling calmly replied. Then she opened her mouth and enveloped the skeletons and skulls in black-and-white mist, taking over Han Li’s restrictions of them.

He nodded and reached out to the azure mist, creating a large azure hand that grabbed the Nascent Soul.

A streak of azure light then flew away and disappeared into the Greatnorth Essence Light nearby.

As for the human puppet, it remained motionless.

When Gui Ling saw him disappear, she began to examine the puppet for a long time. Then, a trace of shock appeared on her face. If she hadn’t personally seen Han Li summon it out from a storage pouch, she would’ve hardly believed that the cultivator before her was actually a puppet.

Time slowly moved by and a quarter hour passed. The Greatnorth Essence Light stirred and parted way for Han Li to emerge. He revealed no emotion and Old Devil Qian’s Nascent Soul was nowhere to be seen.

When he approached Gui Ling, she pointed to the five cinque devils and asked, “How should we deal with them? To the best of my knowledge, there is no other way to vanish them from this world apart from slow refinement from great Yang flames.”

“Refine?” Han Li paused for a moment, “There is no need for that. I have another use for them. I’ll just seal them away for the time being.”

“Then so be it.” Despite her surprise, she readily agreed.

Han Li waved his sleeve, summoning a dense swarm of talismans from within and instantly covered the skeletons and skulls with various colored balls of light.

He then clapped his hands together and flicked a finger, arcing lightning from his hand and weaving it together with golden strings layer upon layer around them.

As light flashed, over ten balls of golden light appeared before them.

With an incantation gesture, Han Li released spell seals at the balls, quickly shrinking them to the size of a fist.

When Han Li looked at them, he frowned when something came to mind. He opened his mouth and spat out a bubble that glowed with Buddhist light.

It was the vajra barrier that he had been nurturing his body with.

He pointed to the item in his hand and a seven-colored radiance swept them all up, absorbing them into the golden orb.

With Divine Devilbane Lightning and the Buddhist treasure suppressing it, no matter how vicious what lay ahead, they shouldn’t have any way of escaping.

He finally felt at ease and placed the vajra barrier into a jade box before carefully putting it away.

“Let’s go! Fellow Daoist Gui should have some hidden locations on this mountain. We’ll hide there for a few days and wait for the opening in the seal to recover once more.

“A hidden location?” With roused spirits, Gui Ling instantly answered, “I did unintentionally discover a place like that, and there shouldn’t be anyone else that knows of it.”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1033: Devil Blade

Devil blades forged from Devil Essence Diamonds possessed a fearsome reputation.

It was said that such blades possessed the vicious ability to kill by absorbing flesh and soul, and in turn, refine them into power. The devil blade’s might would then increase with the body count. Many believed that after a certain amount of time and honed with a continuous stream of kills, it would eventually rival a Divine Spirit Treasure and be possible for the wielder to kill a Deity Transformation-stage cultivator.

Of course, Divine Spirit Treasures and said blades in particular have long been extinct in the mortal world, so there was no such thing as a true comparison. But when the Yin Sifting Sect Elder suddenly mentioned this treasure, Han Li’s expression turned unsightly.

Gui Ling blinked and mused, “The blade can’t have been a Devil Dragon Blade, since his Nascent soul was given the opportunity to escape. It should be a rare Devil Dao treasure of another kind since the saber only bore a strong resemblance to the weapon.”

“That should be the case,” Han Li nodded.

Soon after, he looked in the direction of the Devil Suppressing Pagoda and saw that one of the peaks in the distance was gone.

When he thought of the Heavenvoid Cauldron in his hand, his heart stirred and he muttered, “Kunwu Mountain was known to be the center of human cultivation; it shouldn’t be rare for a Divine Spirit Treasure to be there.”

With Gui Ling’s help and the human-like puppet, he now had a chance at acquiring the treasure. And with the eight high-grade spirit stones he acquired from Old Devil Qian’s storage pouch, he could use his puppet quite freely.

Silvermoon’s voice suddenly spoke in his mind with hesitation, “Master, how about we take a look? For some reason, ever since I left the hall, something has been beckoning me towards there. It seems quite familiar — perhaps there is something that is related to my lost memories.”

“There is something calling for you?” Han Li asked, startled.

“That’s right, I can faintly sense it. If we miss this opportunity, my memories may never be whole,” Silvermoon spoke with an earnest tone.

Han Li silently mused for a long while. Then, he chuckled, “In that case, let’s take a look. I am also quite interested in this Divine Spirit Treasure.”

When Silvermoon heard him, she happily replied, “Many thanks, Master!”

Han Li then turned to the side and slowly said, “Fellow Daoist Gui, since a Divine Spirit Treasure has emerged, it seems hiding away isn’t an option anymore.”

Gui Ling gave a slight bow and answered, “You are my master. I will do what you bid.”

With the appearance of such a rare treasure, no cultivator could turn a blind eye. Gui Ling had already anticipated this and wasn’t surprised by his change of mind.

Then, the Nascent Soul trapped by the large azure hand shouted, “Could you agree to not harm me? I swear that everything I told you is true.”

“I never mentioned sparing you, and you clearly understood that not speaking would only mean having your soul refined. You can only blame yourself for falling into my hands.” With that said, Han Li opened his mouth and released a bolt of golden lightning.

With a miserable scream, the large hand and the Nascent Soul disappeared in a flare of gold, only for a faint green banner to fall to the ground.

Han Li’s eyes lit up and he swept it up with a wave of his sleeve. He quickly glanced over it and found it to be another Ghost Sifting Banner.

After using a soul scouring technique on Old Devil Qian, he came to understand that the banners were no trivial items. If all eighteen were combined, they would have unimaginable power.

Since he was already the nemesis of the Yin Sifting Sect, he planned on taking all of them into his possession.

Even if they were of little value to him, he couldn't allow them to restore their number.

In the past when one had been destroyed or lost, if the sect wasn’t able to recover it, they refined a new one.

However, this was only done a few times in the entire history of their sect. No matter how wealthy they may be, these banners weren't easily created. After refinement, it would take quite some time before they were powerful enough to be used.

Han Li looked in the direction of the pagoda and muttered, “Let’s hurry! We don’t know if there are cultivators already fighting over the treasure.”

He then flew down the steps with Gui Ling closely behind.

There were restrictions to either side of the stairway, preventing them from cutting through.

Along the way, he spotted no further signs of combat and soon, they returned to the main white jade plaza, then making their way up to the Devil Suppressing Pagoda.

Farther down the path, there was an area reduced to a mess littered with rubble and holes.

Han Li turned a blind eye to this and continued on his way. Gui Ling let out a gasp and looked at one of the piles of rubble.

Surprised, he followed her gaze and found something strange.

Below an unremarkable pile of debris, there was a small white object. It was clearly the bones belonging to an arm.

He swept his sleeve and blew away the rubble in an azure wind, revealing a skeleton underneath.

Shock appeared on Han Li’s face. The hair and clothes draped on the skeleton belonged to Old Man Fu. The Dark Violet Pearl was tightly held in his other hand, but it was mostly shattered.

Han Li remained silent and began to look around.

After a long while, he sighed, “To think you put all that effort into refining the Nascent Cultivating Pill only for you to die here! The path of cultivation is truly perilous!”

Although he didn’t consider them to be friends, his sudden death left a rather peculiar feeling in his heart.

“Does Fellow Daoist Han recognize this person?” Gui Ling asked, “His death is quite odd. The flesh had been stripped clean and there are no signs that his Nascent Soul had manifested. And there is only the mark of a single cut from his back. It appears like...”

Han Li let out a long sigh, “This person died from the blade that the Yin Sifting Sect Elder described, right?”

Gui Ling solemnly said, “Indeed, although there are other devilish techniques capable of stripping away flesh, they don’t leave a mark like this. Additionally, the Yin Sifting Sect Elder’s Nascent Soul was able to flee but this person’s simply perished. Could it truly be a Devil Dragon Blade? How could we explain this difference in strength?”

After some thought, Han Li shook his head and said, “I very much doubt that. The Devil Dragon Blade might have the power to increase its strength from consuming the souls and flesh of cultivators, but the process should take quite a bit of time. How could its power grow so rapidly?”

“Yes, that does make sense,” Gui Ling chimed with a sense of understanding.

“More importantly, this ‘Master Scatterwind’ has no fear of consequences. He dared to attack elders of both the Yin Sifting Sect and the Nine Serenities Sect. Furthermore, he hadn’t destroyed their bodies after killing them. Doesn’t he have any fear of the two sects joining together to take revenge?” Han Li took another glance at the skeleton and puzzlement appeared on his face. Given that his storage pouch had disappeared, the Nascent Cultivating Pill should’ve fallen into the hands of that character.

As Gui Ling had just emerged from imprisonment, she had little understanding of the current cultivation world and thus little to add.

Han Li pondered for a moment more and couldn't come up with an answer. Then, he raised his hand and released a fireball, burning the skeleton to ash.

“Let’s be careful. That blade will be stronger after consuming a Nascent Soul cultivator. We'd best not suffer in the same way.” With those indifferent words, he led the way ahead but wore a much gloomier expression.

Gui Ling’s heart trembled upon hearing this, and she grimaced with her unsightly face before following after him with a wry smile.

As they headed up, the two hadn’t encountered anything else of note and eventually arrived at the end of the stairway, or what remained of it.

They found themselves at a cliff that had been cut half in size and the mountain behind it had vanished without a trace.

Han Li peered into the distance and then looked down at the unfathomable depth. He then stroked his chin with a pensive expression.

Although Gui Ling had already been expecting this from what the Yin Sifting Sect Elder had said, she was astonished to see this with her own eyes, “It appears that others have already descended and that the Devil Suppressing Pagoda had truly sunk into the mountain. Who knows what’s going on below.”

“Fellow Daoist Gui, do you know what monsters are being detained in the pagoda?”

After some hesitation, Gui Ling earnestly replied, “I’m not too sure. In the past, I was one of the demon beasts used to guard the mountain. Those cultivators hadn’t mentioned the matter to me. But before I was moved outside the mountain, I sensed a huge devilish Qi that appeared here. Soon after, it disappeared. It should’ve been sealed in the pagoda. It is a pity that my cultivation at the time had been rather shallow. From how powerful the aura was, I could’ve determined the true cultivation of the master of the Qi.”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1034: A Blood Saber

Han Li took a deep look down the cliff and said, “It’s no matter. Regardless of how powerful that being may be, it should’ve been immensely weakened after being suppressed for so many years. Furthermore, there should’ve been many late-Nascent Soul cultivators to deal with it.”

Soon after, he beckoned to Gui Ling and the two slowly floated down.

The darkness was unfathomably deep. After floating down for a quarter hour, they still hadn’t reached the bottom.

Han Li felt both sullen and bewildered.

At this depth, his surroundings had already become shadowed and dark, and his vision was limited.

He raised his head and could only faintly see a white dot shining far away.

Under the present restrictions limiting one’s spiritual sense, a common cultivator would only be able to sense movement within a hundred meters.

But Han Li had the Brightsight Spirit Eyes, allowing him to clearly see a kilometer around him.

As they continued to drop, Gui Ling suddenly shouted, “Fellow Daoist Han, below us!”

Stirred by her words, he looked down.

Specks of light glowed not far below them and they could see the faint outline of a huge building.

His expression stirred and he moved to get a closer look when saw something flash from the corner of his eye. A crimson light was silently sweeping towards him from the darkness.

He was suddenly barraged by a bloody scent assailing his nose which filled him with absolute disgust.

‘Master Scatterwind!’ Han Li’s heart trembled.

The crimson light was as fast as lightning, arriving before him in the blink of an eye. If it weren’t for his continued vigilance, he feared that he would’ve been too slow to act.

He quickly raised his hand and summoned a sparkling small silver disk: the Tailstar Essence Shield.

It violently surged in size and a sheen of white light emerged from it to cover Han Li.

Before an eye could even blink, crimson light cascaded around him, leaving him completely surrounded.

Hiss. A three-meter-long saber suddenly emerged from the light and struck the silver barrier.

The saber appeared peculiar as it was as narrow as two fingers and as thin as paper, not to mention the demonic crimson glow on its surface.

The barrier swayed from the strike before shattering into tiny fragments. The saber moved on to directly strike at the Tailstar Essence Shield.

The shield brilliantly flashed and its surface turned sleek as a mirror. Crimson and silver intertwined, finding them at a deadlock for the time being.

Just as the tension in his heart eased, the blood saber suddenly warped and twisted around the shield with an unbelievable flexibility.

Seeing that the saber had snaked around to strike him, he shot backward and flicked his fingers, releasing azure swordstreaks to repel it.

Clangs of metal sounded out as the saber incisively slid through all of them in a single blow and continued towards Han Li without the slightest obstruction.

Han Li’s face paled and he opened his mouth to spit out an object wrapped in azure light.

A crisp clang rang as the crimson saber was blocked by not the object, but the light that surrounded it. It was the Heavenvoid Cauldron.

“ Yi! ” A surprised yelp came from the distance.

Taking advantage of this opportunity, Han Li summoned his Thunderstorm Wings and blinked over thirty meters away. He then raised his hand and had the Tailstar Essence Shield and the Heavenvoid Cauldron shoot back towards him.

Then, the crimson light surrounding him surged and rushed at him in every direction, filling the air with a disgusting bloody scent.

Han Li coldly snorted and held his hands in an incantation gesture. Thunder sounded out and a barrier of golden lightning emerged from his body, dispersing the crimson that attempted to approach him and held them at bay.

Divine Devilbane Lightning! When the hidden figure saw this, he was surprised and knew that they had encountered a fearsome opponent.

Han Li looked at the figure in the distance and coldly said, “Master Scatterwind? Is that you?”

The person didn’t reply. Instead, the saber let out a hum and absorbed all of the crimson light nearby. Then in a blur, the figure disappeared into the darkness along with the weapon.

“Fellow Daoist, are you alright?”

The ambush had taken place in only a moment, and Gui Ling was caught off guard. She anxiously asked about his well being, fearing that he would rebuke her afterwards.

“Yes. As I expected, it does resemble a Devil Dragon Blade. A common treasure would’ve been split in two by the initial attack, but my shield managed to block it well enough,” Han Li calmly stated. Then with a wave of his arm, the Tailstar Shield returned to his hand.

When he glanced it over, he saw a deep slender cut on the surface. Han Li’s eyes widened in surprise and he frowned.

As he poured great amounts of spiritual power into it, silver light began to wander across its surface and the cut was slowly mended. With a now restored shield, he put it away and absorbed the cauldron back into his body.

“Did Brother Han clearly see the person’s appearance?”

“No, spiritual light masked his body, I wasn’t able to see if he was truly Master Scatterwind. However, his cultivation didn’t seem very high.” With that said, he turned to look at the silhouette of the large building and narrowed his eyes in contemplation.

Although Gui Ling wished to proceed, she didn’t know what he was thinking and simply remained at his side.

Without raising his head, he indifferently said, “Fellow Daoist Gui, I will treat your hesitation to act as a single mistake and ignore it. I hope you will not have any further thoughts of this in the future.” Then, he flew down in an azure streak before she could reply.

Gui Ling felt her heart thump, but was relieved after hearing that he didn’t plan on harming her. But for a time, her expression was conflicted. She did have a few erring thoughts a moment ago, and it seemed that the Han Li had sensed this from the portion of her soul possessing her lifesoul tile.

A long while later, Gui Ling let out a wry laugh and helplessly followed suit.

Han Li arrived above a huge square platform and began to calmly examine his surroundings.

Apart from veiled steps heading downward, there was no other course.

“So this is the Devil Suppressing Pagoda,” he muttered.

Gui Ling landed behind him. Having heard his words, she quickly explained, “You may not know this, but the pagoda is structured quite oddly. They constructed it so that its peak is on the lowest floor. The deeper one heads in, the more fearsome the monsters it imprisons.

“So it was like that!” Han Li nodded and looked around him once more. He acted as if nothing from moments ago had happened at all, causing her to hold him in even more fear.

He tossed a moonlight stone into the air and had it float above him. After calling out to Gui Ling, they began the descent into the pagoda.

The first few floors were exceptionally wide and peaceful as there were no ghosts inside. It seemed the cultivators who arrived first had cleanly wiped them out.

However, there were many signs of battle. There was fighting to prevent others from heading further inside.

When he arrived on the third floor, a scorched corpse lay sprawling at the side of a stone pillar. Han Li examined it for a while before concluding that it didn’t belong to someone he could recognize, likely a Ye Clan cultivator.

However, this one had released his Nascent Soul before his body perished, but it was unknown if it managed to successfully escape.

Oddly, there was nothing of note on the fourth floor, but once he entered the fifth, he found two more corpses. One was a shade of dark green, having perished from some kind of fierce poison. As for the other, it belonged to the large man from the band of vagrant cultivators. His head was lobbed to the side and his body was shredded to pieces. His severed head donned a face of disbelief.

Although Han Li felt his heart tremble at the sight of this, he didn’t slow his stride. After turning the corpses to ash, he solemnly entered the sixth floor.

To his unexpected surprise, he found a living person, a palace-robed woman sealed in a huge chunk of ice — Bai Yaoyi.

Her eyes were shut and she had her hands clasped in a gesture around a crystalline flying sword.

If it weren’t for the faint spiritual fluctuations he sensed from her, he would’ve believed her to be dead from her deathly white complexion.

However, he didn’t immediately free her and instead swept his entire spiritual sense past the floor. When he made sure the area was clear, he softly placed his hand against the block of ice.

Then with a crackle, a layer of purple flames ignited from his palm and quickly ate away at the cold Qi.

In the blink of an eye, the huge chunk shrunk and soon, Bai Yaoyi was released.

As the last of the ice evaporated from her body, her eyelashes fluttered before she opened her eyes.

When she saw that Han Li had appeared in front of her, her tense expression instantly relaxed.

“So it was Brother Han! I had begun to worry.” Bai Yaoyi weakly smiled. It was clear her vitality was greatly weakened.

Han Li frowned and examined the woman’s expression before slowly asking, “If I remember correctly, Fellow Daoist Bai cultivated an ice-attribute technique. Could it be that you sealed yourself in the ice?”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1038: Devil Restricting Ring

Confronted against the two impatient cultivators, Master Sable dryly coughed. As he considered what to say to pacify them, a cold voice chimed from the distance, “What? Do you plan on charging through even with both the Heavenly Devil Sect and High Zenith Sect blocking you?”

Suddenly, Old Man Luo’s expression vastly changed. A black light shot before them from the distant horizon.

It faded to reveal a hook-nosed middle-aged man in black scholar robes.

As soon as he appeared, the old man’s bearing turned completely gloomy.

“Daoist Sevenwonders!” He coldly gasped.

It wasn’t to say that Sevenwonders was superior to Master Sable, but that he was notorious for his extremely cruel acts as the Heavenly Devil Sect’s enforcement elder. As Old Man Luo was only a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator, he was entirely unwilling to upset him.

“Fellow Daoist Sevenwonders must be joking. Since your esteemed sects view this matter with such severity, it seems the passage must truly be dangerous. Waiting a few more days is perfectly acceptable.” The old eccentric chuckled and drew back into the crowd.

The cultivator in green mist silently withdrew as well.

With the appearance of the top sects of both the Righteous and Devilish Dao joining hands, dissonance stirred in the crowd.

As of current, even an idiot would know that whatever being sealed was of grave importance. Why else would the two greatest sects be willing to spare such a strong force?

But under the pressure of two vastly powerful factions, the vagrants and those from smaller sects didn’t dare complain. Even those from the larger sects were unwilling to stir up trouble.

Eight Heavenly Devil Sect cultivators flew in their direction, all at Nascent Soul stage.

As soon as they arrived, they silently took out formation plates and spell flags, quickly erecting a huge restriction in the blink of an eye and creating a dense white mist over the seal’s opening. The High Zenith and the Heavenly Devil Sect cultivators then disappeared into the formation without a trace.

Right after, many of the cultivators that wished to observe them looked at each other in dismay.

Inside the restriction, Master Sable sighed and smiled to Daoist Sevenwonders, “Fortunately, you made haste. I fear I wouldn’t have been able to ward them off much longer. Your reputation should strike them with fear.”

The middle-aged scholar put on an insincere smile and said, “Do you wish to yell my name to those outside?”

Master Sable dryly laughed, “Perish the thought.”

“Alright, let’s get back to the matter at hand,” Sevenwonders frowned and said, “These orders are not something we can simply disobey. On the way, I heard that the Yin Sifting Sect already managed to enter. Did you let them in because Old Devil Qian be among them?”

“Before I came, Old Devil Qian and a few vagrant cultivators had already entered. Later on, some Yin Sifting Sect and a few Endless Sky Temple cultivators entered as well with one of their grand immortals in tow. At the time, I hadn’t known the grave importance of the seal and wasn’t resolved to block them.”

Sevenwonders snorted and gloomily said, “I didn’t expect the Ye Clan to use their Divine Spirit Treasure replica as a diversion, and use the opportunity to come here and seize genuine Divine Spirit Treasures. If it weren’t for the spies we placed in their ranks long ago, we would’ve been entirely in the dark.”

Master Sable sighed, “It is a pity. The Ye Clan had kept a close watch over their plans. Although our informants had known of this some time ago, they didn’t have an opportunity to report it. They were only able to destroy a few of their spell formations before escaping. Had we discovered this information earlier, we would’ve never given them the opportunity in the first place. What’s the worth of a Divine Spirit Treasure if the incarnation of the ancient devil ancestor is released? There will be nothing that can be done if we allow it. Given how long its been since Old Devil Qian had entered, he should’ve already found the site where the devil was sealed.”

“He isn’t a fool. He won’t do something that won’t benefit himself. However, those Endless Sky Cultivators are another story. They aren’t from the Great Jin.”

“Oh? I heard that your sect had a relationship with the Endless Sky Temple. I didn’t expect you’d be wary of them.”

“What relationship? We merely conduct deals in our own interest,” Sevenwonders indifferently replied. “How can a seal placed by the ancients be so easily broken? So long as they hadn’t yet dissolved the Elder Devil’s restrictions, we should be able to stop their rampant actions. And even if the Elder Devil incarnation escapes, it will have been greatly weakened after spending so many years imprisoned. With the five Devil Restriction Bands I’ve brought along, we should be able to subdue it.”

“The Devil Restricting Bands? Those ancient artifact passed down from the Spirit Realm?” Master Sable’s eyes lit up at the mention of it.

Sevenwonders coldly smiled, “That’s right. When the Elder Devils invaded our world, the cultivators from the spirit realm brought along a treasure specifically meant to deal with the high-grade Elder Devils. With the five Devil Suppression Bands, even the incarnation of the Elder Devil Sacred Ancestor will be helpless.”

Master Sable’s expression calmed and he said, “That will be good. I was originally worried that the trip would prove dangerous. I didn’t expect you would be able to find these treasures.”

“Who said that I found them? These bands were given to me from the same person who gave me my orders. The one from the High Zenith Sect didn’t send you a treasure to deal with them?” The scholar shot a doubtful glance at the old man.

“When I left, I was particularly busy and hadn’t the time to prepare anything. However, I did bring the Heavenbound Blade. I should be able to offer some assistance,” Master Sable said with a wry smile.

Sevenwonders nodded, “That treasure will be suitable enough.”

“However, there is something I still don’t understand. Why are we prevented from taking the devil’s life unless it’s absolutely necessary? Why would they want us to seal it again, so it can break out again in the future?”

Sevenwonders pondered for a moment and seriously replied, “Who knows, the ancient cultivators hadn’t killed the devil either. There should be some extraordinary circumstances behind this. Let’s just follow our orders.”

Master Sable pensively nodded and then glanced in the direction of the seal’s opening, “It is as you say! Let’s save ourselves the trouble and not be so meddlesome. Did Brother Sevenwonders come here on the Flying Tortoise Chariot? Let’s hurry inside.”

Sevenwonders chuckled and shook his sleeve, summoning a ball of light. It circled around them before massively expanding in size, turning into a ten-meter-long chariot. It appeared similar to a huge tortoise shell.

Soon after, Master Sable and Sevenwonders gave orders to the cultivators accompanying them, and the two entered the carriage in the blur before shooting into the seal’s opening in a streak of black.

...

The Great Pillar Mountain Range was one of the four grand spirit veins in the Great Jin. It belonged to the Righteous Dao’s number one sect: the High Zenith Sect.

Apart from the Heavenly Devil Sect and the Myriad Demon Valley, no other faction on the continent could compete in terms of power. This resulted in over a hundred various spirit mountains falling under the control of the High Zenith Sect.

Ice Soul Valley was a unremarkably small place among these mountains.

It was entirely lacking in spiritual Qi and bone-chilling Yin winds haunted the location, coating the valley walls in an icy sheet year long.

This place of seemingly little value was actually one of the forbidden areas of the High Zenith Sect that few knew of.

What was particularly mysterious was the illusion formation concealing the valley entrance. Outside from these few restrictions, there were no cultivators standing guard.

In truth, no one had dared to step foot near the place for several hundred years. Even the high ranking elders of the sect didn’t dare to step inside. They merely stood outside and spoke towards the valley with a respectful tone.

Right around when, Daoist Sevenwonders and Master Sable both entered Kunwu Mountain, a grey-robed old man with a sickly appearance appeared outside the valley.

He glanced at the illusion formation at the entrance with ridicule and let out a cough, then flying inside in a streak of green light.

A short moment later, he appeared at the end of the valley and coldly looked at the huge ice wall in front of him with his face sank. He spoke with a soft cold voice, “Old Ghost Bai, I know you’re here. There is no need to hide from visitors in your coffin!”

Soon, his words were repeated with deafening echoes throughout the valley.

The ice walls quaked without end as if they were on the verge of collapse.

The grey-robed old man didn’t seem perturbed by this and narrowed his eyes as he stood in front of the ice wall.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1047: Sword Recovery

The Elder Devil’s attention was so focused on Han Li that the black dagger escaped his notice.

By the time he discovered it, it was too late.

A red line flashed from the Elder Devil’s neck and its last remaining head was cleanly lobbed off.

Han Li rejoiced, but before he could celebrate, the headless Elder Devil raised his two sabers and swung, flinging two black streaks towards him. Soon after, the headless body of the Elder Devil ruptured into dense clouds of devilish Qi.

Han Li felt surprised, but he had no intention of letting his prey escape. He clasped his hands together in an incantation gesture without hesitation and detonated the purple flame flood dragon that he previously released.

Blazing purple embers spread throughout an area of thirty meters like falling rain.

Several dozen small golden swords sliced through the two black streaks and scattered them. The flying swords then dispersed in every direction, shortly sparking golden lightning between them to create a giant net around the purple flame.

A huge crackle sounded out.

The majority of the devilish Qi didn’t make it very far and were frozen solid in a huge chunk of purple ice. The remaining black Qi was caught by the lightning net, evaporating them with huge bolts of lightning.

When Han Li saw this, he clasped his hands and solemnly uttered, “Rupture.”

Countless thin arcs of golden lightning leapt onto the purple ice as the net dissolved, completely rending it to dust and wiping away the soul of the Elder Devil concealed within.

Several treasures fell out from the extinguished devilish Qi as well.

When he glanced at two of the items there, his eyes lit up.

He flicked his finger and two arcs of golden lightning shot out, and immediately scattered the black threads surrounding them.

They were the two Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords Han Li had lost back at Devilfall Valley!

He rejoiced and quickly tested them with a mental command. The two blades leapt into the air before launching back into his hand.

The worry that had been plaguing his mind was now put at ease.

Fortunately, he would only have to shortly temper them before they return back to fighting form despite having remained seal for such a long while.

At that moment, the others blankly stared as Han Li slayed the Elder Devil with clean efficiency. Even its soul didn’t even have the opportunity to escape. The spectators couldn't help but look at each other with fear.

His human-like puppet, however, had left them completely baffled. They had no idea how Han Li called upon such a powerful cultivator. They hadn’t spotted this person ever since they arrived. Could it be his concealment techniques were at a level where he could hide in plain sight from the best of them?

With that thought, their hearts were thrown into further turmoil.

However, they weren’t ordinary people and were able to quickly calm themselves. Rather, they all made a tacit agreement to begin striking at the barrier protecting the teleportation formation.

The grey wall isolated the formation from the world and was produced from several flags surrounding the formation. There was also a restriction that was disabling its use.

Several attacks whistled through the air and crashed down.

Spiritual light flashed and rumbles shook the space. Much against their expectations, the barrier held firm against the assault. Be it the demon’s fierce attacks or Grand Immortal Xu, their strikes had only caused faint ripples.

They naively believed that they would be able to immediately leave following the Elder Devi’s defeat, but now their hearts tensed.

The Lion Hawk in particular was upset by this and wildly flailed its talons to no effect. Then with an ominous glint shining in its eye, it unleashed golden shockwaves from its mouth towards it, leaving a deep depression in the barrier and visibly putting it under great strain.

Grand Immortal Xu’s mind stirred at the sight of this, and he commanded his Keen Spirit Peacock to spread out its wings and rainbow release a gust of rainbow light as well. To the side, Lin Yinping followed suit and repeatedly spat out silver light to strike at the same spot. The Silver-winged Nightfiend condensed countless Ghostfiend Threads into a huge python to add on to the relentless assault.

They all knew that breaking through would be key to escaping so they spared no effort.

In the blink of an eye, an astonishing spiritual light completely enveloped the barrier.

Sounds of cracking had finally begun to ring. By then, Han Li and Gui Ling had arrived in several blurs. The human-like puppet had disappeared from sight along the way.

Han Li appeared entirely calm when he arrived, but his presence inspired fear in the others. And with his timely arrival, the formation flags finally howled and split in two, dissolving the barrier to the teleportation formation. The cultivators immediately made a mad rush inside.

But before anyone actually reached it, several balls of light ruptured and the cultivators fell to the ground.

Following that mutual attack, the others backed away from one another.

Grand Immortal Xu held an azure pearl in his hand and furiously glared at Han Li. “Fellow Daoist Han, what are you doing!?”

“I should be asking you that,” Han Li replied with a mysterious smile. There were several golden swords floating in front of him, and he was holding the fearsome Triflame Fan in his hand.

With his wings wrapped around his body, the nightfiend glared at Han Li and coldly said, “The first one to leave will be me! I don’t trust any of you humans!”

“ Haha, that will be difficult,” Han Li’s smile disappeared and he spoke with an icy tone, “This small formation can only move two people at once. If the formation is destroyed from the other side, where are we to go?”

With that said, the others began to slowly encircle the formation.

The three parties stared each other down in a standoff.

When they finished the circle, an overly sweet voice sounded out from the direction of the palace, “You killed one of my brethren in front of me? Don’t think even think about escaping!”

Despite how far away the voice spoke from, everyone could clearly hear her cold and furious tone.

In the instant her subordinate was slain, Devil Ancestor Yuan Cha sensed it.

By using nearly half of the Black Wind Flag’s power, the woman managed to completely overwhelm the Ninetruths Devil Suppression Formation. Even the Eight Spirit Ruler was completely ineffective against its power. It had summoned the eight spirit beast phantoms to besiege her, but the Black Wind Flag’s supreme power kept them at bay.

The woman originally planned on first dealing with the formation before subduing the ruler, but now that her only subordinate had unexpectedly perished, her ire was raised.

The black-robed woman’s expression turned icy and she spat out several crimson flags into the air. Afterwards, she flicked her fingers and struck them all with spell seals.

Blinding light flared from each of them and they surged in size, growing thirty meters tall in the blink of an eye. These giant flags had purple incantation characters and black Qi roaming across its surface.

With the appearance of the flag, the nearby tornados surged with power and twisted viciously, slowly scraping away at the altars establishing the Ninetruths Formation. The golden blades of light were launching attacks into the winds with fervor but it was clear that the formation was nearing its limits.

When the black-robed woman grew closer to the palace, the Eight Spirit Ruler wasn’t able to exhibit most of its power and could only attack her with its eight beast phantoms. However, the Black Wind Flag blew them astray and their figures grew unsteady.

The cultivators and demons hearts trembled with the sudden and violent surge of wind following the black-robed woman’s threat. The three parties then glared at one another, fearing that they would leave through the teleportation formation first.

With rumbling from the direction of the palace and dark clouds blocking the sky, a dozen black tornados converged together and caused the air itself to tremble. Han Li felt an immense sense of dread from this and immediately said, “Let’s first have Fellow Daoist Gui and Fellow Daoist Lin teleport through. Gui Ling is a demon beast and old friends of the Nightfiend and the Lion Hawk. Fellow Daoist Xu should be more at ease once Fellow Daoist Lin crosses over. For our second group, the Lion Hawk and Fellow Daoist Xu will cross over, then lastly, I will cross over with the Nightfiend. Let’s hurry before we all die!”

Grand Immortal Xu and the others also sensed that something terrible was on the verge of creation. But even so, they had misgivings about the plan, but with no better option they couldn't afford to delay any further. After exchanging a glance with one another, they nodded.

Gui Ling immediately followed Han Li’s commanded and stepped into the formation with Lin Yinping.

But unbeknownst to anyone, just as the two stepped in, it lit up with white light and a silhouette appeared within.

The others were left completely baffled.

At that moment, the black-robed woman’s cold voice sounded out, “Primal chaos, rend the heavens!”

A pillar of pitch-black light erupted from a distance, but soon, it came to a sudden stop midair and split the sky into two. One half was completely clear and shining with sunlight. The other was engulfed in a curtain of black and soon grew to cover the entire sky. In nearly an instant, it spread above Han Li and company.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1048: Falling Out

Before anyone could respond, the black-robed woman coldly laughed. The bright pillar of light disappeared in the distance, and now everything was being immersed in darkness.

This Devil Ancestor Yuan Cha actually used the Black Wind Flag’s spatial abilities to seal them away.

Grand Immortal Xu and the others betrayed shock from their faces.

“Run!”

“ Yi! Where is the person who just arrived?!”

“T-the formation isn’t working! We can’t leave!”

A series of furious voices fired out in succession. Panic had begun to set in.

Han Li felt his heart sank. He also lost sight of the person who just used the teleportation formation. He also hadn’t caught sight of his appearance. However, there were more pressing matters at hand.

He blurred and reappeared in front of the formation.

Lin Yinping and Gui Ling were standing in front and were examining it from every direction with anxious expressions.

“Let me look!” Han Li sullenly shouted. He then raised his hand and struck the edge of the formation with a spell seal. It weakly lit up but had no other reaction.

His expression sank.

At that moment, Grand Immortal Xu and the Silver-winged Nightfiend arrived next to him, but they were unfamiliar with the workings of spell formations. When the nightfiend saw Han Li’s expression, he asked, “Is there something wrong with the formation?”

“There is no problem with the formation; it’s the Black Wind Flag that is blocking us. Unless the seal goes away, neither will we.”

“How exactly can we manage that?! Do you want us to kill that Devil Ancestor Yuan Cha? If we had such abilities, why would we bother to leave!?” The nightfiend shouted.

Han Li glared back at him and bluntly retorted, “Why bother asking? You should keep your complaints to yourself. Fortunately, the devil is currently focused on dealing with the person inside the palace. Now that she’s trapped us, she won’t be paying us any heed for some time. Let us take this time to come up with a new plan. “

Angered, the nightfiend wore a hostile expression on his face, but something soon came to mind and he suppressed his anger with a snort. Then, his eyes wandered as he brooded.

To the side, Grand Immortal Xu was lost in his thoughts as well.

Lin Yinping and Gui Ling both tightly frowned in disappointment at failing to leave.

But just as Han Li and the others found themselves helpless in the face of crisis, outside the formation, the black-robed woman was enveloping herself in a black tornado and looked at the huge flag with a sneer on her face.

Apart from the several tornadoes at her side, the violent winds had gradually begun to still, making the carnage visible.

Although maintaining the spatial seal used up by the Black Wind Flag’s capacity, the Ninetruths Devil Suppression Formation is now completely destroyed and now she only had to deal with the masterless Eight Spirit Ruler. Although it was immensely powerful, it couldn't command many of its own abilities using what intelligence it had.

With that thought, she began to glance around her.

The Eight Spirit Ruler’s spirit beast phantoms were continuously torn away by the tsunami of winds, only for them to reform a moment later. Although they weren’t able of reaching her, she wasn’t willing to leave the protection of the wind.

The black-robed woman expressionlessly turned her gaze back to the person floating above the palace, the large-headed eccentric. Ever since the battle started, he remained completely still.

Although the baleful winds summoned by the Black Wind Flag were formidable, he was completely safe at the center of the palace.

A strange delight glinted from her eyes and she said, “Fellow Daoist Ye, go ahead and take the Eight Spirit Ruler. Don’t worry, I’ll watch over you and prevent Long Meng from attacking you.”

When the eccentric heard this, he wore a hesitant expression.

“What, do you fear that I won’t protect you?” The black-robed woman chuckled and brushed away the hair from her face. Then she raised her arm towards the Ye Clan cultivators in the distance.

Those cultivators were accompanying the grand elder’s doppelganger illusion. When they saw her act, they were greatly frightened.

She simply flicked her finger at them as if she were brushing the air.

The cultivators were baffled, and the large-headed eccentric was as well.

Then, several muffled pops sounded out. A small blossom of crimson blood appeared on the foreheads of the Daoist Nun and the old man at her side, their empty bodies promptly plummeting to the ground. The treasures and light protecting them had no effect.

As for the square-faced middle-aged man, the bone bracelet in front of him brightly flashed with yellow light and blocked the attack of a translucent pearl.

The gem was only the size of a thumb and exploded after being blocked. The mirage of the Ye Clan Grand Elder had it’s forehead struck and the pearl disappeared without a trace.

“ Yi! ”

“Huh?”

“The Shining Moon Band? No, a replica!” The black-robed woman muttered with a trace of surprise.

“Sacred Ancestor, what are you doing?” The eccentric wore a gloomy expression.

“What? Since you don’t trust me, I needed to let you witness my abilities,” she shot a glance at him and casually asked, “Could it be you still have a relationship to those people?”

The eccentric snorted and felt somewhat annoyed, but he didn’t air it. Instead, he looked at the mirage of the Ye Clan Grand Elder with a bewildered expression.

At that same time, the two Ye Clan cultivator’s corpses ruptured forth and two Nascent Soul’s flew out towards the square-faced cultivator in a panic.

With an icy expression on his face, the square-faced man briefly put away the bone bracelet and allowed the two Souls to enter his sleeve before he released it once more.

As this happened, he was staring at the black-robed woman in fear that she would attack him.

Feeling it beneath her dignity to launch another attack and believing that she had already displayed the might of her abilities to the eccentric, she paid no further attention to the square-faced cultivator. Instead, she turned to the eccentric and said, “So long as you help me in taking away the Eight Spirit Ruler, I will consider your task fulfilled. After I manage to escape, I will infuse your body with devilish Qi and extend your lifespan. When I deal with the demon in there, you won’t need to attack... Could it be that you can’t perform this simple task?”

With that said, the black-robed woman’s expression turned icy and her black-and-white eyes bleed a shade crimson.

The eccentric’s quickly expression moved. When he heard that Yuan Cha’s tone became displeased, he knew that he would have to take on this risk. He gritted his teeth and flew in the direction of the Eight Spirit Ruler.

As the eccentric moved forward, a cold snort sounded out from the palace below. Suddenly, the space above him began to distort, and a thirty-meter large fist instantly appeared, smashing down on him like a falling mountain.

The huge first carried a dense spiritual pressure and deeply shocked him. He immediately wanted to retreat, but at that moment, the black-robed woman let out a chuckle and flicked her hand in the direction of the palace.

A huge explosion bloomed out, followed by the fist shooting to the side. It then scattered into specks of white light.

The eccentric felt great relief towards this and flashed forward without any further hesitation, flying towards the Eight Spirit Ruler in a yellow streak.

But when he arrived around thirty meters away, he heard a nearly inaudible sigh. Soon after, a strange light flashed, followed by the appearance of a streak of black-red swordlight sweeping towards him.

“The Black Blood Blade!”

The eccentric shouted out with a breath cold from surprise. He instantly spat out one of his small yellow swords and had it expand to three-meters-long. It circled in the air, forming layers of sword images around itself. Then, the eccentric flipped his hand to produce a small white bottle and pointed its opening towards the blade of light.

A mist of white shot out from the bottle and blurred to block the incoming attacking.

When the two sides collided, the black-red blade faintly stirred before chewing apart the mist. Soon after, the light shined brighter and expanded ten meters long before cleaving down at the eccentric.

The eccentric wore a panicked expression. He clutched his hand in an incantation gesture and willed the huge yellow sword to block it. At that same time, he released a pitchfork from his sleeve and had it fly up in a silver streak.

The black-red blade cleaved down upon the sword illusions, pausing for just a moment. A low hum then sounded as they were torn apart like paper and moved on to the huge yellow sword.

The weapon wailed and its body began to crack from the impact.

The eccentric’s face paled and he spat out a mouthful of black blood on the blade. Fortunately, the flying pitchfork he had released earlier quickly assisted the huge sword in blocking the blade’s downward momentum.

But despite this, the two treasures wouldn’t be able to defend against this blade of light for much longer. The eccentric’s entire body flashed with light as he prepared to shoot away.

When the black-robed woman saw this, her expression sank and she casually flicked her finger in the direction above the palace.

A muffled snort sounded out and a faint white silhouette staggered into view.

It was a white-robed scholar, the Ye Clan Grand Elder who had earlier disappeared.

However, he wore an expressionless face and there was a small hole in his chest. It was positioned right above his heart, and it wasn’t bleeding.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1051: Broken Seal

The white fur grew from Master Scatterwind’s arm and withdrew all in an instant. Afterwards, he continued his discussion with the others as if nothing had happened, mostly everyone ignorant of what had happened.

Meanwhile, none had noticed Han Li sending a thread of spiritual sense into one of his spirit beast pouches. As he calmed his riled Soul Weeping Beast, thoughts quickly churned through his mind, but he still maintained his bearing and calm voice.

In the time it took to finish a cup of tea, Han Li and the others finished discussing their plan of action. Then they blurred quickly and set off, taking out their own sets of formation tools, and setting down spell formations to boost their offensive potential.

Han Li and Grand Immortal Xu were simultaneously setting down a grand attack formation known as the Windfire Dragon Formation. Although it can’t compare to other grand formations, it was the most powerful offensive-type they could place down on short notice.

It was said once the formation was activated, it could produce attacks on the level of a full powered strike of a late-Nascent Soul cultivator using a common magic treasure.

A half-hour later, the formations were finished being placed down one after another, and they began to take charge over them.

Han Li and the Grand Immortal Xu decided to take joint charge of the Windflame Dragon Formation.

It was a laughable situation. The two were irreconcilable enemies, but they were quickly forced into such a ragtag alliance.

Grand Immortal Xu stared at the grey mist barrier sealing them and raised his hand, releasing a ball of white light and pounding against the wall. However, the ball didn’t rupture. It simply floated in the air and sparkled, indicating a clear marker.

He then bluntly said, “In a moment, everyone will attack this point!”

The others remained silent in tacit agreement.

Grand Immortal Xu then shot a glance at Han Li and nodded.

He gave a faint smile in response and cast an incantation gesture without another word. He flicked his fingers around him and began to launch spell seals. In the blink of an eye, several tens of spell formations began to light up and hum.

Grand Immortal Xu took a shallow breath and a fire-red light sparked from his hand. He pressed it against the ground, and in the glow of red light, he activated a few formation plates buried deep into the ground.

The space suddenly trembled before a dozen pillars of crimson flame shot up from the ground. Each pillar was a foot thick and emitted a scorching heat as if the very air was being lit aflame.

At the same time, Han Li flipped his hand and produced a faint azure formation plate.

He slapped his other hand on top of it and it began to flicker with light. The spell formation immediately glittered, releasing hums as a dozen flood dragons condensed from the blue winds inside. Following an incantation, they all charged towards a different pillar of flame.

Wind and fire merged together to form a dozen windflame flood dragons, combining the intensity of fire and momentum of wind.

As soon as the dragons took form, Grand Immortal Xu’s face lit up and he harshly shouted, “Attack!”

Then, he spat out an azure pearl, and the Keen Spirit Peacock circling above its head flapped its wings, releasing a wave of rainbow light, bursting with astonishing speed.

The others then activated their contributing spell formations and released their own abilities and attacks in an unreadable sequence

World-shaking explosions shattered without end. Bursts of light repeatedly flared with gigantic momentum, causing the entire space to tremble.

Han Li flung his sleeve and released several tens of flying swords into the air. Soon after, they duplicated themselves to create a swarm of several hundred sword-lights. When the others saw the force that they carried, they were reminded of the sharpness his swords originally carried, and their expressions faintly shifted. Their fear towards him had grown a tad heavier.

Not caring of what the others thought, Han Li commanded the swordlights with a spell seal and they instantly condensed into a huge sword that was over thirty meters long. After it was struck with another spell seal, a layer of golden lightning arced from its surface and thunder rang out.

Despite the huge sword’s completion, Han Li didn’t immediately set off on his attack. With a soft shout, he flung the formation plate up into the air.

He clasped his hands in an incantation gesture and then pointed at several different spots on the plate, causing it to tremble each time before rapidly eroding in a muffled burst, raining down azure light that was quickly absorbed by the formation.

With the newfound power, the spell flags flared blindingly, and the dozen huge windflame flood dragons began to rage. With roaring cries, the dragons surged several times in size and charged forward with brandished claws and fangs.

The windflame flood dragons arranged themselves in a line during the charge and struck the seal wall in succession.

This time, the grey mist violently quivered from the attacks and soon began to warp.

When the last windflame dragon exploded against the wall, the residual energy of the attacks concentrated into a huge ball of wind and fire. In a crimson flash, it was stained red and transformed into a huge blade slicing at the same location.

The brittle sound of breaking glass filled the air.

A three-meter-long crack appeared in the wall that was a foot deep. But with its appearance, black light flashed from the wall intent on mending itself. When the other cultivators saw this, they immediately rained down a mad barrage of attacks, forcefully slowing down the rate of the wall’s recovery.

It was then that Han Li took action.

The huge golden sword struck down at the crack as a bolt of lightning.

Golden light ruptured from the breach as if a golden sun had been born within it. The fissure instantly expanded and sank several times deeper. The strike of this single attack produced several times more power than all their previous strikes combined.

Even Han Li was stunned by the outcome.

It appeared that the Divine Devilbane Lightning was able to restrain the wall for the moment. Could it be that the Black Wind Flag was a Devil Dao spirit treasure?

Although Han Li felt apprehensive, the light faded away to reveal a thin barrier of white light past the seal.

When they saw this, they rejoiced, but before anyone could launch an attack, an inch-large blade silently appeared in front of the crack and blurred out of sight. With one final bang, the thin white wall flickered with black light and shattered to pieces, producing a ten-meter-large hole that led to a familiar scene.

They felt instant relief at the sight and in a silver flash, a silhouette appeared in front of the opening in a strange fashion and passed through it first. It was Han Li’s human-like puppet.

The others that were originally hesitant turned flustered by this. Without much more thought, they used their various teleportation techniques to follow through.

A pair of silver wings also appeared behind Han Li, but he didn’t immediately follow through. Instead, a strange expression momentarily flashed from his face and his lips stirred.

Gui Ling came to a sudden stop with a bewildered expression on her face when she saw this. She had already arrived in front of the opening in a white-black streak.

In that short moment of delay, Grand Immortal Xu and the others rushed through.

However, a crimson light suddenly flared from outside, and countless black threads ripped through the air as they tore into the opening. Grand Immortal Xu and Lin Yinping let out deafening shouts in their alarm. In a loud and abrupt explosion, dense blood Qi suddenly surrounded Master Scatterwind who was now wearing a sinister smile.

“Go!”

Han Li shouted without any hesitation and directly shot through the opening in a spark of silver lightning.

Gui Ling felt complete bewilderment but quickly followed him out regardless. As soon as he appeared outside the seal, his surroundings were completely engulfed in blood Qi, but as he was already prepared for this, arcs of golden lightning from his body kept the blood Qi at bay.

He then stopped and looked in the direction of the opening with a raised brow.

The breach in the seal was quickly shrinking, and there was a sea of dense blood Qi roiling around it, filling the air with a sour stench. There were also a few figures floating in the air above the seal: the Silver-winged Nightfiend, the Lion Hawk, and a giant white-furred monster.

The monster wore the same clothes as Master Scatterwind and his body stank of profuse corpse Qi. He turned his head to reveal eyes lit with a green blaze, sharp fangs, and a shriveled face covered in white fur.

At that moment, the monster was controlling the blood sea and his crimson blade to suppress a single person from escaping.

This person’s body had lost one of his arms and legs, and was desperately using an azure pearl and silver hook to block the crimson light and corrosive blood Qi surrounding him. He was Grand Immortal Xu who now wore a hateful expression.

Not far from him was the Keen Spirit Peacock. It was trapped by a purple mist that was rigidly produced by the Lion Hawk. It was fully occupied with preserving its own life.

As for Lin Yinping, she was caught in a barrage of countless Ghostfiend Threads by the Nightfiend. Were it not for the grand abilities of her embroidered silkworm scarf, matching thread for thread, she would’ve long been captured.

But it was only a matter of time before she would fall.

Because of Han Li’s warning, Gui Ling also managed to make it out. Then, her eyes focused on the white-furred monster and astonishedly shouted, “It’s him!”

Translator's Thoughts

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1053: Nascent Soul Convergence

A bolt of lightning suddenly crashed from the sky and ruptured in dazzling golden light, dispersing half of the ghost face in an instant.

The face let out a miserable scream, but the attack only provoked it further. Just as Grand Immortal Xu rejoiced from the assistance, the ghost bit down on his neck.

Endless layers of crimson light engulfed him in an instant.

He sensed his body quickly eroding within the crimson light. Frightened, he hastily chanted a strange incantation and surrounded his body in a layer of golden light. It briefly shrunk before exploding.

Golden light flared, scattering the crimson around him, followed by a Nascent Soul flittering out from it. It used instantaneous movement to blink over thirty meters away.

“You want to run?” Corpse Xiong coldly snorted and fiercely grabbed at the air.

A cloud of black Qi suddenly condensed above the Nascent Soul, creating a large hand that swept down towards it. Its very appearance seemed to suppress an area of thirty meters around it with its vast pressure.

Immortal Xu inwardly cursed at the sight.

If it were before the ambush, his Nascent Soul would’ve been able to easily teleport farther away and even have the power to break past the Black Wind Flag’s restriction. After all, the Nascent Soul congealed from his cultivation was immensely powerful and had the ability to fight without a body.

As he had already exhausted most of his spiritual power inside the sea of blood, he stood little chance at resisting this technique.

Meanwhile, Han Li was standing a hundred meters with his hands behind his back, wearing an indifferent expression. He appeared to be unwilling to take any further action after releasing his earlier bolt of lightning.

With no other option, Immortal Xu could only run with all his might.

He channeled his remaining magic power and had his Nascent Soul open its mouth to spit out a metal medallion in preparation to use his soulbound magic treasure to escape.

But then, silver light flashed and a man appeared above the black hand. He raised his arm and a dragon’s cry sounded out. In a bright flare, a green streak glowing with golden light shot out, striking the large hand.

A huge hole instantly exploded in the hand, and countless thin arcs of lightning wildly raged through the air, collapsing the black Qi.

The silhouette in the silver light then blurred, arriving over thirty meters away and quickly moving to Immortal Xu’s Nascent Soul.

He rejoiced in his escape of death and instantly glowed as he flew farther away.

Although the silhouette in silver light had saved him, he wasn’t about to trust his life in the hands of another.

The silhouette ignored this gesture and instead turned to face Corpse Xiong and the others.

The Keen Spirit Peacock had received an order from Immortal Xu and its body trembled, launching several of its long tail feathers towards the Lion Hawk.

Rainbow light surged from the attack, forcing the Lion Hawk to withdraw.

The purple mist was dissolved by the rainbow light, creating a large opening.

The peacock took advantage of this opportunity to wildly flap its wings, strangely warping its body like smoke as it twisted its way through the mist and rushing to the side of Immortal Xu’s Nascent Soul.

The Nascent Soul rejoiced and the two immediately converged. An inconceivable scene followed.

The peacock opened its mouth and swallowed his Nascent Soul. It soon let out a clear cry, and the peacock flared its feathers.

Suddenly, blinding rainbow light then submerged and hid the bird’s body.

At nearly the same time, a cloud of black-white Qi suddenly warped close to the Silver-winged Nightfiend and Lin Yinping’s battle.

Gui Ling appeared and the Nightfiend’s expression froze as soon as he saw her.

She expressionlessly glanced at him, and simply sent him a few voice transmissions before taking any further actions.

His expression faintly shifted and he pondered to himself for a brief moment before drawing out a long sigh. He waved his hands and released Lin Yinping from the assault, having his Ghosfiend Threads return to him in a dense and massive wave.

Lin Yinping rejoiced and thought to escape, but Gui Ling had other plans. Her figure blurred and suddenly arrived at Lin Yinping’s side with the huge silver axe raised. She swung down without any hesitation, light flaring from the weapon.

In her fright, Lin Yinping pointed to her embroidered cloth desperately wishing for it to block the attack.

But in a strange flash of light, a huge tiger phantom appeared from the axe and pounced towards her.

A rip sounded out as the embroidered cloth was split in two, and the tiger phantom immediately covered the woman in a ball of yellow Qi.

A fishy scent enveloped her and she inwardly cursed. Her head drooped and her body soon plummeted through the air.

Gui Ling then formed an incantation gesture and had the cloud of yellow Qi firmly constrict her.

Black-white Qi surged and Lin Yinping disappeared from her original location. She reappeared at Han Li’s side in a flicker.

As this all happened, Corpse Xiong hadn’t yet to take action. He simply observed with a cold indifference.

With their orders accomplished, the human-like puppet and Gui Ling blurred, reappearing behind Han Li.

Rather than taking even a glance at his new hostage, he wore an odd expression as he looked in a different location.

The rainbow light shining from the peacock was brilliant, and only grew more intense with time.

“Fellow Daoist Han! What are you scheming?” A thunderous voice rumbled out from the blinding light. The voice resembled Immortal Xu’s but was much harsher and carried a furious and violent tone.

“Didn’t I help you by saving Fellow Daoist Lin?” Han Li replied with indifference.

“Oh? So it seems I’ve been overly suspicious,” the voice from the rainbow light softened and the light faded to reveal the Keen Spirit Peacock. However, it was much larger than before and there was a shining white face on top of its head. The face was hollow and transparent, but it was clearly Immortal Xu.

But when he saw that Lin Yinping was unconscious, he wore a worried gaze.

“Relax, I don’t do anything to her, but I have a few things I must ask of you. I hope you won’t disappoint me,” Han Li calmly said.

“Are you threatening me?” The face’s expression sank with faint anger.

“I wouldn’t dare, but don’t forget what you said. Fellow Daoist Lin is by my side only so that you don’t do anything...unbecoming of your position. You’re not going to turn back on your promise, are you?” Han Li sneered and his expression turned sinister.

Immortal Xu’s expression remained unwavering and turned his gaze, “How about we settle this after we deal with the demons before us?”

Han Li stroked his chin and said, “That’s fine. I had the same idea.”

His indifferent attitude came as a shock to the grand immortal. He found himself at a loss of what to say.

Han Li faintly smiled and gave a command to Gui Ling. After, the two flew forward along with the human-like puppet.

When they arrived near the blood sea, they stopped and Han Li glanced at Corpse Xiong, saying, “As the overlord of Myriad Demon Valley, you should’ve come to Kunwu Mountain on important business. So have I, and these two are useful to me, so I’ll be taking them for the time being. I hope you don’t take offense.” Han Li’s words were gentle, but his tone was unyielding, much to the fury of the Nightfiend and the Lion Hawk.

Corpse Xiong suddenly broke his silence, “Fellow Daoist, you are named Han Li, correct? And you also come from the Heavenly South?”

Han Li paused and he cautiously answered, “That’s right. Do you plan on seeking revenge?”

“Not at all. I can turn a blind eye to your actions this time, but only once. The next time you meddle in our affairs, you’ll never see the Heavenly South again.” A green flame surged from Corpse Xiong’s eyes for just a moment.

When Han Li heard this, the corner of his mouth twitched, but he simply wore a silent smile.

Corpse Xiong grasped his hands in an incantation gesture and pointed to the crimson light in the distance.

The light flickered and turned into a huge crimson blade. It then descended towards the blood sea.

The ghost face previously scattered reappeared from the blood blade and sneered.

Then, the sea combined into a pillar of blood and flew into the ghost face’s mouth, soon disappearing in the blink of an eye.

While the blood blade appeared no different than before, the stench of blood was far more putrid.

Corpse Xiong then beckoned to the two demons before flying in the direction of the palace.

In the blink of an eye, the three disappeared without a trace. Corpse Xiong seemed to have another objective in mind, and seemed to have persuaded the two demons to follow him.

Han Li narrowed his eyes to a shining cold glint.

He then turned around and said, “Alright, Brother Xu should have no trouble answering my questions now!”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1055: Soulburn Mine

Han Li stared at Grand Immortal Xu’s Nascent Soul and calmly said, “Although I don’t fear your Endless Sky Temple and I don’t want to provoke any powerful enemies, that doesn’t mean I’m willing to take the marking of your holy beast and become a part of your temple. I also don’t know if the marking has anything strange behind it. It’ll be fine so long as your temple doesn’t seek me out any more, but don’t blame me for being ruthless if you continue to bother me.”

Grand Immortal Xu hurriedly agreed, “That is only natural. Given your current abilities, we wouldn’t do something that would harm ourselves. Could you now release the Saintess?”

Han Li snorted and bluntly said, “Why the rush? I still haven’t finished raising my conditions.”

“Then, please continue.” Grand Immortal Xu felt his heart sink.

An odd expression appeared on Han Li’s face, “I can give back the holy beast incarnation, but not immediately. It will take a few years. I can at least guarantee that the beast won’t suffer any harm.”

Grand Immortal Xu replied with a hesitant tone, “This... this will be hard to agree to.”

“This is only the first condition. Secondly, I will place down a few restrictions on both your Nascent Souls as well to prevent you from breaking your promise. Don’t worry, it isn’t a soul restriction technique. At our level, such tricks are hardly effective. But I happened upon an ancient refinement technique for something called the ‘Soulburn Mine’. You will need to swallow one of these and they each contain a thread of my spiritual sense.”

Grand Immortal Xu’s heart trembled and he shouted, “A Soulburn Mine! You might as well kill me right now!”

Han Li calmly stated, “If you aren’t willing to agree, then I will head to the Soaring Sky Plains after I’m done with you two. I imagine the Moulan will be very excited to know that all of your Grand Immortals are dead. When the time comes, it is likely your people will become extinct from this world.”

Grand Immortal Xu felt an icy chill spread down his back and he furiously shouted, “You dare!?”

“Why wouldn’t I? When you were just trying to bind me with that marking earlier. I detest the idea of entering the control of others. To avoid that I would need to use another method and this is the only one I have. If you are unwilling to swallow the Soulburn Mine, I’ll be taking this opportunity to rid myself of you. This is your last chance.” Without any intention of delaying the matter further, Han Li raised his hand and bent his thumb, counting down, “Five!”

In a panic, Grand Immortal Xu hastily rattled, “How do I know you won’t use the mine to deal with us at a more opportune time?”

“How would I ever find a more opportune time than now?” Han Li sneered and folded his index finger, “Four!”

“But...” The Nascent Soul began to mutter to itself and its eyes wildly wandered as if it were looking for an opportunity to escape.

But at some unknown time, Gui Ling had already flown above the peacock’s head and was watching the Nascent Soul with a cold expression.

“Three!”

Startled, he felt his heart drop.

With the three surrounding him, escape was only a vain delusion.

“Two!”

Han Li now only had one finger standing.

Gui Ling and the human-puppet released an astonishing spiritual pressure in a threatening gesture.

Gui Ling raised her hand and summoned the silver axe into her grasp. The puppet also summoned the thunderfire bow and the small golden arrow in its hands flared with light, aimed directly at the Keen Spirit Peacock.

Han Li flipped his hand and summoned the Triflame Fan into his grasp. With a gentle wave, talisman characters rolled across its surface and tri-colored flames flashed, releasing the clear cry of a phoenix.

When Grand Immortal Xu saw that light that flared from the fan, his skin turned completely pale and he tightly shut his mouth.

A glint as cold as sword steel shined from Han Li’s eyes as he uttered, “One!”

Seeing that Han Li was willing to carry out his threat, Grand Immortal Xu could only grit his teeth and yelled, “Fine! I agree...”

When Han Li heard this, he nodded and held one hand in an incantation gesture and chanted ancient words.

After a short while, Han Li’s complexion paled and a white ball of light shot out from his forehead and floated towards Grand Immortal Xu’s Nascent Soul.

Han Li still held the Triflame Fan in his other hand. It was obvious that he wasn’t going to allow Grand Immortal Xu the opportunity to escape.

Gui Ling and the puppet also stayed on guard. Grand Immortal Xu even felt the pressure they emitted become even stronger as they focused on his Nascent Soul.

He could only inwardly sigh as he looked at the tiny white ball with fear. It had a white misty layer that covered something faintly signed with rainbow light. It matched the description of the Soulburn Mine, known to be a legendary technique during ancient times.

It soon arrived before him and was being kept at bay by the rainbow light that covered him. He still hesitated, but Han Li’s glare left no room for discussion and he could only allow the white ball to pass through his barrier.

In a flash, the ball entered his Nascent Soul, leaving no trace.

Then, Grand Immortal Xu hastily used his spiritual sense to examine his soul.

He found nothing out of the ordinary as if the mine wasn’t there.

This was only cause for greater fear.

This legendary technique was something that was created from a cultivator’s spiritual sense and was undetectable.

It was exactly as the legends said. It wouldn’t be possible to rid himself of something he couldn't find.

Han Li indifferently interrupted his search, “Fellow Daoist shouldn’t think about forcefully expelling it. It isn’t something that can be removed with magic power. So long as you hold true to our conditions, I will not activate the mine.”

Grand Immortal Xu wore an unsightly expression in response.

Han Li then turned his sights on the unconscious Lin Yinping and frowned. After some hesitation, he shook his head and placed a mine on her too.

Still unable to find the mine, Grand Immortal Xu resentfully said, “Since you placed us underneath this restriction instead of killing us, do you plan on coercing us?”

“Coerce you?” Han Li said indifferently, “Don’t worry, so long as you obedient follow me here and lend me your aid, we’ll go our separate ways when we leave. You’ll still be members of the Endless Sky Temple, and I’ll return to secluded cultivation in the Heavenly South. As for the mines, they should disappear in just a few hundred years.”

“‘Just’ a few hundred years!” Grand Immortal Xu was at a loss for words.

“We’ve wasted enough time. Let’s move.” Han Li glanced at the unconscious Lin Yinping and waved his sleeve, covering her in an azure mist.

Her eyes soon began to stir and she slowly roused. When she saw Han Li at her side, she blurred away without another thought, moving over thirty meters away. She then spat out a silver flying sword in her vigilance.

“Fellow Daoist Lin, please don’t act rashly!” Grand Immortal Xu shouted out. He then began to quickly send her voice transmissions.

Han Li calmly observed with his hands behind his back.

Gui Ling returned to his side and the human-like puppet once again disappeared from sight.

In the blink of an eye, the Endless Sky Saintess Lin Yinping came to realize what had happened to her and her complexion instantly paled, her eyes unable to conceal her terror.

Han Li thought to say something, but then a huge explosion sounded out, shaking the entire space that contained them. A huge swordstreak pierced through the walls of the sealed space that had previously trapped them, creating a large hole three meters wide. Two streaks then shot through, circling once in the air before dropping down near Han Li and the others, revealing a man in Daoist robes and one in a scholar’s.

“Daoist Sevenwonders!” Lin Yinping saw a black-robed scholar amongst them and wore a trace of joy.

The black-robed scholar had a hook nose and a harsh appearance. With a tone of surprise, he asked, “ Yi! How did Fairy Lin end up here?”

This person was the Heavenly Devil Sect’s Sevenwonders. Because the sect had some trade agreements with the Endless Sky Temple, Lin Yinping had friendly relations with the old devil, which led to him allowing her to borrow the Clear Sound Mirror at the Jin Capital — a treasure that could see through illusions.

The white-haired red-faced Daoist at his side was the High Zenith Sect’s Master Sable. When he saw the woman, he called out to her with a beaming smile, but when he saw the others, he wore an astonished expression.

The old Daoist’s smile faded and he bewilderedly asked, “Fairy Lin, who are these two Fellow Daoists? Fellow Daoist Xu’s peacock is here, but I don’t see him.”

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

MonkaS

Chapter 1056: Spatial Destruction

When she heard Master Sable’s question, Lin Yinping glanced between the Keen Spirit Peacock and Han Li with a hesitant expression.

Just then, white light flashed above the head of the peacock and Grand Immortal Xu’s face appeared in the air. As Daoist Sevenwonders and Master Sable looked on with amazement, he wryly smiled, “There is no need to look for me. Since my body has been destroyed, my Nascent Soul is currently residing in my bird.”

Alarmed, Master Sable’s complexion paled. “How can that be?! You were a late-stage cultivator! Could it be the Ancient Devil Ancestor has already escaped!?”

Grand Immortal Xu’s expression sank. “...It seems you already knew about that devil.”

Master Sable chuckled and reassured him, “Fellow Daoist Xu, don’t misunderstand. I only recently learned of this when my master sent information about what laid here. This matter was so important that I was hoping that you could give us some more insight.”

Grand Immortal Xu felt doubtful of his words, but since he was reduced to a Nascent Soul, he couldn’t question him. Instead, he sighed and said, “The devil ancestor indeed escaped its prison, but my body was not destroyed by the devil. Rather, we were ambushed by the Myriad Demon Valley’s Ancient Corpse Xiong.”

Master Sable blinked and said, “Myriad Demon Valley? That’s impossible. I’ve been guarding the entrance to the mountain this whole time. How could Old Corpse Xiong slip past me? Could it be he entered before us?”

“That’s right. Not only did he enter before us, but he also used some sort of technique to mask the corpse Qi from his body and disguised himself as a human cultivator.” He felt great heartache, having suffered so much to the power of the blood blade.

Daoist Sevenwonders frowned, “Then the result isn’t surprising considering that Corpse Xiong ambushed you. It sounds like he used the strange treasure that the Myriad Demon Valley has called the Form Enchantment Pearl. It is said once the pearl is consumed, one can not only change their appearance at will, but also conceal demonic, corpse, or any other odd aura. Common cultivators wouldn’t be able to see through it. I doubt that even my Clear Sound Mirror wouldn’t be able to break their concealment.”

Something sparked in Master Sable’s mind and he said, “Now that you mention it, I heard that after one swallows the pearl, their magic power is greatly reduced for the pearl’s effects to work. When Corpse Xiong ambushed you, his true appearance must’ve been revealed.”

“Fellow Daoists, you are correct. Corpse Xiong did appear in his true form when he ambushed me.” Immortal Xu wore a resentful expression.

Sevenwonders, the middle-aged scholar, examined the Keen Spirit Peacock and smiled, saying, “It’s still fortunate that your Nascent Soul was able to escape Corpse Xiong’s attacks. Furthermore, you haven’t fully possessed another body yet. So long as you find a suitable replacement, you’ll be able to restore your cultivation with only a hundred years of seclusion.”

Immortal Xu sighed, “Brother Sevenwonders is quite wise. Although I’ve temporarily attached myself to the Keen Spirit Peacock, it will be better for me to find a suitable body as soon as I can.”

Sevenwonders said nothing more and turned his gaze to Gui Ling with an odd expression.

“This... Fellow Daoist is quite unfamiliar to me. Could you tell me your name?” Sevenwonders asked. At his side, Master Sable also began to closely examine the horned woman.

After all, Gui Ling wasn’t capable of concealing her identity as a grade ten demon beast in the face of these two similarly ranked grand cultivators.

Gui Ling remained expressionless, but Han Li smiled and said, “This Fellow Daoist is Gui Ling, and I am Han Li. We were delivered to this mountain after we had mistakenly activated a teleportation formation.”

Master Sable appeared quite surprised that Han Li was speaking on the horned woman’s behalf and began to look at him with greater importance. He smiled and replied, “That is quite unusual. Could you tell me what sect you came from, Fellow Daoist Han? I don’t believe we’ve met.”

Although this was Han Li’s first meeting with Master Sable, he could faintly guess that he was an elder of one of the ten great sects. As such, he politely replied, “I am only a vagrant cultivator. It is only natural that you wouldn’t know of me. But since you are here together with the Heavenly Devil Sect’s Daoist Sevenwonders, this matter must be of grave importance. If I may boldly ask, how did you enter the pagoda’s eighth floor? The teleportation formation wasn’t activating for some reason.”

Master Sable casually answered, “I’ve been quite careless and have forgotten to introduce myself! I am the High Zenith Sect’s Master Sable. As for how we entered, we didn’t need to use any teleportation formation. Rather, we used the High Zenith Sect’s Worldbreaker Talisman, and forcefully entered by breaking through the walls of the eighth floor.”

Han Li doubtfully said, “The Worldbreaker Talisman? Would it be possible for that to break through?”

“It wouldn’t be with the talisman itself, but it was paired together with a specific secret technique and the Heavenbound Sword. But I didn’t think that we’d be trapped in a sealed space right after we entered.” With that said, Master Sable glanced around him and clicked his tongue.

Lin Yinping sighed in admiration, “I’ve long heard of the grand reputation of both the High Zenith Sect’s Worldbreaker Talisman and the Heavenbound Sword. What we managed with great difficulty was easily accomplished by the two of you. It is no wonder why your sects are among the greatest of the Righteous and Devilish Dao in the Great Jin.”

Master Sable twirled his beard and politely answered, “Fairy Lin praises us too highly. The powers of your temple’s treasures are by no means small. It just so happens that we had more suitable methods to tear through space.”

She couldn't help but wryly smile in the face of his modest remarks.

The Endless Sky Temple had about the same number of high-grade cultivators as the two of them, but they couldn't possibly compare in terms of treasures. The two sects had legacies that stretched back to ancient times.

Sevenwonders then glanced around him and puzzlingly asked, “Where is that Old Devil Qian? Master Sable mentioned that he entered this mountain earlier.”

When Immortal Xu and Lin Yinping heard this, they couldn't help but glance at Han Li.

Lady Mu had previously mentioned that Old Devil Qian and Han Li had fought once before. They originally hadn’t believed that Han Li would be capable of slaying the old devil, but after witnessing his current abilities, they couldn't help but be suspicious.

When Master Sable and Daoist Sevenwonders saw the two’s strange actions, they exchanged a glance of surprise and focused their attention on Han Li.

Han Li inwardly sighed, but maintained a calm exterior and said, “Fellow Daoist Qian and I parted after we left Kunwu Hall. He is probably searching for treasure elsewhere. I also don’t know where the other Ying Sifting Sect Elders are.”

Immortal Xu sternly said, “Fellow Daoist Han doesn’t need to ponder much about Fellow Daoist Ge and the others. On the way, they were ambushed by the Ye Clan Grand Elder and have already perished. Their Nascent Souls are no more.”

“So it was like that!” Han Li said with realization.

Having realized something, Master Sable gave Han Li a strange glance and said, “Kunwu Mountain is truly perilous for so many to have perished here.”

Sevenwonders glanced at the ruins of the palace in the distance the solemnly said, “It is good that the Yin Sifting Sect Elders are gone. It has saved us some trouble. Fellow Daoists, please tell us about the Ancient Devil Ancestor.”

“Yes, let us hear it! I won’t hide this from you. We came here for the matter of the ancient devil ancestor. Since this matter concerns the stability of the entire cultivation world, I hope you will join us.” Master Sable gave Han Li and company a beaming smile.

Immortal Xu and Lin Yinping didn’t immediately reply, and wore odd expressions as they remained silent. Now that they were placed underneath restrictions, they didn’t dare to speak carelessly without knowing what Han Li planned.

From the very start, Gui Ling hadn’t spoken.

Han Li continued to appear calm and collected, and he glanced at the two grand cultivators with a towering gaze.

Master Sable and Daoist Sevenwonders glanced at one another with a trace of astonishment. It was clear that Immortal Xu and Lin Yinping held Han Li in fear.

“Since you wish to know about the devil ancestor, I will explain,” Han Li indifferently stated.

“Good, in that case-” As Master Sable started with a smile, a world-shaking explosion erupted from the direction of the palace, followed by the eruption of a dozen pillars of white light.

The entire space around them wildly shook and a loud and shrill cry sounded out. The ground slowly split, emitting white light into the air and distorting space itself.

“Not good! The devil ancestor has begun dissolving the seal on the ninth floor! To think that she could have recovered enough in such a short time!” Daoist Sevenwonders shouted out in terror.

‘The seal on the ninth floor?’ When Han Li heard this, he saw the space surrounding them begin to collapse. Without another thought, his body flashed with light and released the Tailstar Shield, covering him in a silver barrier.

Before he could perform anything else, the pillars of light suddenly faded and turned pitch black. Afterwards, they surged in size and curved off in every direction, rending apart space wherever it brushed past, producing clashing white and black light.

“Spatial tears!”

Han Li could no longer maintain a calm appearance.

Without another thought, he summoned a fire-red talisman into his hand and slapped it onto his body, summoning forth a crimson flood dragon which soon disappeared.

In the blink of an eye, Han Li turned into half-flood dragon, half-human form.

Lin Yinping shouted out as a black crevice suddenly appeared in the air before them.

When Han Li looked at this black streak, he sensed an insatiable abyss; an inexhaustible darkness that released none who entered.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1057: The Ninth Floor

Having experienced what it’s like to experienced what it’s like to be devoured by a spatial tear, Han Li was greatly fearful of them, but still managed to collect himself. With the power of the Spirit Subjugation Talisman, his magic power was forced to the peak of mid-Nascent Soul stage, and his Tailstar Essence Shield became blindingly bright as he poured in his newfound power.

He apprehensively thought, ‘Against a tear this large, so long as I don’t skirt past its edge, I should come out of this relatively safe.’

As the spatial tear enveloped him, he felt darkness embrace him and he suddenly grew dizzy. Then, light shined around him and he found himself in a new space.

Fortunately, Han Li had experience with this and instantly cleared his mind, hastily looking around him in a state of caution.

“The ninth floor!” he gasped.

He was clearly in an isolated space of mostly empty area a couple kilometers long. It was surrounded by a ravenous yellow mist that repeatedly lit and dimmed. It was unknown how broad it stretched.

Underneath him stood a huge altar that was hundreds of meters tall, but was rather narrow and had steps down on every side. It was made from an ethereal jade of impeccable majesty.

Surrounding the altar was a circle of huge stone pillars that formed a giant spell formation. They blazed with radiance as if showing the formation was active. At the very top of the altar, lay a giant two-headed wolf along with several silhouettes. There was an ongoing battle of great intensity as the wolf’s black head blew out an endless stream of inky black Qi.

These silhouettes must have been the cultivators and demons from the eighth floor.

Long Meng, still in possession of Hua Tianqi’s body, was fluttering her hands in the air, producing two giant white hands to smash down on the black Qi repeatedly.

The Ye Clan Grand Elder, Corpse Xiong, the Silver-winged Nightfiend, and the others were standing farther away, trying to avoid being drawn into the exchange. Only the large-headed eccentric was missing among them.

But what astonished Han Li the most was that the younger elder from the Immortal Form Sect stood at the wolf’s side.

At that moment, her eyes were lifeless and black Qi engorged her face. She was controlling a sparkling silver textile shuttle and was fighting a furious Lady Mu.

The others were also using various techniques to attack the huge wolf with all the power they could muster. Additionally, the surrounding yellow winds rolled on the surface of the huge wolf where a black flood dragon was concealed. It spat out black torrents, blocking a huge silver lotus and eight demon beast mirages.

The silver lotus was motionlessly floating in the air and shining brightly, producing an unending stream of ancient palm-sized talisman characters across its surface. When the torrents made contact with it, a fierce explosion would form and the black wind was scattered.

It was the Black Wind Flag and the Eight Spirit Ruler!

Han Li was astonished by the appearance of the two Immortal Form Sect Elders.

Previously, Gui Ling reported that they had placed some sort of spell formation underground and were scheming. Had they not been rushing towards the black teleportation formation, he would’ve stealthily observed them. In any case, it appeared that one of the women had succumbed to the influence of the Elder Devil.

But what astonished Han Li in particular was how the huge wolf still held the advantage despite having so many highly cultivated opponents. Her attackers were even being pushed back.

The black Qi that the huge wolf released was as dense as oil. Apart from Corpse Xiong’s crimson blade wildly slashing at it, the others were keeping themselves and their treasures a fair distance away, not daring to touch it. They could only launch various ranged attacks to strike at any of the approaching black Qi pythons.

If it weren’t for Long Meng and Corpse Xiong receiving most of the attacks from the huge wolf or the lotus-form of the Eight Spirit Ruler occupying the huge wolf’s attention, everyone else would’ve been wiped out.

The Silver-winged Nightfiend’s Ghost Fiend Threads and the Lion Hawk’s golden shockwaves didn’t seem to have any effect on the black devilish Qi as well.

After all this examination, Han Li noticed something rather strange about the battle.

The two-headed wolf wouldn’t leave the altar and continued to fight as if it were guarding the top of it.

Then, he heard a furious voice shout out from a distance.

“Not good! How did the Elder Devil gain the magic tool to open the seal?”

Han Li turned and looked in the direction of the shocked voice. It belonged to Master Sable who stood a sixty meter distance. Daoist Sevenwonders was at his size with an equally gloomy air.

Han Li then discovered that everyone else had all appeared within the space of the ninth floor and none of them appeared to be injured.

The spatial tear’s appearance wasn’t an accident then. Probably was caused by an activated restriction, teleporting everyone on the eight floor to this one.

However, Lin Yinping’s complexion was bloodless. The recent surprise had left her completely in terror.

Han Li then followed Master Sable and Sevenwonders’s gaze to the altar.

After closely examining for a moment, Han Li yelped in surprise.

He saw two huge ten-meter-tall stone tablets behind it. They appeared unremarkable.

As soon as he saw those, a glimpse of astonishment crossed his face as the name of Flexile Spirit Jade appeared in his mind. This jade is the same as the stone tablet he saw in the depths of the devilish Qi whirlpool in the Heavenly South. [1]

However, the stone tablet he saw in the past was shattered. These two were still intact and one had a dark-green block seal embedded within it, causing the stone pillar to tremble and shine with a faint black power.

Han Li’s expression stirred upon discovering that the pillar’s light was causing a reaction in the spell formation surrounding the altar, displaying that the pillar was a core part of the formation.

His thoughts became more fervent the longer he looked.

When Lady Mu saw the arrival of the others, she happily shouted, “Master Sable, Brother Sevenwonders, you’ve come at the right time! The devil ancestor is currently using the altar to remove the sealing restriction. Although I don’t know what is being suppressed, it cannot be good.”

“We meet again. Fellow Daoist Sable, let us act quickly or suffer the consequences.” Daoist Sevenwonders’s expression deeply sank and he immediately flung out his sleeve.

Suddenly, various-colored light flashed from his sleeve and seven various treasures were released down towards the huge wolf with great momentum. These were the grand treasures that earned him the name of ‘Sevenwonders’.

Master Sable sighed and acted with similar haste, taking out a sheathed golden sword.

Once drawn, it appeared dim and ancient, but when the old Daoist spat a mist of blood essence onto the sword, it seemed to have awakened. A heaven-shaking dragon’s cry rattled from the sword and it lit up with blinding light.

The old Daoist formed an incantation gesture with one of his hands and pointed to the sword with a solemn attitude, before waving his arm down.

A huge thirty-meter-long giant sword streak suddenly shot out from the ancient weapon and cleaved down as if a sword was a declaration from the heavens.

Before the sword Qi landed, a thunderous boom shot out. The sword Qi extended into a long white line as if it were tearing the air itself into two.

But as it so happened, the Devil Ancestor Yuan Cha had already taken notice of the newly arrived as soon as they had appeared.

A keen glint flashed from the wolf’s eyes and its body trembled. The black Qi that surrounded the altar quickly circled it and entered its body, rapidly disappearing. An instant later, the wolf opened its mouth and released a dense wave of black Qi to meet the attack.

“Be careful, the devilish Qi is extremely powerful!” Lady Mu cried out, “You cannot allow it to directly corrupt your treasures, or you will immediately lose their powers!”

At that moment, seven blinding lights and the giant swordstreak clashed against the devilish Qi.

As soon as Daoist Sevenwonders heard her, his expression briefly changed and he reached out for his treasures without another thought.

His seven streaks of light stopped in place upon initial contact with the devilish Qi. They promptly bound together and released a haze of variously-colored light before continuing on.

The huge swordstreak was the first to cut through the devilish Qi.

The swordlight and black Qi intertwined, releasing an astonishing boom. Countless yellow streaks erupted from the black Qi, leaving more holes than naught. Soon after the mist of light produced from Daoist Sevenwonders’ treasures instantly wiped away the remaining devilish Qi before the two attacks moved on to strike at the huge wolf down below.

Several puffs sounded out from below as the wolf released several more mouthfuls of black Qi in response.

Suddenly, the new Qi ruptured and completely submerged both of their attacks. Dim light violently flickered from them, only for them to immediately disappear after.

When the old Daoist saw this, his heart trembled and he hastily formed another incantation gesture, ordering the sword Qi, but it didn’t respond, only to disappear a moment later, to the old man’s surprise.

Having dealt with their attacks, the black Qi marched onward, madly rushing towards them in a display of astonishing momentum. The sheer force and scope of the attack would inevitably engulf Han Li and the others nearby.

Daoist Sevenwonders saw that the situation was far from good and moved to recall his treasures. Master Sable held the ancient sword in his hand and slicked at the air several times, producing a curtain of yellow light to temporarily protect them against the devilish Qi rushing towards them.

The old Daoist immediately turned to the scholar and gravely said, “Brother Sevenwonders, it seems that our usual treasures can’t deal with this devil. Quickly use those other! We cannot allow the seal to open, I will protect you!”

“I’ll have to trouble you then.” Without any further hesitation, Sevenwonders nodded and slapped his storage pouch. In a flicker of white light, several palm-sized emerald-green rings appeared in his hand.

Meanwhile, Han Li released several tens of golden flying swords. Before the devilish Qi approached, golden lightning wildly flashed and thunder roared, scattering them in their entirety.

[1]. In Chapter 968: Success, Han Li dived to the depths of the devilish Qi whirlpool located off the shore of the Heavenly South.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1059: The Scarlet Cry Drum

While Han Li was releasing his flying swords, he spoke to Silvermoon in his mind.

“If I cut off the black wolf head, the devil ancestor should temporarily lose control over the body, but that could massively backfire. Wouldn’t Long Meng rush to take control of the body first?”

Silvermoon quickly explained, “With the Devil Restriction Bands’ control, the devil’s Qi is sealed and her soul won’t be able to leave the head. So long as the soul is detached from the body, I am confident in my ability to regain control. Even if Long Meng comes with her strong spiritual sense, she cannot contest with your incisive blade tempered with Auric Essence. Given that common treasures can’t harm the Silvermoon Wolf body and she would have to fight for control against the devil, she most likely wouldn’t try since she would be at a disadvantage. Of course, she can’t imagine that master possesses so many flying swords of the same make, or she wouldn’t have run off to fight for the Divine Spirit Treasures.”

When Han Li heard her, he took a deep breath and resolved himself.

Silvermoon was his artifact spirit after all. Any power she gained would directly be his as well.

He promptly formed his hands in an incantation gesture and released his flying swords in the air. Golden light sparked between them and condensed together to form a giant shimmering golden sword.

With the simple point of a finger, deep thunder boomed as a layer of golden lightning sheathed the sword. Silver strands burst from the tip to flash a silver wolf head for only a moment.

With Silvermoon directly possessing the weapon, the sword was vastly improved, and she would be able to directly enter her original body as soon as the devil was beheaded.

The huge sword blurred, cleaving through the devilish Qi like a bolt of lightning. Sparks leapt out from its wake, soon arrived near the altar in several flashes, heading straight towards the neck of the huge wolf’s black head.

The golden sword’s astonishing display naturally caught the eye of everyone that was vying for the two Divine Spirit Treasures.

Even Long Meng gave a short pause in surprise before letting out a sneer.

She didn’t believe that the sword of a trifling mid-Nascent Soul cultivator could injure the body.

But for everyone apart from her, they felt completely startled as they witnessed what would happen.

When the huge blade dropped down with immense momentum at the neck of black head, the wolf suddenly leapt up and evaded the attack.

Han Li and company were completely dumbstruck.

“It was an act! The Devil Restricting Bands didn’t restrain it!” Master Sable shouted out with a trembling voice. Daoist Sevenwonders’s face also grew unsightly, but he wasn’t about to give up. With his hands in an incantation gesture, he began to chant in an attempt to reactivate the restriction bands.

The five rings brightly flared and began to tightly shrink once more, but the wolf only gave a cheshire grin in response. It then leapt back on top of the altar without any difficulty.

A pitch-black light shined from the wolf’s center and completely enveloped it in a blaze of light before withdrawing entirely inside the wolf.

In the blink of an eye, the wolf’s sparkling silver fur dimmed and was tarnished black, the only exception being the other silver wolf head.

“...Devilform Body? When did she complete the transformation?”

When Long Meng saw this, her expression paled in disbelief.

At that same time, the wolf raised its head and released matte black waves from its mouth that rippled the air.

They was no sound and they looked as delicate as a flower.

The five emerald rings on the wolf’s body were enveloped in these waves and shattered in dim sparks of light.

With the initial attack of the golden sword missing, the blade immediately turned around and twisted its path like a viper as it made its way back to Han Li.

The wolf coldly howled in response, condensing the devilish Qi that had originally been scattered. They began to coil around the sword in blacks ensnaring threads.

Han Li raised his brow and instantly formed a hand seal, commanding the sword to release nearly half of its Divine Devilbane Lightning reserves.

Thunder rang out and a ball of golden lightning radiated from the huge sword, releasing a world-shaking eruption.

Countless arcs of lightning chaotically scattered through the air, erasing away the devilish Qi wherever it passed, greatly thinning out most of the wolf’s attack.

The huge sword then used this opportunity to piece through the opening the lightning created and instantly arrived back at Han Li’s side.

“How does so much Divine Devilbane Lightning even exist in this mortal realm?”

The huge wolf couldn't help but glance at Han Li with a deep gaze.

Despite Han Li’s indifferent exterior, he felt his heart tremble.

No matter how powerful the wolf’s black shockwaves may be, they were extremely slow and faded away once they reached a hundred meters away from her body.

At that moment, the others felt a cold chill run down their back, feeling both relief and trepidation.

The devil ancestor was truly cunning. It was able to easily break the Devil Restriction Bands and deliberately feigned being incapacitated, luring the others to turn hostile in their fight for treasure. If it weren’t for Han Li’s wanton strike breaking her ploy, they would’ve done all the work for her as they fought for the Divine Spirit Treasure, letting her kill whoever remained.

The others then glanced at one another and dispersed in confusion.

The Divine Spirit Treasures were priceless, but now wasn’t the time to pursue them.

At that moment, a cold glint cast from the huge wolf’s eyes and she raised her claw, swiping at the air. Five translucent claw streaks ripped through the air before disappearing.

A woman’s miserable scream filled the space.

Alarmed, the others looked at the edge of the devilish Qi and saw Lady Mu rend to shreds by the claw streaks, her treasures and defenses gave without the slightest resistance. She had been caught off guard as she was occupied with fighting her bewitched junior.

Her Nascent Soul immediately emerged from the remains of her corpse and looked at the golden textile shuttle with a trace of hesitation before shooting off.

However, the Nascent Soul found her escape blocked.

The devilish Qi nearby gathered and turned into a large black hand, blurring towards the woman’s Nascent Soul in the blink of an eye.

Another step ahead, the huge wolf suddenly let out a fierce howl.

The piercing howl momentarily froze the Nascent Soul’s magic power when she was attempting to escape with instant movement.

The black hand then grabbed her and instantly dragged her into the devilish Qi.

“Stop!” Master Sable paled upon seeing this and shouted with furious alarm. He wildly poured magic power into the Heavenbound Sword and began to chop at the air with violent fervor.

In an instant, the Heavenbound Sword created unending phantoms of itself, turning countless deep yellow swordlights into a mountain of blades. With astonishing pressure, it flew forward with unyielding strength in an attempt to save Lady Mu’s life with all his might.

The others were surprised by his actions, but were nonetheless happy to witness the old man launch such a powerful attack.

Long Meng and Corpse Xiong exchanged a glance before joining in a joint attack.

Daoist Sevenwonders frowned at Master Sable’s sudden movements, but then he recalled a few rumors involving the two elders and an odd expression appeared on his face. Then after a moment of thought, he flipped his hand and summoned a half-foot-large drum.

The drum was scarlet and shined with beams of red light that almost appeared to be condensed from a raging inferno. As soon as it appeared, it instantly expanded to the size of a hundred meters, filling the entire air with senseless heat, leaving all the cultivators and demons with the sensation of being roasted alive.

When Lin Yinping saw the drum, she couldn't help but shout, “The Scarlet Cry Drum!”

Grand Immortal Xu circled above her head in the body of the peacock and also wore an expression of astonishment.

Han Li swept his gaze and sensed the astonishing fire-attribute spiritual power. It appeared to be just as powerful as his Triflame Fan.

In his shock, he instantly recognized it to be a Divine Spirit Treasure replica.

Sevenwonders raised the drum in his hand and turned to Han Li with a blank expression, “Fellow Daoist Han, your Divine Devilbane Lightning is rather effective against devilish Qi. Let us attack together. I will use the drum to conceal your movements.”

Han Li narrowed his eyes at the offer.

Before he could respond, the great attack that Master Sable had just released made contact with the surging devilish Qi down below. A huge rumbling quaked the air.

The swordlight and the devilish Qi clashed. For a time, the two seemed to have found themselves in a deadlock. It was then that Long Meng’s large white hand and Corpse Xiong’s blood blade entered the battle. The huge wolf easily blocked this attack by releasing beams of black light from its mouth.

Not only this, but the huge jet-black wolf suddenly raised its head and spat out two black balls.

When the orbs touched the ground, devilish Qi suddenly surged from them to form two silhouettes with eagle wings.

These two pseudo-devils had the appearance of a young man with a hooked nose, each wielding a large black saber. They expanded their wings and directly flew over to the Silver-winged Nightfiend and the Lion Hawk, who have already mostly destroyed one of the formation’s stone pillars.

Before the two devils drew close to the two demons, they waved their weapons and launched sword streaks at the two.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1062: Devil Giant

After Han Li was thrown twenty meters through the air, he concentrated the magic power in his body in furious alarm and managed to stabilize himself. Sensing a sharp pain from his abdomen, he looked down and felt his whole body run cold.

The Tailstar Essence Shield and his protective azure light barrier now had a fist-sized hole penetrated through. His clothes and armor formed from Gold Devouring Beetles had been ripped away as well to reveal the final layer of black armor.

The armor had a three inch opening where a sparkling silver blade had dug in, piercing through his stomach.

Azure Qi lit up his face and he shouted, suddenly forming a faint golden barrier around his body. He surprisingly received another attack by a strange blade. The wind rustled and the blade ricocheted towards the sky.

Han Li quickly raised his hand to the air and grabbed onto the weapon.

It was a half-foot long and curved like a crescent moon, but upon closer inspection it wasn’t a blade at all, it was more like an incredibly sharp wolf nail.

Han Li’s heart trembled and took another look at wound at his abdomen. The wound didn’t bleed, but revealed a glistening raw flesh that seemed to be mixed with faint golden threads. It was the unyielding metal-hard flesh he had gained after cultivating the first layer of the Bright Jade Technique.

Were it not for this last line of defence, the attack would’ve pierced through his dantian, a mortal strike.

This so-called Heavenwolf Drill was truly fearsome.

In his astonishment, he raised his head and looked at the puppet in front of him. Apart from rainbow light glistening from where the two nails pierced into its body, it appeared completely ordinary.

When Han Li saw this, he was relieved.

As Tailstar Essence and Elemental Jade was used to forge the puppet’s body, its durability was difficult to imagine.

Within the black light shining from the altar, the devil ancestor was amazed that her successive attacks hadn’t resulted in a kill.

The Heavenwolf Drill was the most vicious ability of her Silvermoon Wolf body.

Each use required her to destroy one of the four nails on her claws, with each nail being something that had been painstakingly nurtured after countless years. Their might was something even a late-Deity Transformation stage cultivator wouldn’t underestimate. Even with that, Yuan Cha was using devilish Qi to control them, so their might should be even greater.

However, these two successive attacks were withstood by a mere mid-Nascent Soul cultivator — an inconceivable result!

At that moment, the black light faded away from the altar as did the huge wolf’s form, instead taking on the form of a gorgeous black-robed woman.

In addition to her black robes, she wore armor of sinister design. It was jet-black with a two-horned ghost engraved on it. Several foot-long spikes pierced out sporadically from various parts of the armor, glistening with an eerie light.

She was now glaring right at Han Li.

He gasped in alarm. “That’s-”

“- The Elder Devil’s True Fiend Armor, only capable of being used when a large quantity of perfect devil Qi is condensed in a fully devilfied body,” Silvermoon explained, “Not only is it incredibly durable, but it also gives her a second source to draw devilish Qi from, greatly increasing her abilities. In the ancient war, the demon and human clans had suffered greatly at the hands of this armor. Fortunately, only a small portion of Elder Devil were able to use this ability, or there would’ve been no war in the first place.”

“You remembered that?” Han Li spoke with surprise. Then, he commanded the puppet to take out the silver nail that was still embedded in its body. Immediately afterwards, rainbow light stirred from its body and the wounds were slowly repaired. At the same time, the Gold Devouring Beetles surrounding his abdomen stirred before closing the gap in his armor.

He even withdrew the small silver shield and had it return to its small original form as a small silver shield.

Silvermoon wryly laughed, “I’m not too sure of how much I recall, but it’s slowly coming back to me. A few of my more vague memories have become clearer, and I know much more.”

Han Li’s face stirred but he remained silent. And with the puppet fully repaired, it blurred to his side.

Yuan Cha slowly withdrew her gaze and turned to look at the confrontation of radiant and black light. With an odd expression on her face, she formed a hand gesture and uttered an incantation with a sweet voice before flicking her fingers.

Ten unremarkable black threads struck the giant stone tablet that contained the Dragon Call Crest. A series of black light began to wind around it and a loud drone thrummed out.

The stone pillars surrounding the altar shook with increasing violence.

Now with a far more stern bearing, she dropped her hair over her face, making for an eerie appearance. The alter below her immediately trembled and black light flickered from its surface as it slowly crumbled. Countless strands of pitch-black Qi then began to rush into the pillars backs.

When she saw this, she became crazed and broke out into a satisfied laughter. She pointed to the sky and shouted with a shrill voice, “Shatter!”

Black Qi gathered together above the altar and roiled to form a huge devil the size of a building.

The devil possessed the body of a gorgeous woman, but her eyes were closed. It wore the exact same armor as Yuan Cha’s incarnation did, had a delicate face, and a pair of short exquisite horns.

“Devil Ancestor Yuan Cha!” Corpse Xiong cried out with shock.

The others were also greatly alarmed. In the next instant, the huge devil slowly opened its eyes, to reveal a pair of twinkling purple abysses, like the endless void.

Just as it so happened, the combined attack of the three spirit treasure replicas broke through the wall of black light, collapsing it into countless rays.

The blazing radiance continued to rush forward, shining down upon the altar as if to envelope it in a curtain of light.

When the giant devil sensed this, it shifted its head towards the approaching light and casually lifted its hand and gave an effortless slap.

A huge explosion ruptured.

A giant black monstrous claw appeared in the air, grasping at the attack like clouds covering the moon. In a short flash, five black streaks cut through the curtain of light, completely blocking it until they found a large jade block and a small crimson drum in its grasp. In that moment, all light from the attack had faded away.

Everyone who saw it was dumbstruck.

The huge devil lowered its head with a cursory glance at the two treasures in its hand as its eyes flickered with purple light. Then, with a trace of confusion, an icy woman’s voice sounded from its mouth, “This... This is... the mortal realm?”

At that moment, Long Meng’s possessed body had condensed a silver wolf head on Hua Tianqi’s back in preparation for leaping out.

But when she saw the newly arrived huge devil in the distance, the silver wolf burrowed back into Hua Tianqi’s body. Long Meng woke up with frightened eyes and trembling body, shrieking, “Spatial Soul Crossing! That is Yuan Cha’s true soul!”

Complete shock was betrayed from the faces of the cultivators.

Master Sable and Daoist Sevenwonders had bloodless complexions. The devil claws quitely lit up with a purple flame that instantly evaporated the treasures it held.

Two Divine Spirit Treasure replicas, destroyed with laughable ease.

Afterwards, the giant devil withdrew its arms and slowly turned around to face the black-armored woman.

The woman expressionlessly met the giant’s gaze and giant devil noted, “So you still live. It seems my past efforts haven’t been in vain. So you summoned me here to deal with insects? Do you believe that my efforts are worth this much? You should know that you’ve already called me twice in the past. After this, I will be erasing you. The perfect devil Qi I used to create you here may as well be used to refine another… more reliable group of our holy race.”

With a raised brow, the black-armored woman coldly replied, “We are of the same being. I wouldn’t have done this unless I had no other choice. If it weren’t for the assistance of the True Devil Qi leaking from the altar and my desperate circumstances, I wouldn’t have been able to summon you.”

The huge devil looked down at the steady flow of black Qi from the altar and nodded, “So it was like that! Gathering me here had taken up much energy. So it wasn’t your personal devilish Qi that summoned me. It appears I’ll need to act quickly. I don’t know how long I can be sustained.” She then turned her head to look at the demons and cultivators.

Under the devil’s frigid gaze, many of them even began to silently back away in terror.

The devil gave a sadistic smile at the sight of their squirming and raised her hand before flicking her finger.

A shriek sounded out as a blur faded from sight.

The Lion Hawk that was tangling with the huge devil bird let out a miserable scream. Its body inflated for a moment before imploding.

Translator's Thoughts

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1067: Vortex

The black streak that was launched from the puppet was the knife made from a Devil Essence Diamond, the very last of the treasures in Han Li’s reserves.

Only a moment after it was released, it arrived before the giant sphere of black wind.

Soon it entered, and the black winds came to life and the many vortexes within the sphere began to violently stir, the surface visibly warping. The spiritual pressure emitted became chaotic like a volcano on the verge of eruption.

This scene caused Yuan Cha’s smile to freeze. When Ling Long saw this, she was reminded of something and she sighed with a faint smile.

“Impossible! How can a single knife disturb the Black Wind Flag?” Yuan Cha shouted in disbelief. She couldn't continue her incantation with the sphere on the verge of collapse and was forced to point at the black ball in her hand, striking it with a grey spell seal.

Wind tore apart the air and the black ball trembled, channelling a beam of light into the huge wind vortex above it.

Han Li’s expression sank and he had his puppet release a spell seal as well. The knife grew in size before wildly flailing around inside the sphere, disturbing any remote stability it might have gained.

“You’re courting death!” The black-armored woman grew furious at his action and reached out her hand in Han Li’s direction, condensing a massive spiritual pressure above him.

Han Li’s heart trembled as he immediately thought to move, but Ling Long had acted sooner. She gently waved her hand in his direction, resulting in a resounding boom. A black devil claw and the white hand collided in midair, producing glittering black-white light and crackles of tearing space.

“Did you forget that I’m here too?” Ling Long smiled, rigidly staring at Yuan Cha.

With an expression as cold as ice, Yuan Cha remained silent. She knew that Ling Long didn’t have a physical body and received a heavy injury from her original self, but she still wasn’t an enemy she could easily face.

“So it seems it’ll take some time before victory is certain, I can’t delay this any longer!” Yuan Cha saw that the giant wind sphere was about to lose control and took a deep breath. Then, her figure blurred, disappearing like a wisp of smoke.

Ling Long paused, then wore a harsh expression in realization. Her head of silver hair flicked forward, shooting towards an empty space beneath the sphere.

But before her silver hair arrived, black Qi suddenly condensed to form a three-meter-large black wolf with two heads.

The wolf revealed surprise upon seeing silver hairs shoot towards it, but it soon turned to disdain. It shook its body and released spikes of sparkling black fur from its back like a barrage of arrows. As the attacks collided, deafening clangs rang from the air.

The wolf then used this opportunity to dive straight into the sphere of wind.

The sphere violently trembled for just a moment before it became entirely stabilized.

At the same time, Han Li sensed that the black knife became slowed as if it had sunk into a pit of tar.

In his alarm, he ordered the puppet to channel all of its spiritual power into the knife to forcibly recall it. But an icy snort sounded from the sphere, and the knife trembled before losing connection with the puppet’s spiritual sense.

Without another thought, he clapped his hands together and raised them, releasing two foot-thick bolts of lightning in the air. Meanwhile, the flying swords circling in front of them vibrated before roaring with thunder. Countless arcs of lightning leapt between them and condensed together into one sixty-meter-long flood dragon.

The dragon of dancing lightning roared ceaselessly as soon and brandished claws and fangs as it appeared. As soon as the dragon took form, Han Li commanded it in overbearingly charge at the giant wind sphere.

His grand and imposing use of the Divine Devilbane Lightning was well noticed by everyone.

The giant sphere of black wind was condensed from pure devilish Qi. If it were struck by the lightning, they would dissipate, given that Yuan Cha didn’t pull any further tricks.

Currently caught in a deadlock fighting off the black spikes, Ling Long gasped upon seeing the lightning dragon.

Although she had some understanding of the power of Han Li’s Divine Devilbane Lightning from Silvermoon’s memories, this was the first time she personally witnessed it. The lightning's might came as a shock to her.

Within the sphere, the two-headed wolf had restrained the black knife using a transparent ooze. When she saw the golden dragon roll forth its eyes stained crimson and both of its heads released beams of red light.

In the blink of an eye, the two attacks collided. Suddenly lightning wildly danced and the stench of blood choked the air. The blood managed to hold off the lightning for the time being.

When Ling Long saw the red light, she tensely scowled and furiously shouted, “You dare to destroy my body like this?”

The crimson beam was the wolf body’s blood essence. It was only natural that its sacrificial use would anger its original master.

“Why should I give any consideration to a body with a dead owner?” Yuan Cha sneered, but her voice sounded far weaker than before.

Ling Long’s face warped from anger, but she soon calmed down, “How arrogant! Your spiritual sense is no longer at Deity Transformation stage. Will you still be able to detonate the Black Wind Flag? And even so, could it even break the seal?”

“Should you already know that?” Yuan Cha looked down at the ball of light at the altar and sinisterly smiled. It had been fueling the wind sphere with devilish Qi this entire them. She then set her plan into motion.

The huge sphere dazzlingly flared with black radiance and a loud shriek whistled. All of the vortexes contained within combined into a single thirty-meter-wide vortex that flickered with light. The two-headed wolf was at the center, breathing out black radiance onto a small black flag.

Soon after, the vortex emitted an astonishing spiritual pressure, followed by clouds of rainbow light being released.

As the light swept through the air, it left specks of dust in its wake, only to be later absorbed by the vortex and increasing its power.

The lotus-form of the Eight Spirit Ruler seemed to have reacted and its light faded to return to its original form as a sma;; green wooden ruler. Then with a cry, it summoned eight of its spirit beast phantoms around it, charging into the mist without a trace of hesitation.

Ling Long’s expression vastly changed and she clasped her hand in an incantation gesture, spitting out the Star Defying Plate from her mouth. She then pointed at it and had it spin in the air, quickly growing three-meters-wide.

She pressed her hand on the top of the plate with her fingers stretched out, crystalline light soon flourishing out from her body. Then, golden starlight shined from the surface of the plate and stretched out from its center.

When the two-headed wolf saw the black vortex, it looked down in disgust as if it held her actions in contempt.

At that moment, a great amount of white light had entered the sphere, causing the space nearby it to distort like wrinkled paper. The closer the area to the vortex, the more warped space became.

When Han Li saw this, he felt his breath turn cold. Having witnessed immensely powerful spatial tears in the past, his body blurred as he backed as far as he could in the space containing them, his puppet following suit. While he did this, he also sent a few voice transmissions.

Gui Ling’s and Lin Yinping’s brows fell as they were fighting the three-headed devil to a stalemate. They suddenly retreated towards the back wall of the area.

Corpse Xiong and Daoist Sevenwonders also heard the conversation between Yuan Cha and Ling Long. With the strange changes in the black vortex, they knew that things had turned for the worse. With the retreat from the two women, they followed suit and withdrew in streaks of light.

Having suddenly lost its opponents, the three-headed devil paused in surprise, but it soon flew into a rage and blurred from sight, instantly moving in front of Daoist Sevenwonders. It waved its weapons, forcibly halting his path in an explosion of black light.

Either by the short time the large-headed eccentric had turned into the devil or the corruption of turning into an Elder Devil, he wasn’t particularly clever. After setting its eyes on Sevenwonders, it blinked several times without any restraint on its magic power and began to chase him, preventing him from straying very far from the altar.

Sevenwonders’ heart sank.

Translator's Thoughts

e: akiwimain

Chapter 1069: Escape

Han Li only gave Corpse Xiong and Lin Yinping a glance before turning his focus back at the altar, betraying blatant nervousness from his face.

Intending to destroy the altar’s seal, Yuan Cha’s soul fragment had detonated the Black Wind Flag, enveloping the altar in a giant jet-black void. Although he couldn't see through it, he could sense that a majority of the stone pillars comprising of the spell formation were destroyed.

Han Li stared attentively at the sparkling black light, seeing it rapidly collapse and suddenly disappear, causing his eyes to widen.

Nearly half the altar was now missing, the upper half vanished as if it were cleaved off.

There was now a person floating near the ruins of the altar.

It was Xiang Zhili, covered in a barrier of purple light that was on the verge of collapse.

He was laden with sweat and his face was bloodless as if he had gone through an intense battle.

Two items were floating next to him: the foot-wide Star Defying Plate that was spinning in the air with a golden paste-like barrier surrounding it, and a broken pitch-black stick. Han Li soon recognized it to be a small piece of the Black Wind Flag.

Most of the Divine Spirit Treasure had been annihilated in the eruption. What remained of it sparkled with black light as if its spiritual nature was still intact.

Han Li looked around and saw no sign of Ling Long or the black wolf. As he puzzled over this, the Star Defying Plate spun and released a mist of golden light from its core.

Ling Long emerged from the mist and coldly glared at the remains of the Black Wind Flag, which mirrored the Star Defying Plate and released a cloud of black Qi, quickly condensing into a meter-tall two-headed wolf. The wolf’s fur was dull and eyes listless.

Xiang Zhili’s expression sank at the sight of the two and he took several deep breaths. His pale complexion turned radiant and he wordlessly raised his hand, pointing two fingers towards the wolf.

Two gusts of wind followed, and one gold and one red swordstreak were released, expanding into two celestial dragons overlapping each other as they charged at the wolf.

Xiang Zhili was quick to act. Although he was in the dark as to what had happened, he was certain that the wolf filled with devilish Qi was the devil that had been suppressed in the pagoda. He knew he had to take advantage of this moment of weakness to subdue it.

The wolf scowled at the attack and its two heads spat beams of black light to block the swordlight, but it was clear that the counter wouldn’t prove a match. It had exhausted too much of its devilish Qi detonating the Black Wind Flag.

Surprisingly, the wolf wasn’t afraid. Instead, it gave a sinister glance down at the altar below and suddenly let out a shriek that could shatter even metal.

In the distance, Han Li couldn’t hide his disbelief at what unfolded.

The remains of the altar completely collapsed, leaving nothing behind.

Meanwhile, a pitch-black devilish Qi emerged from the rubble and quickly spread throughout.

“No! The seal was opened!” Corpse Xiong yelled in alarm.

Ling Long’s expression sank.

Although Xiang Zhili wasn’t aware of the circumstances, when he saw so much devilish Qi emerge, he immediately recalled something and his face became unsightly.

Nevertheless, Han Li wordlessly pointed at the huge golden sword floating above his head. It hummed and chopped at the closest point of the space’s wall.

A deep eruption boomed and blinding golden light jutted from the wall, followed by a barrage of crimson arrows from the puppet’s Thunderfire Bow densely targeting the same point.

In the blink of an eye, the wall trembled but it was clear that it was far from breaking.

Han Li’s face shifted grim and he flipped his hand to summon the Triflame Fan. Before he could prepare to use it, a golden streak and two white crescents struck the same spot he targeted.

Startled, Han Li saw that Corpse Xiong and Lin Yinping had arrived nearby and were attacking the wall with hurried and anxious strikes. They also knew their lives was at risk. No matter their desires, they had to preserve their lives first and foremost. Without another word, Han Li joined them and unleashed a tri-colored flame bird from the fan, striking at the surface of the wall.

A nova of flame briefly appeared with talisman characters flickering within it. Then with a series of deafening explosions, the wall finally began to warp.

Under their successive barrage, the wall bent to an extreme degree, but showed no signs of destruction.

Han Li’s expression turned grim and he quickly downed a drop of spirit milk, replenishing his magic power before he continued with the assault.

But at that moment, a yellow streak flew over and stuck to the wall, fading away to reveal a yellow talisman.

Suddenly, a layer of yellow energy covered the entire wall.

Another ball of blinding golden light struck down like a shooting star.

A strange beast wrapped in raging golden flames took form from the light.

With a huge quake, the wall was rent in two, peeking traces of light from the outside.

Pleasantly surprised, Han Li moved without another thought and shot out into the hole, his human puppet following suit.

His surroundings lit up and he found himself in a large familiar hall. Several streaks followed behind him and circled in the air once before stopping.

They were Lin Yinping, Corpse Xiong, and Xiang Zhili.

The large hall was the seventh floor of the Devil Suppressing Pagoda.

Han Li looked at Xiang Zhili with astonishment, but he simply chuckled at Han Li and said nothing else.

But at that moment, the mass of golden light that earlier struck the wall flew out as well. It was Ling Long holding the Star Defying Plate above her hand.

Xiang Zhili opened his mouth and closed it again. He mustered his words once more, but nothing came out.

The hole in the wall rapidly shrank and mended in the blink of an eye.

Then, the people in the hall glanced at each other cautiously, a stifling silence filling the empty space.

Ling Long took a glance at Han Li and Xiang Zhili, breaking the silence with a snort, “How long are we going to remain? Once that devil absorbs enough devilish Qi, we’re dead.”

Xiang Zhili hesitated for a moment and doubtfully asked, “Are you Senior Long Meng?”

In the past, he had been sealed by the fused soul of Long Meng and Yuan Cha. The woman before him gave him a different impression from before.

“You know quite a bit. Did the three Kunwu Masters leave behind an explanation? This so-called Long Meng was only a portion of my being.” Ling Long bluntly responded.

Such a vague explanation left Xiang Zhili blinking in confusion.

Ling Long frowned and sent him a voice transmission. The few words left Xiang Zhili shocked. With a glint of realization in his eyes, he took another glance at her, using his spiritual sense to confirm the woman didn’t have any devilish Qi present on her. His expression relaxed and he hastily bowed, saying, “My greetings, Imperial Concubine Ling Long. The three masters had left me behind some information with regards to your imprisonment. They had been forced to keep you here, as a portion of your soul had fused with that devil soul. They didn’t dare to release you.”

Long Meng coldly said, “ Humph , leave that matter for when I return to the spirit realm. You had better focus on how we’ll control the situation. Once my body is immersed in perfect devil Qi in three days time, it will become thoroughly corrupted. When that time comes, the devil will have restored its abilities, and raising an army once she escapes should prove a trivial matter. The entire mortal realm will be engulfed in war once more.”

Xiang Zhili shugged and wryly smiled, “I know a small bit about how fearsome the true devil Qi is. Once this devil restores its original power, I fear there is no one left capable of stopping it. The ninth floor is also now flooded with devilish Qi, meaning the devil will be able to easily avoid us as it restores its strength. How about we retreat for the time being? Of the Worldbreaker Talismans I took from my sect, I only have two left.”

When Ling Long heard this, she began to ponder.

Lin Yinping couldn't help but ask, “You mean to say we aren’t able to seal the devil Qi once more?”

Xiang Zhili shook his head and sighed, “As if matters would be so easy. The original seal is broken, and the devil destroyed the Dragon Call Crest just as we left. If we had that crest, we would’ve been able to activate the reserve sealing formation and suppress the devil, but now...”

Silence filled the hall once more.

Han Li then calmly said, “Since there is a spell formation in reserve, in their vast wisdom, the ancient cultivators should have prepared a spare magic tool to control it too.”

Chapter 1070: Reverse Spirit Stream

Xiang Zhili paused in surprise, but then shook his head and said, “Indeed! Since there is a spare spell formation, the ancient cultivators should’ve prepared an alternative means to control it, but the magic tool’s whereabouts were unknown. It is said to be hidden in an unremarkable place on the mountain. Only one of the descendants of the Kunwu Masters knew of its location. However, these descendants have long concealed their identity. What are we to do?”

Ling Long bitterly said, “ Humph , those old fogies were too careful.”

Lin Yinping and Corpse Xiong wore worried expressions when they heard this. Han Li frowned and asked, “Was this tool also styled like an imperial seal?”

“No, it was called the Heavencrystal Stele,” Xiang Zhili casually replied, “With that, we’ll be able to use the reserve sealing formation.”

Han Li’s face changed, and in his surprise, he recalled the slab he acquired from the mountain gate. Wasn’t that name inscribed on it?

Ling Long’s gaze casually brushed past him as well when this was spoken.

Han Li felt his heart drop.

“Since there is nothing that can be done, let us first try to leave the mountain. The devil won’t be able to escape in a matter of a few days. Let’s take this opportunity to gather those near Nanjiang and place down a large formation to reseal the mountain for the time being. Afterwards, I’ll gather all of the sects of the Great Jin here. Although the devil will be immensely powerful with the devilish Qi, with hoards of cultivators attacking it, there is no reason it wouldn’t perish. As for the true devil Qi, we can turn the surrounding thousands of kilometers into a restricted area while we think of a way to contain it.” With Xiang Zhili’s experience, it only took a moment for him to come up with a plan.

Corpse Xiong let out a long breath and he politely replied, “Fellow Daoist Xiang’s words are quite reasonable. I will return to Myriad Demon Valley and make a report to the valley lord. This matter doesn’t only concern humans.”

“Oh! If your valley were to take action, our odds of victory will be far greater. I’ve long heard of Fellow Daoist Che’s might in particular. Its a shame I never had an opportunity to greet him as he has always remained in seclusion!” Xiang Zhili spoke with a smile.

Corpse Xiong dryly laughed and he eyes changed direction. He gave Ling Long a respectful bow and said, “Imperial Concubine, our valley lord said that he was an acquaintance of yours! He...” with that said, he sent the rest of his message to her through voice transmission.

Ling Long’s calm expression stirred and her eyes betrayed surprise.

“It’s him! I wonder how he knew it was I who was sealed here!” Ling Long muttered a few words as she mulled over the matter, a tired and aged look on her face.

Corpse Xiong sincerely said, “Since the Imperial Concubine already knows the identity of our valley lord, wouldn’t it be better for you to stay with us at Myriad Demon Valley for some time. With countless demons and variants, we’ll be able to select an appropriate body for you.”

“I have no interest in leaving Kunwu Mountain. In a moment, I will be returning to the ninth floor.” Those in the room thought they misheard her.

“The Imperial Concubine wishes to return inside? How can that be?” Corpse Xiong cried out.

“That’s right, but it won’t be me alone,” she pointed at Han Li and said, “He will be accompanying me. This person’s Divine Devilbane Lightning will prove useful.”

Han Li betrayed surprise, but that soon neutralized.

Xiang Zhili gave Han Li a strange glance and couldn't help but ask, “Senior Ling Long, surely you jest? Why would you do something so dangerous?”

“We are different,” Ling Long coldly stated, “I originally came from the spirit realm in my true body. Even if my cultivation is restored to late Deity Transformation-stage, I will not be able to return to the spirit realm unless I retrieve my true body. Once that is done, I’ll return through a reverse spirit stream. This time, I’ll prepare to use the innate ability of the Silvermoon Wolves. By relying on this, I should have a half-chance of taking back my body.”

“This... please reconsider!” Corpse Xiong wore a hesitant expression.

Xiang Zhili urged against this as well.

Ling Long simply brushed the hair from her face and smirked, “I know that you’ve been wanting me to share with you the whereabouts of a reverse spirit stream. You fear that you’ll lose your chance if I go in!”

When they heard this, Corpse Xiong appeared embarrassed, but Xiang Zhili remained unphased and denied her claim.

Ling Long carelessly stated, “Enough. Although there are many humans and demons that descended upon this world, likely none of them know the details of reverse spirit streams. Even in the spirit realm, they weren’t something those of common cultivation could touch. These reverse spirit streams possess no fixed position or existence.”

Han Li’s eyes flickered as if he were paying attention to what was happening before him. However, his spiritual sense was focused on the Heavencrystal Stele in his storage pouch. To the side, Lin Yinping’s attention was completely enraptured by their secret conversation about the reverse spirit stream.

“What do you mean they have no fixed existence?” Xiang Zhili quietly asked with a grave expression.

“It’s quite simple. Reverse spirit streams are temporary passages that we created using the power of heaven and earth. The passage that has brought us here has long ceased to exist.” Ling Long coldly said.

“Impossible!” Corpse Xiong quickly shouted, “I clearly saw people who were returning to the spirit world after the war. Without reverse spirit streams, how could this have been done?”

Ling Long indifferently said, “You forget that the ancient cultivators of the mortal realm contacted the spirit realm for assistance during the invasion of the Elder Devils.”

“...Realm Whisper Incense!” Xiang Zhili furrowed his brow.

“Yes, when those people returned, they ignited the incense to inform the spirit realm to open a passage. Even if you somehow managed to acquire the ritual, would you know anyone in the spirit realm willing to open a passage? A vast amount of peak-grade spirit stones are used in the creation of a reverse spirit stream. Even if the humans and demons joined hands, it will be an impossible task to accomplish.” Ling Long’s words dashed Corpse Xiong’s last hopes.

“But then, how does your Imperial Highness intend on returning to the spirit realm?” Xiang Zhili calmly asked.

“I am the concubine of the Wolf Monarch Tian Kui and the high princess of the Silvermoon Wolves. My circumstances are different. My body and spiritual sense have the imprint of a Star Defying Plate. So long as I can take back my body, I can activate the power of the imprint. An elder in my clan placed down a formation that is activated by the power of the Star Defying Plate, even across realms. This would forcefully open a small-scale reverse spirit stream to take me back. The passage will be for me alone. If others attempt to take it without the imprint, their bodies would immediately be destroyed by the passage’s spatial distortions. Were it not for the sudden possession of Yuan Cha’s soul fragment and the separation of my soul, I would’ve long since returned to the spirit realm,” Ling Long spoke with a bitter tone.

Corpse Xiong glanced at the plate in Ling Long’s hand and bewilderedly said, “An imprint? The Star Defying Plate in your hand isn’t its true body? I suspected that this legendary treasure was far too weak.”

Xiang Zhili’s smile faded and his expression turned grim.

His hopes of several hundred years had been completely crushed.

At that moment, Han Li grew vigilant and stealthily took several steps back. He didn’t know if anything would soon happen.

Corpse Xiong sighed and asked with a desperate tone, “Could it be that unless one reached late-Deity Transformation stage, there are no other methods to ascension?

Ling Long saw their earnest gazes and smiled. With a particularly charming bearing, she said, “Of course not. Apart from reverse spirit streams, there is only one other method, but it is only feasible in theory. Few have ever succeeded with this method as a vast majority dies in the attempt. Do you want to hear it?”

When Han Li saw this, he felt his mouth grow dry, and he immediately utilized the Great Development Technique in his fright, stabilizing his shaken mind.

“Of course I want to hear it,” Xiang Zhily hurriedly answered, “Even if there is a danger, I’d rather take the risk than to wait for my death staying idle.”

Corpse Xiong repeatedly nodded his head.

“I can tell you, but there is a price. I will need you two to lend something to me to help me reclaim my body!” A sly expression appeared on Ling Long’s face.

“Lend you something?”

Xiang Zhili and Corpse Xiong were stunned.

“That’s right,” Ling Long muttered, “The Devil Dragon Blade replica and Fellow Daoist Xiang’s two Worldbreaker Talismans.”

Translator's Thoughts

e:akiwimain

Chapter 1079: North Night Island

The Snowchain mountains have been enveloped in silent cold for over ten years.

Everyone in the region knew that a vastly powerful expert was cultivating on the mountain. Naturally, no one dared to travel near the area and the mountains remained undisturbed.

When the nearby factions saw that this expert was only looking for a place to cultivate and had done nothing else, they were relieved.

One day, a heavy snowstorm assailed the Snowchain mountains with ferocious winds and dandelion-sized snowflakes. As the storm concealed the mountain from view, a foot layer of snow quickly blanketed it.

Such a large snowstorm was uncommon in even in such an icy climate. Even lower-grade cultivators were unwilling to brave the weather, but it was then that a dazzling azure streak broke through the air and flickered out of sight.

Two hours later, an azure streak appeared tens of thousands of kilometers away, near a mountain range far from the Snowchain mountains. The light faded from the streak to reveal Han Li.

Having cultivated for over ten years, he had fully refined all of his treasures and even took the Great Yin Trueflame into his body, completing the first stage of its cultivation. With all of this prepared, there would be nothing that posed a threat apart from an attack from many late-Nascent Soul cultivators or a fearsome existence on the level of the Devil Ancestor Yuan Cha.

Not only was his cultivation and abilities far greater than when he entered Kunwu Mountain, the cinque devils and treasures he acquired should allow him to fight several late-Nascent Soul cultivators on fair ground.

After so many years passed, he reckoned that the Kunwu Mountain commotion should’ve died down and decided to make his way to his next destination, North Night Island.

When half a month passed, cultivators would begin to discover that the white mist covering the Snowchain Mountains had disappeared, and had become completely uninhabited.

Following the appearance of a suddenly uncontested spirit vein, the nearby factions broke out into war.

...

North Night Island was actually a peninsula a prefecture away from the Shuang Region.

Additionally, rather than being a peninsula surrounded by water, it was surrounded by endless sheets of ice with glaciers embedded between them. Due to the extreme temperatures caused by this environment, even high-grade cultivators didn’t dare to tread outside without protection.

North Night Island was hundred thousands of kilometers long with a giant city of ice at the island’s northmost edge. It was North Night Palace, the greatest sect in the north.

In truth, the sect’s power was no weaker than the top ten devilish and righteous sects of the Great Jin. But because North Night Island was located in what was considered wilderness, the many sects didn’t recognize the palace as part of the Great Jin, regarding it as an overseas sect and discluding it from the ranking of sects in the Great Jin.

But in the sparsely populated northern regions of the Great Jin, the North Night Palace was even more famous than the top sects of the Great Jin mainland, the Heavenly Devil Sect and the High Zenith Sect. There was no doubt they were the top sect of the north.

In the northern regions, the sect was also known by the name of the North Immortal Palace. Countless low-grade vagrant cultivators wished to enter it.

North Night Palace was also divided between inner and outer divisions. The inner palace disciples chosen from several great cultivator clans in the region. As for the outer palace disciples, they were chosen from smaller clans and vagrant cultivators from outside the peninsula. Of course, if an outer palace disciple displayed immense talent or achieved great merits, they had the opportunity to become an inner palace disciple.

And if one lacked aptitude and still wished to join the outer palace, it would require one to tread the thousands of kilometers of frost surrounding North Night Palace on foot.

Since these low-grade cultivators couldn't fly due to the restrictions in the area, they would have to rely on their abilities and cultivation to block the glacial cold. As such, if they would be admitted into the outer palace if they managed to reach it.

No matter what they relied on to cross the harsh temperatures, this accomplishment would display some redeeming qualities.

Of course, there still weren’t many cultivators that succeeded. Many would freeze trying. But for their quest to tread the path of cultivation, the cultivators were drawn like moths to the flame.

One day in a region thousands of kilometers away from North Night Palace, there were over ten figures each covered in fur cloaks. Their bodies sparkled with light as they slowly made their way forward on foot inside a vicious snowstorm.

These people have been threading in the frost for over half a month. Their complexions were deathly pale and their footsteps were unsteady. However, none of them dared to stop and rest. The cold wouldn’t allow it. They could only forcefully sustain themselves with magic stones and power.

But one of these travelers had a particularly unsightly expression and his breath was ragged. After a moment, he gritted his teeth and took out a medicine bottle from his robe, putting a scarlet medicine pill into his mouth and soon restoring a bit of color to his pale face.

The middle-aged man in front was covered in a deep yellow light barrier. Without turning his head, he knowingly said, “Fellow Daoist Gu, how many Yang Fire Pills do you have? If you can take them regularly, you might have a problem reaching North Night Palace. Future hailstorms will prove several times harsher than the one we just passed.”

The cultivator who took the medicine pill was a youth in his twenties. He forced a smile and said, “Brother Gu, don’t worry. I still have a bottle in reserve. I’ll be able to make it past!” He seemed somewhat fearful towards the middle-aged man.

“That will be good. I don’t want to travel together with a person without a chance.” As if satisfied with the youth’s reply, light flickered from his body and he continued forward.

When the others saw this, they hastily head on their way. It was almost as if sticking close to this person was their only chance at entering North Night Palace.

When the middle-aged man took several steps forward, he let out a yelp and his steps came to a sudden halt, then turning his head to look above.

When the others followed his gaze, they discovered an azure silhouette floating in the sky amidst the snowstorm. Strangely enough, there was an invisible force keeping the snowstorm ten meters at bay.

The middle-aged man was quite exceptional to discover this person in the air.

All of the cultivators present were alarmed and soon their expressions changed. Even Core Formation cultivators shouldn't be able to fly unaffected by the area’s restrictions. Could it be that this person was a legendary Nascent Soul cultivator? Or was it a high-grade cultivator from North Night Palace? But their attire seemed foreign!

The cultivators looked at each other in dismay, apprehension filling their hearts.

“You are vagrant cultivators looking to enter North Night Palace?” The silhouette glowing in azure light spoke with a young voice.

Although the middle-aged man’s cultivation wasn’t very high, he knew much of the world and his mind was roused upon hearing this person’s question. He promptly bowed and hastily answered, “This Junior’s name is Gu Tianqu. I am one of those undergoing the trial to join. Does Senior have any commands?” As he spoke, he wore an expression of solemn respect.

The azure figure calmly said, “You are quite discerning, but I don’t have orders in particular. It's just that this land is strange and I can’t seem to figure out my way forward. Since you are certain of your path, do you have something to guide you?”

When the middle-aged man heard this, his expression relaxed, but he still hurriedly replied, “It seems this is Senior’s first time at North Night Island. Other areas of North Night Island are easy enough to tread, but this region is under the influence of the palace’s grand formation."

"It uses renown Mythic Serpent Stone as the formation’s core, causing a cultivator’s spiritual sense to sway in different directions. If anyone were to think they were flying straight, I fear that would never reach the palace. As for Juniors like us, we’ve each bought a Soul Stabilizing Medallion from the market at North Night Island’s entrance. With this magic tool, our sense of direction won’t stray.”

The azure figure seemed stunned. “A Soul Stabilizing Medallion?”

“Yes, although it isn’t a rare magic tool, it is required to make it to the palace. It is sold by a shop from the palace. Furthermore, there are only thirty that are sold throughout a year and they lose effectiveness when the year passes. In order to be safe, I purchased an extra medallion. May I offer it to Senior?” The middle-aged man’s eyes shifted and he took out a yellow plate from his sleeve. He then held it forward with both hands.

The azure silhouette stroked his chin and chuckled, reaching out towards it without any reservations.

In a yellow flash, the medallion was summoned into his hand.

Needless to say, the azure silhouette was Han Li, who had flown to North Night Island in about a month’s time.

Originally, he believed he would be able to easily overcome the sect’s restrictions with his abilities, but when he arrived at the palace, he couldn't have imagined that his spiritual sense would lapse. For a time, he wasn’t able to find the palace’s location, much to his surprise and irritation.

Because he had come here to pay a friendly visit, it wasn’t as if he could break through the restrictions with violent force.

Unable to come up with a better option, he happened upon a group of people.

Chapter 1081: The Black Dragon Border

“I am surnamed Han. I was invited by Fairy Bai, so I thought to pay her a visit.” Han Li calmly answered.

The elder surnamed Ren muttered to himself for a moment and then wore a trace of realization, “So it was Brother Han? Could it be you’re talking about Junior Martial Sister Bai Yaoyi?”

“That is right.” Han Li replied.

A glint flashed through the cultivator’s eye and he eagerly said, “That is good. I was planning on visiting her as soon as I returned to the palace. Would you like me to bring you?”

Han Li’s expression remained unchanged, but he felt somewhat odd over his enthusiasm.

Before Han Li could think of a reply, a red light flashed from the distance and quickly arrived towards them.

“Its a voice transmission talisman from Senior Bai!” Shi Yun quickly explained, grabbing ahold of the flame in his hand.

When Han Li heard this, he had an excuse to swallow his reply.

After catching the fiery streak, Shi Yun quickly read it with his spiritual sense and respectfully address Han Li, “Senior Han, Martial Aunt Bai is happy to see you. She has already left seclusion and is waiting to see you at the Pure Focus Pavilion.”

Elder Ren rushed to say, “Shi Yun, continue to watch your station. I will guide him.”

When Shi Yun heard this, he didn’t dare to oppose him.

Han Li frowned but found it awkward to refuse him. He could only nod and said, “Then I will have to trouble you. Elder Ren.”

“Haha, Junior Martial Sister Bai and I are close friends. Since you are a good friend of Junior Martial Sister Bai, then you are a good friend of mine! Please, follow me,” Elder Ren courteously said. He then flew off in a red streak.

Han Li followed him without reservation.

Elder Ren suddenly asked, “Is this the first time you’ve arrived at North Night Palace?”

“Yes, it is. Your palace is worthy of being the top sect of the north. It is truly imposing like no other,” Han Li said with a chuckle.

When Elder Ren heard this, he wore a satisfied grin and said, “Brother Han exaggerates his praise. But if the palace wasn’t in such a remote palace, we truly would be on par with the ten great Righteous and Devilish sects. Ah yes, Junior Martial Sister Bai did go on a journey over ten years ago but other than that, she’s remained in seclusion. That must’ve been when you met her. With such deep cultivation, you must belong to a sect. I won’t hide this. Although the palace is located in the extreme north, I often travel throughout the Great Jin, so I know quite a few fellow Daoists.”

Han Li laughed and looked at him with a mysterious smile, “I didn’t come from the Great Jin. It is no wonder you haven’t heard of it. If you ask Fairy Bai, she’ll know more about it.”

“Hehe, is that so. I was wondering how a high-grade cultivator appeared in the Great Jin without anyone knowing about him.” Ren Bi appeared displeased by his reply and gave a hollow chuckle. After all, finding out that Han Li wasn’t from a Great Jin was a gain in itself.

When the two arrived at the entrance of the ice city, they ceased their flight.

A faint mist covered the entire city, the only exception being a giant mountain. It was clearly an extremely powerful formation.

As he stood beneath the city of ice, Han Li found it increasingly gorgeous.

The hundred-meter-tall wall of ice surrounding the city wasn’t exceptional in height, but its translucent and sparkling material was mesmerizing.

But what was particularly eye-catching was that the wall appeared entirely smooth as if it was carved out from a blade. There wasn’t the slightest hint that bricks had ever been used.

At the city gate, there were a dozen white-clothed cultivators standing guard.

The highest cultivation among them was at Foundation Establishment cultivation, but more notably, several white apes were squatting amongst them. They had long snow-white hair and a pair of menacing green eyes.

The apes were spirit beasts that were long acclimated to the snow. Although their cultivation wasn’t very high, they were exceptionally intelligent and easy to tame, leading to many northern cultivators raising them.

However, the apes on the walls were particularly large, several times larger than one would expect of a snow ape, and their demonic Qi revealed them to be rank four and five demon beasts, equivalent to the power of a Foundation Establishment cultivator.

This attracted much attention to Han Li. As the top sect in the north, the Night Night Palace should have an original technique to nurture these apes.

When the cultivators on the walls saw the pale youth with a headful of gray hair, they repeatedly addressed him as “Martial Ancestor Ren”.

Elder Ren grunted in acknowledgment and boldly walked through the gates.

When they saw Han Li following behind their martial ancestor, they didn’t dare to question them.

But just as Han Li crossed the gate, the snow apes suddenly acted strangely.

The spirit beasts whined and backed away from Han Li in a panic.

In their alarm, the North Night Palace cultivators scolded the beasts, but the apes continued, lying on their chest and covering the back of their head with their arms, showing submission to Han Li.

When Elder Ren saw this, he yelped and shot Han Li a glance with an odd expression. “Do you have a high-grade ape-type spirit beast? Although these apes aren’t very powerful, their senses are exceptionally keen.”

When Han Li heard this, he knew the snow apes sensed the Weeping Soul Beast and they acted out of fear. He indifferently answered, “I do have one, but it isn’t all that powerful. I rarely ever use it.”

Elder Ren smiled and dropped the matter as they entered the city of ice.

The city’s main road started from the city gate and was exceptionally wide. A layer of smooth ice paved its surface.

In the distance, one could see a few people on the roads, all low-grade cultivators wearing yellow and white.

Buildings lined the side of the road in an orderly fashion. Rather than a city, it was more appropriate to call it a fortress.

Before Han Li could further examine the city, Elder Ren flew in the direction of the huge mountain at a low altitude.

Han Li’s face betrayed a trace of surprise and he silently took off after him.

A short while later, the two landed on a platform at the center of the mountain.

Elder Ren beamed at Han Li and explained, “From now on, Brother Han must follow me on foot as the upper portion of the mountain enters the scope of the inner palace. I am an elder there, but even I must adhere to the rules.”

Han Li nodded, and the two slowly made their way up a flight of translucent stairs carved from ice.

There weren’t many disciples that were allowed to enter the inner palace, but the few people they met along the way respectfully saluted the pale youth.

Additionally, the elder treated these disciples differently and smiled at them no matter their level of cultivation.

Han Li perceived that these inner palace cultivators all possessed exceptional aptitudes, and along the way, he discovered four fearsome restrictions that gave him a shiver down his back. It appeared the sect possessed an ingenious spell formation grandmaster.

This piqued Han Li’s interest in the sect even more. He would have to see whether or not he could converse formation insights with the said expert.

As the thoughts appeared in his head, he followed the pale youth to a more obscure path. When they reached the end, they stood before a giant wall of ice that was a kilometer tall.

When Han Li spotted it, he raised his brow and looked at it with slight awe.

The pale youth raised his hand and he released a jade tile glowing with green light. A silver mist emerged and wrapped around it before phasing into the wall of ice.

A moment later, the wall silently trembled and an opening split through the middle, creating a six-meter-wide passage.

Elder Ren shook his head and explained, “The buildings on the top of the mountain are only for show. In truth, they’re used as residences for the inner sect’s low-grade cultivators. Higher grade disciples reside in Hidden Arctic Dragon Border, the true location of our palace. Were you not a good friend of Junior Martial Sister Bai, I wouldn’t have dared bring you here.”

Han Li wore a smile in response, but he was indifferent about the matter. This so-called Hidden Arctic Dragon Border was well known in the north. It could hardly be considered a secret. Otherwise, why would this Elder Ren bring him here, or for Bai Yaoyi to tell him about this place?

More notably was how this person made such efforts to befriend him, despite being the first time they had met. This puzzled Han Li and caused him to view Elder Ren with greater caution.

But when Han Li was offered passage inside, he didn’t refuse and walked inside shoulder to shoulder with Elder Ren.

The passage was only three meters long. He couldn't help but betray shock from his face after what he saw at the other end.

There was a verdant valley filled with spring life. It was filled with bright sunlight and rarely seen plants.

The valley spanned a couple of kilometers and was enclosed in the green mountain walls. However, there were several jade buildings constructed against the walls in a display of beautiful and impeccable craftsmanship.

At the very center of the valley, there were three large halls carved from white jade that seemed to take up a third of the valley’s space.

Han Li glanced at them with a slight change in expression but astonishment filled his heart.

Translator's Thoughts

The text for chapters 1080 and 1079 have been fixed.

Chapter 1082: Ice Spirit Fruit

‘Heavenvoid Hall?’ In his alarm, a thought resounded through Han Li’s mind.

The three jade palace halls shared the exact same style as the Scattered Star Sea’s Heavenvoid Hall.

There were carved from single portions of fine jade and shined with a faint gorgeous light.

However, these buildings were only a third of the size of Heavenvoid Hall when he saw it floating in the air.

Han Li forcefully stifled his surprise and took another look. Eventually, he concluded that his impression was correct and that there was no doubt a relationship between the three buildings and Heavenvoid Hall. However, the gates to the halls laid bare as there were no signs on top of them.

With a raised brow, Han Li asked, “This is the sect’s inner palace? It is in place of rich spiritual Qi as expected, but the three large halls appear quite aged. What's the history behind them?”

Elder Ren glanced at the three buildings and answered, “You’re talking about Spirit Void Halls? These three buildings were here before the sect was established. It was said that the sect ancestor and several of his good friends used their vast abilities to place them here. They are even more marvelous to behold from the inside.”

“The Spirit Void Halls?” Han Li repeated its name with an odd look in his eye.

Elder Ren wore a mysterious smile and said, “Do they interest you, Brother Han? Apart from important affairs, the halls will remain sealed. It is only under the approval of half of the sect elders that the Spirit Void Halls are opened. As for the reason, it isn’t something that I can tell!”

Han Li smiled back and asked no further questions. Suspicions of prying into the secrets of another sect could have great consequences.

Additionally, even if the three halls had any relationship to Heavenvoid Hall, it had little to do with him. The most important treasure of Heavenvoid Hall was already in his possession.

“Fellow Daoist Han, please follow me. The Pure Focus Pavilion is over there. As it seems that Junior Martial Sister Bai views you importantly, I’ll bring you to where she receives her close guests. It is rather serene there.”

“Is that so? I am honored.” Han Li smiled.

Elder Ren smiled back and took to the air, bringing Han Li over to one of the mountain walls before landing in front of a pavilion.

The building was three stories tall with each floor being over thirty meters tall. Its body was constructed from emerald wood and was mostly embedded into the mountain. There was a yellow signboard that hung on its entrance with the words “Pure Focus Pavilion” engraved in silver lettering.

As Han Li in front of it, a white-robed woman walked out from the building. When she saw the two, she momentarily paused in surprise and respectfully said, “I pay my respects, Martial Senior Ren. And this must be Senior Han?”

“Correct,” Han Li calmly replied, “Is Fairy Bai inside?”

The beautiful woman stood slightly to the side and faced Han Li, saying, “Master had just emerged from her seclusion and is stabilizing her magic power in the pavilion. She has sent me to welcome you, Senior Han. I hope you don’t take offense!”

Revealing little surprise, the woman wryly smiled and said, “Martial Senior Ren, you’ve put me in a difficult position. You should know that Master has already told me that she does not wish to see you. When Junior Martial Sister Gong allowed you to see her, she was punished severely after the fact.”

Elder Ren blushed, but soon, he shifted his gaze, “But this time is different. I am accompanying Brother Han. Will she refuse to see me along with Brother Han?”

When Han Li heard this, he smirked and said little else.

“This...” A hesitant expression appeared on her face.

“Yan’er, let your Martial Senior Ren in. I will see him!” Bai Yaoyi’s voice sounded from the pavilion.

“As you command!” The woman’s expression relaxed and she withdrew further to the side. “Martial Senior Ren, please come in.”

Elder Ren’s face lit up when he heard Bai Yaoyi’s voice and a trace of happiness lit up on his face. His lips immediately moved, sending a voice transmission to Bai Yaoyi inside.

“Senior Martial Brother Ren Bi, how about you talk after you enter? Why are you speaking while Fellow Daoist Han is still outside? Do you want us to appear rude?”

Han Li stroked his chin and smiled silently.

With embarrassment on his face, he said, “How careless of me. Brother Han, let us talk inside!”

“What? I’ve always seen Brother Ren as a friendly person!” Brother Han replied with a beaming smile. He now realized that the reason why the man made such efforts to befriend Han Li was that he held affections for Bai Yaoyi. This greatly reduced Han Li’s wariness towards him.

With the woman guiding the way, the two entered the Pure Focus Pavilion.

The first floor couldn't be considered to be very large as it was only sixty meters wide. There were a set of simple bamboo table and chairs but there were pots of blooming yellow flowers that surrounded the corners. They were all particularly fragrant.

Bai Yaoyi didn’t immediately descend to meet them, but when the two took a seat, her voice sounded from above, “Brother Han, please wait a moment. My cultivation technique is a bit peculiar. Once I finish circulating it, I’ll head down immediately to see you. Brother Han may as well sample our sect’s Snow Spirit Fruit for the time being.”

Once that was said, Bai Yaoyi’s disciple clapped her hands and two young white-robed women walked in, each holding a vermillion wooden plate with a branch filled with thumb-sized translucent berries.

Once they placed the plates on the table, the two women respectfully withdrew.

“The Ice Spirit Fruit is exclusive to our sect. Even our inner palace elders acquire a few every year. Not only is the fruit delicious, but it also contains pure ice spiritual power. If an ice-attributed cultivator regularly consumed them, it would greatly aid their cultivation.” When Ren Bi saw the fruits, he introduced them to Han Li and casually tossed one of them into his mouth.

When Han Li saw this, he followed suit and tossed one into his mouth. As soon as he bit it, he felt pure glacial Qi roil in his mouth.

Although he didn’t cultivate ice-attributed techniques, he harbored peak glacial flames within his body, such as the Purple Apex Flames and the Great Yin Trueflames. As such, he was able to swallow them without any problem.

With an interested gaze, he took another one and tossed it into his mouth.

When Ren Bi saw this, shock momentarily appeared on his face.

The Ice Spirit Fruits were quite famous, providing even Nascent Soul cultivators benefits in their consumption. However, cultivators who didn’t practice ice- or fire-attributed cultivations arts would suffer internal frostbite if they carelessly consumed one.

Han Li, who emitted pure wood-attributed spiritual power, was able to swallow one and displayed little surprise. Taking two such fruits were something that even a fire-attributed cultivator such as himself didn’t dare to do.

As Ren Bi was inwardly shocked, footsteps sounded from above to reveal a gorgeous white-robed woman walking down the stairs.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and he immediately stood up with a hearty smile, “Fairy Bai, it's been over ten years. I trust you are doing well?”

Ren Bi’s face happily lit up, “Junior Martial Sister Bai, you’ve finally agreed to see me!”

“On the day that we parted, I knew that Brother Han wouldn’t have made an appointment without reason. For the past several years, I’ve been waiting for your arrival in the sect. Your arrival has been expected,” Bai Yaoyi beamed a smile at Han Li, but then she turned to Ren Bi and her face turned cold, “As for you, Senior Martial Brother Ren, I wouldn’t have agreed to see you if it weren’t for Brother Han!”

Ren Bi rushed to speak, “I’ve already found a method to resolve the problem. I definitely won’t leave you disappointed.”

Bai Yaoyi shook her head and said, “In that case, speak of it later. Fellow Daoist Han has come a long way. Leave that matter for later!”

Ren Bi’s expression blanked a moment as if something immediately came to mind. He then smiled, “That’s fine, I’ll find an opportunity to talk about it in more detail in the future. Now, I am already very happy that you’ve agreed to see me.”

Bai Yaoyi nodded with a neutral expression and sat down at the main seat at the table. Han Li and Ren Bi sat back down.

After examining her, Han Li smiled and said, “Fairy Bai, your cultivation has vastly increased since the last time I saw you!”

Bai Yaoyi beamed in response, “Brother Han must be joking. My abilities can’t hope to compare to yours!”

She clearly remembered Han Li’s display of abilities at the Yin Yang Cave and Kunwu Mountain, and therefore treated him with the utmost respect.

When Ren Bi heard Bai Yaoyi’s respect for Han Li, his expression changed and he examined Han Li once more in surprise.

Bai Yaoyi continued, “Brother Han, when you mentioned paying a visit to North Night Palace, you should’ve had some purpose in mind.”

Han Li’s face turned pensive for a moment before answering with a grin, “Since you raised the question, I will be forthright. It is true, I came to North Night Palace because I had a request for you.”

Chapter 1083: Goldwind Racoon

Without any reservation, Bai Yaoyi said, “I’ve yet to forget the many times you’ve helped me. Please don’t hesitate to speak.”

To tell the truth, even if Han Li hadn’t rescued her from the ice that sealed her in the Devil Suppressing Pagoda, he still possessed the fearsome abilities comparable to a late-Nascent Soul cultivator. She was happy to befriend such a character.

Han Li calmly said, “It isn’t anything major. I only heard that North Night Island grew Profound Ice Flowers in abundance. I require them as the main ingredient for a medicine pill.”

“Profound Ice Flowers? Those aren’t very easy to find. Although we don’t have many that are ripe, there are a few that will soon be ready. I’ll have a few of our disciples go look for any Myriad Year Profound Ice. The flower only grows on profound ice that had recently reached that age. There shouldn’t be a problem!”

Han Li grinned, “It is great that you can help me. It would be quite troublesome if I had to handle it alone.”

Bai Yaoyi wore a beaming smile and said, “It is only a minor affair. However, it isn’t something that will finish in a couple of days. Since Brother Han has come to our sect, how about he stay for a few days? I hold your abilities in great admiration. Perhaps we may converse on a few teachings.”

“I am also greatly interested in the techniques of your sect. I have long heard that your palace has several of the most powerful ice-attributed techniques in the Great Jin. Although I don’t personally cultivate ice-attribute techniques, perhaps there are benefits to be had.”

After this brief exchange, a discussion broke out between them.

Because the two were in similar realms of cultivation, they began to talk about their troubles of cultivation. As Ren Bi was also a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator, he also had a few original points to add. As such, time passed in the pavilion in a lively chatter.

After half a day passed, Han Li bid farewells, feeling it inappropriate to bother her further after she only recently emerged from secluded cultivation.

When Bai Yaoyi saw this, she hadn’t urged him to stay. Instead, she commanded her disciple surnamed Yuan to guide Han Li to an esteemed guest building for the time being. He would be notified as soon as the information of Profound Ice Flowers were acquired.

With his request accepted, he saluted the two and followed the disciple out from the building.

Ren Bi didn’t immediately depart. It seemed he had something he wished to further discuss with her.

With the beautiful woman guiding Han Li, he was led to a span of dozen buildings built into the mountain wall, all beautifully constructed. It seemed these were the quarters for esteemed guests.

Knowing that Bai Yaoyi viewed Han Li in high regard, the beautiful woman was extremely respectful towards Han Li and answered all his questions to the best of her knowledge.

In the blink of an eye, the two arrived in front of one of the buildings. Before they entered, a young doll-like woman dressed in maid clothes emerged from the building.

The woman immediately stepped forward and bowed, “I pay my respects to Martial Aunt Yuan!”

Disciple Yuan sternly said, “Martial Niece Hua, this is Senior Han, an esteemed guest of the Martial Ancestor. Serve him well. If you are negligent, there will be punishments.”

“I will do my utmost!” The maid’s heart trembled and she answered with a respectful tone. Meanwhile, she stole a glance at Han Li and hastily turned her head away when their eyes met.

Han Li replied with a smile.

Disciple Yuan turned to Han Li, “Senior Han, if you are dissatisfied with Martial Niece Hua, we’ll replace her immediately.”

“There is no need. She will do.” Han Li shook his head and entered the building in stride.

The other two closely followed after him.

The building’s interior was well arranged and was to Han Li’s satisfaction. There were a few simple restrictions that prevented cultivators from prying inside as well.

With a few brief words, he sent the disciple away and stayed in the residence.

To tell the truth, he was left somewhat tired as he was traveling ever since he left the Snowchain Mountains. He planned on using this time to take a proper rest and bring himself back to peak performance.

Two days passed with Han Li meditating on the second floor. He had yet to emerge.

If he were to roam as he wished, he would certainly attract the attention of many high-grade cultivators of the sect.

After all, he was a foreign Nascent Soul-grade cultivator. It was impossible for them to not be on guard.

He also had no intention of stirring up trouble. Although he wanted more information on the Great Yin Trueflame, he wouldn’t risk taking action until after he finished refining the Profound Ice Pill.

The removal of Nangong Wan’s Soul Seal Curse was at the top of his list of priorities.

As for the maid that was assigned to serve him, he hadn’t spoken to her apart from telling her to wait outside.

On the morning of the third day, his face began to stir as he sat in meditation. Azure light flickered from his body and a series of booms sounded out. He opened his eyes with a sullen expression.

Someone’s spiritual sense had penetrated the building’s restrictions without any restraint and directly moved to probe his body. As such, he forcefully repelled it.

However, this person’s spiritual sense was no weaker than his. It should’ve belonged to a late-Nascent Soul cultivator.

Han Li’s mind quickly stirred, but before he could think of how to respond, he heard a delicate child’s voice in his ear.

“You’re Fellow Daoist Han? I am Master Arctic Dragon. Would you be interested in meeting me?”

“Master Arctic Dragon?” Han Li’s heart trembled. Wasn’t he North Night Palace’s grand elder?

He was an exceedingly mysterious person. Although he was known to be vastly powerful in the north, it was rather odd how no one had seen him take action. It was almost as if he became the grand elder overnight.

Han Li felt a bit odd, but with his current abilities, he had nothing to fear from a late-Nascent Soul cultivator. He hesitated for a moment before resolving himself and promptly replied through his spiritual sense, “Since Fellow Daoist Arctic Dragon invited me, how could I refuse such kindness. I will immediately head over to pay my respects!”

Pleased by Han Li’s response, Master Arctic Dragon happily said, “Hehe, very good! My spirit beasts will soon arrive. Fellow Daoist Han will only have to follow it. My residence will be honored by your presence!”

Soon after, white light flashed and the threads of spiritual sense disappeared.

Han Li didn’t immediately move. He stayed still as a light flickered from his eyes, then slowly moving down the stairs.

The doll-faced maid was sitting on a chair on the first floor, looking at a jade slip in her hand. When she saw Han Li descend, she stood up in a panic.

He simply nodded at her and walked out of the building without paying her any further heed.

The maid was left completely shocked, at a loss of what to do. At her cultivation, she couldn't have known what happened on the upper floor.

When Han Li walked outside, he instantly spotted a cat-like beast perched on top of a tree. It glanced at Han Li with eyes glowing yellow. Its body glowed with shining golden fur as if it were made of pure gold.

He narrowed his eyes and examined the small beast before revealing a trace of surprise.

‘A Goldwind Raccoon! These rare creatures should only be in male-female pairs. And it is said their concealment techniques are miraculous beyond compare,’ Han Li muttered to himself. Then, his expression became blank and he swept his gaze to another tree without discovering anything.

Having made sure of Han Li’s identity, the raccoon yelped and golden light flashed from a nearby tree to reveal another small beast. The raccoon was slightly smaller than the one he saw first.

Han Li’s heart trembled. Even with his vast spiritual sense, he wasn’t able to detect it in the slightest.

The two Goldwind Raccoons exchanged a glance and immediately rushed off behind them.

Without another thought, Han Li brightly glowed and he followed after the two beasts in an azure streak.

As he continued to follow them, an inconceivable event occurred.

One of the Goldwind Racoons blurred and disappeared in front of Han Li.

In his alarm, he hastily swept his spiritual sense nearby but to no avail.

He felt his blood run cold. Unwilling to give up, his eyes flickered blue and swept his gaze past his surroundings. He eventually found it near the raccoon guiding him as a shadow-like figure.

Having finally found the beast, Han Li inwardly sighed with relief. If there was something he truly couldn't detect roaming near him, he would be ill at ease.

The two Goldwind Racoons were only somewhat faster than ordinary flight techniques, Han Li was able to easily trail behind them.

On the way, he encountered many inner palace cultivators. They were somewhat shocked upon seeing Han Li’s unfamiliar expression, but when they saw the Goldwind Raccoon flying in front of him, they seemed to realize something and left the matter alone.

Of course, the wouldn’t dare to block Han Li in the first place given his Nascent Soul cultivation.

Following the beasts, he flew swerved across several buildings before arriving at a stone gate in front of the mountain.

The stone gate was about twenty meters tall and shined with a faint yellow light. Talisman characters shined from its surface as if under the effects of a grand restriction.

Han Li came to a stop and looked at it with narrow eyes.

Chapter 1087: Ice Fiend

“This is the lair of the Ice Rage Beasts?” Han Li glanced down at an unfathomably deep ravine in the ice and frowned. Biting glacial winds blew out from it without end.

Bai Yaoyi floated at Han Li’s side and looked around them. Then she confidently said, “That’s right, this is the place!”

“In that case, let’s have them come out!” Han Li nodded and formed a spell seal. His entire body flickered with light and specks of starlight emerged in front of him. Then with a crackle, they burst into scarlet fist-sized fireballs.

“Go!”

With a sweep of his sleeve, a wall of flame enveloped the fireballs and launched them into the ravine, soon disappearing from sight.

Han Li and Bai Yaoyi proceeded to stare down with complete focus.

A long while later, silence still filled the ravine. The sounds resulting from the fireballs’ eruption never occurred.

Han Li and Bai Yaoyi looked at each other with an odd expression.

Han Li stroked his chin and said, “They are only grade-six demon beasts. They shouldn’t be able to silently destroy the fireballs. It seems there is a more formidable beast down there.”

Bai Yaoyi wore a solemn expression, “It is possible! The disciple hadn’t tread deep into the ravine. They only saw the Profound Ice Flower from a distance before being discovered by the Ice Rage Beasts.”

“Hehe, that’s fine. I’ll just use my spirit beasts to draw them out,” Han Li said with an indifferent tone. He slapped his storage pouch and summoned a dozen white streaks that circled once around him. They were foot-long Six-winged Frost Centipedes, each possessing translucent wings and a fiendish appearance.

Han Li let out a low cry and pointed at the Six-winged Frost Centipedes in the air. The centipedes buzzed with joy and wrapped themselves in glacial light as they dived down.

Bai Yaoyi betrayed surprise, but she said nothing.

Han Li had no concern for the Six-winged Frost Centipedes. Even a grade-eight demon beast wouldn’t be able to escape them if they launched a joint attack.

And not long after, the sounds of battle echoed from the ravine, drawing closer, turning louder before the battle was dragged outside.

Han Li pursed his lips and silently waved his sleeve, releasing a dozen golden streaks from his sleeve. They turned into a dozen foot-long golden swords, floating still above the ice reveal as they sparkled with light.

Bai Yaoyi smiled, believing Han Li would be able to deal with the demon beasts with ease.

A short moment later, a series of monstrous roars sounded from below. Afterwards, a series of white mist blew out from them, containing eight snow-white lion-like beasts. They appeared extremely frightened as if they were fleeing for their lives.

They were the so-called Snow Rage Beasts.

He launched a sword seal without any hesitation, causing several of his swords to tremble and launch themselves forward, turning into dazzling three-meter-long streaks.

Like a flash of lightning, they slashed across the white mist and arrived before the beasts.

Before they could even respond, the swordstreaks coiled around them.

With several miserable screams, the beasts were cleaved into two and their corpses sank back into the pit.

Soonafter , a world-shaking roar rumbled from the ground, followed by a huge explosion. A dense wind shot out from the ravine’s depths.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and saw an enraged ten-meter-tall demon beast.

It appeared mostly the same as the Ice Rage Beasts, but its fur glistened with silver light and its body was an entire size larger.

“Yi! That isn’t a Snow Rage Beast. That’s an Ice Fiend!” Bai Yaoyi yelped in shock. “What is such a high-grade demon beast doing here?”

Han Li blinked and took no further action. A dozen white streaks then flew out from the ravine and spat icy Qi at the silver-furred beast.

Although the demon beast was only a grade-seven demon beast, it had no fear of the Six-winged Frost Centipedes’s attack. Rather, the attack only served to incite it further.

Han Li raised his brow and coldly snorted. He extended his finger and azure light flickered from its tip, commanding the flying swords above him to strike at the beast.

At the side, Bai Yaoyi suddenly said, “Please wait a moment! The Ice Fiend is a rare ice and wind attributed demon beast. It will be useful if I can capture it.”

Han Li gave her an easy smile. “In that case, I’ll handle it and save you the trouble!”

With that said, he spat out a ball of purple flames. Then, the flames let out a chirp, shaped into a lifelike foot-wide bird before fluttering towards the Ice Fiend.

When the dozen Six-winged Frost Centipedes saw the bird approach, they immediately scattered in fear, leaving the Ice Fiend alone in the vicinity.

Although the Ice Fiend still hadn’t gained higher awareness, it still possessed a trace of intelligence. Under these circumstances, it could tell the purple flame bird was fearsome and immediately swept up gale-force winds, which formed a hurricane to aid its escape.

Han Li let out a cold snort and a light glinted from his eye.

The beast immediately felt needles assailing its mind and it let out a howl as it fell from the air.

Han Li had launched at attack with his spiritual sense, using the Soulfright Thorn.

Although Han Li hadn’t used the full strength of this attack, his spiritual sense was still equivalent in strength to a late-Nascent Soul cultivator. It wasn’t an attack that the beast could withstand.

With the opportunity given, the purple flame bird arrived in front of the beast and circled it.

As a large crackle sounded, a large ball of purple mist of light surrounded the Ice Fiend and enveloped the beast's body.

The purple flame bird then immediately unfolded its wings and disappeared back into Han Li’s body.

After the purple mist of light disappeared, a thirty-meter-tall black of purple ice was revealed, sealing the Ice Fiend within it. The violent winds surrounding the beast had slowly subsided, and the block of ice crashed to the ground shortly thereafter.

To the side, Bai Yaoyi came to her senses after being stunned by the entire affair. She summoned a large hand of white Qi to lift the ice to her.

“Many thanks, Brother Han! I’ll take you up on your offer!” Bai Yaoyi sweetly smiled at Han Li and she flicked her ringer, producing a sparkling black spirit beast pouch.

She tossed the bag into the air and a mist flew out from it, wrapping around the huge block of ice and drawing into the pouch.

Seeing Bai Yaoyi’s satisfied expression, Han Li smiled and pointed to the Six-winged Frost Centipedes circling in the air. With a series of hisses, the centipedes let out balls of icy mist and instantly disappeared.

Bai Yaoyi was startled by the sight of this, but Han Li soon explained, “While I use the Profound Ice Flower to refine medicine, I don’t want any low-grade demon beasts to disturb us. The centipedes will be protecting us nearby."

Bai Yaoyi sweetly smiled and nodded.

The two soon flew down the huge ravine in streaks of light.

The ravine was pitch-black. Apart from icy winds continuously circling the two, it was reminiscent of the two entering the Yin Yang Cave over ten years ago.

But when they quickly arrived at the bottom, the crystalline walls of the ravine could be seen. They were formed from profound ice, suitable materials for ice-attributed magic tools. However, only myriad year profound ice could be considered a rare, top-grade tool refinement material.

Ordinary profound ice was beneath the notice of the two Nascent Soul cultivators.

But when the two arrived at the very end of the ravine, they spotted a crystal vein that emitted a white light. Although it was jagged, there was a point on it that was clearly myriad year Profound Ice.

Han Li’s eyes then focused on the three white flowers on the wall.

These small flowers were only the size of a fist and appeared to be common wildflowers. But their roots were dug into the myriad year profound ice and faint icy Qi continuously roamed around it.

“Three Profound Ice Flowers. This should be enough,” Han Li muttered.

“There is quite a bit of myriad year profound ice here. It appears that disciple made quite an accomplishment. I’ll have to make sure he is rewarded.” Bai Yaoyi examined the profound ice and wore a smile.

Han Li then turned to Bai Yaoyi and said, “I will be plucking the flowers immediately for pill concoction. I’ve already prepared the other materials. Will Fairy Bai be returning first?”

With some thought, she said with a warm tone, “How long will Brother Han need to refine the pills. Would it be better for me to take a look at our surroundings? We aren’t far from North Night Valley. With the appearance of the grade-seven Ice Fiend, I feel somewhat ill at ease. I’ll be taking this opportunity to look around.”

After a short pause, Han Li gave a word of warning, “That would be good. Be careful!”

“Don’t worry, I’m only doing this in case of contingencies. The grade seven Ice Fiend most likely came into the ravine unintentionally. This hadn’t happened before. I’ll be taking off!” Bai Yaoyi pursed her lips into a bewitching smile and streaked into the air.

Chapter 1090: Cultivators of Ice Flames

Contrary to Han Li’s expectations, there were hardly any changes in North Night Palace apart from a few extra guards. In addition, he spotted no trace of Bai Yaoyi. It seemed she was occupied, but it wasn’t any concern for Han Li.

In his current state, there was hardly anything that could pose a danger to his life apart from a few extremely dangerous areas or the full-powered pursuit of a Deity Transformation-stage cultivator. As a result, he decided to stay in the sect for the time being, despite having a policy of avoiding trouble where he could.

Of course, he had also agreed to assist Master Arctic Dragon in breaking his bottleneck to Deity Transformation-stage and most importantly was the secret technique to break through bottlenecks that Arctic Dragon gave him. He only had his portion of the technique. If he wanted a complete understanding of the technique, he would have to personally involve himself in the process. When Han Li discovered this, he felt a bit gloomy.

Additionally, he wasn’t willing to leave until he acquired information on the Puresun Flame Essence. [1]

As such, he made another trip to the Hidden Scriptures Hall and used up his two remaining days to find any information on the Puresun Flame Essence, but he ended up without any results.

Han Li wasn’t surprised by this. Rather, it would've been surprising if he found it easily.

Following that, Han Li spent his time in his temporary residence meditating, taking not a step outside as if the building were his own cave residence.

A month passed in the blink of an eye in complete peace, but it was clear to see that this was the calm before the oncoming storm.

One day, Han Li found his cultivation interrupted by a visitor, a woman who had a similar appearance to Bai Yaoyi. She was at the peak of mid-Nascent Soul stage, a step higher than Bai Yaoyi.

“Are you Fairy Bai’s elder cousin?” With hands held behind his back, he examined the woman with a trace of surprise.

“That’s right, I am Bai Mengxin, one of the inner palace elder, and one of the sect cultivators who nurtures a flame of extreme cold.”

“Ah, I’ve heard from Fellow Daoist Arctic Dragon that there were two others who cultivate ice flames in the sect. So you were one of them! May I ask why you’ve informed me of this?” As Han Li spoke, a twinkled lit from his eyes.

Although the woman appeared beautiful, her flawless face appeared frigid. It seemed to have something to do with her cultivation art.

“Nothing much. I’ve only heard that Brother Han’s abilities are quite amazing, rivaling even late-stage grand cultivators. Furthermore, your purple apex flames are exceedingly profound. I wish to compare them with my own Ice Phoenix Flames. How about it?” The woman then extended her finger and lip up a white flame from it.

The flame was like a wisp of smoke. It spiralled in the air and didn’t appear to contain much strength.

But as one who cultivated an icy flame himself, Han Li had a deep sense of foreboding towards the white flame and his face grew heavy.

Han Li glanced at his surroundings and smiled. “Very well! I’ve long heard of your palace’s three great ice flames. Let’s test it, but how do you intend on comparing them?”

“I only intend on comparing the power of the flames. I don’t wish to truly fight you.” Bai Mengxin wryly smiled and exhaled a breath of icy Qi towards her fingertip.

The white flames increased several times in size upon contact and coiled in the air, turning into a small white flood dragon before charging towards Han Li.

Han Li frowned and swept his sleeves around him, producing several differing spell formations that disappeared into his surroundings.

He then opened his mouth and spat out a small ball of purple flames, turning into a small purple bird and met the incoming flame dragon.

Han Li and Bai Mengxin attentively watched as white and purple flames collided. Deep thunder rang as the flames weaved together.

In the blink of an eye, the purple flames engulfed the white flames and soon extinguished it entirely. The remaining light belonged to the purple firebird that circled in the air.

Bai Mengxin’s expression stirred upon seeing this.

Han Li calmly waved his hand, having the purple bird return to him in the form of a fireball, then disappearing into his sleeve.

Without further hesitation, Bai Mengxin said, “Your Purple Apex Flames are quite extraordinary. I am relieved. Please follow me. The two external holders of the icy flames have arrived at our palace. I’ll lead you to the Grand Elder’s residence where they are both waiting!”

“So it was like that! It seems Fairy Bai wasn’t too sure of me and had me take her test.” Han Li gave her a doubtful smile.

Bai Mengxin silently nodded and soon held her hands in an incantation gesture before flying out of the building window in a white streak.

When Han Li saw this, he stroked his nose with a helpless appearance.

His heart had jumped when the woman entered through the window as well.

But since she already left, Han Li could only follow after her and flew out from the building window.

After the time it took to finish a meal, the two arrived in Master Arctic Dragon’s main hall.

In addition to the huge cauldron burning with Celestial Ice Flames at the center of the hall, four cultivators were sitting on woven mats nearby.

Arctic Dragon was sitting next to an azure-robed middle-aged man. An old white-haired woman and a grey-robed monk were sitting farther away from them.

When Han Li and Bai Mengxin entered the hall, the four immediately turned their gaze towards them. Han Li sensed the old lady and monk swept their gaze past Bai Mengxin and focus on him.

In that case, Han Li didn’t hold back and used his spiritual sense to observe the other two as well.

The old woman possessed about the same level of cultivation as Han Li, but the monk was higher at the peak of mid-Nascent Soul stage.

Han Li slowly took a few steps forward and saluted the four, quietly taking a seat at an empty mat that was a close distance away from the four.

Bai Mengxin took a seat at the side of Arctic Dragon.

“Madam Long, Master Mo Jiu, this is Fellow Daoist Han,” Arctic Dragon said with a friendly face, “He is the fifth cultivator who cultivates a flame of extreme cold. With your assistance, I can put my hundred years of research into practice and attempt to break through the bottleneck to Deity Transformation-stage!” The excitement in his eyes was clear to see.

The old woman expressionlessly glanced at Han Li and remained silent, perhaps a result of her strange temperament. The monk on the other hand looked at Han Li with a kind gaze and gave him a warm smile.

The monk calmly asked, “I heard Fellow Daoist Arctic Dragon mention that Brother Han didn’t cultivate an ice-attributed cultivation technique, but you are still able to use flames of extreme cold. Is that true?”

“It is something that I managed to accomplish through luck,” Han Li replied.

“I also heard that the flames are your original creation. It has been tens of thousands of years since the appearance of a new ice flame. Do you think you could let me see it?” The old woman aloofly asked. Han Li couldn't help but be startled by her young voice.

Arctic Dragon then added, “Don’t be alarmed, Madam Long is the Grand Elder of the Green Willow Sect. Her cultivation art is rather peculiar, causing her voice to be youthful.”

A peculiar feeling lingered in Han Li’s mind upon hearing his explanation. He had seen many instances where women used techniques to preserve their appearance, but this was the first time he had heard of a technique to preserve the youth of one’s voice.

When she saw Han Li looked at her with an odd gaze, the old woman snorted, “What? Do you have any comments towards the techniques of my sect?”

At Han Li’s current cultivation, he didn’t have anything to fear from a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator, but he also didn’t wish to make any unnecessary enemies. As such, he chuckled and tactfully replied, “Not at all! I was only curious for a time. My flames had yet to be refined. How could I dare to compare them to yours?”

The old woman didn’t pursue the matter and her eyes silently wandered.

Then, Bai Mengxin sent a voice transmission to Arctic Dragon.

Arctic Dragon broke into a smile upon hearing her and took a deep glance at Han Li. Then, he lightly coughed and said, “Madam Long and Master Mojiu have been good friends of mine for many years. Fellow Daoist Han also has a deep relationship with one of the elders of my sect. As such, I’ve brought the three of you here to assist me. Although I reckon that this will only have a thirty percent chance of success, I have no choice but to take the risk.”

The monk said with a concerned tone, “Fellow Daoist Shi, you may be reaching the end of your lifespan, but we’ve discovered many high-grade demon beasts on our way here and they’ve started to gather near North Night Island. Isn’t it too dangerous to test your technique now?”

Arctic Dragon confidently said, “Fellow Daoist Mojiu, don’t worry. It would be best for me to successfully breakthrough my bottleneck. Then I would have no fear of those demons. If that fails, the palace already arranged countermeasures. If I die, my sect will not follow me.”

“In that case, I am relieved,” the grey-robed monk smiled.

The old woman nodded, “I have no objections. I’ve been wanting to see the true mystery behind this technique.”

Master Arctic Dragon appeared satisfied by their replies. Then when his gaze turned to Han Li, Han Li calmly asked, “When will we start? I also have no objections. The sooner we start. The better!”

“Good, good! Since the three of you have no objections, please follow me. I’ve already made preparations.” Arctic Dragon clapped his hands together and happily stood up.

[1]. Mentioned in Chapter 948: Returning Sun Water and Puresun Flame Essence, an ingredient in creating a legendary medicine by the name of the Returning Sun Water.

[Back]

Chapter 1093: The Profound Jade Cave

As Arctic Dragon stared at the crack in the altar, he wore a grave expression, “Within lies the greatest hidden chamber of the Spirit Void Hall, the Profound Jade Cave. Although it isn’t very large, the cave’s Profound Jade was something that has existed since ancient times. The ancient cultivators used enormous amounts of magic power to shape a vein of Profound Jade into that cave. Although Profound Jade and Profound Ice sound similar, there are clear differences as you all should well know. And if you leave this hall, you’ll find hardly any Myriad Year Profound Jade even if you searched the entire hall.”

The azure-robed middle-aged man, Elder Ouyang, and Bai Mengxin glanced with a trace of interest.

The grey-robed monk stared at the cracks in the altar and excitedly said, “Of course! Had you not mentioned the Profound Jade Cave Before, we could’ve hardly believed that your sect was concealing something so valuable. Myriad Year Profound Jade is rarely ever found in this. A fist-sized chunk is it is all that is needed for a magic treasure to possess ice-attributed abilities, allowing it to use astonishing glacial Qi to form attacks. It is beyond comparison to profound ice.”

The old woman glanced at the altar with a bright gaze.

As for Han Li, he silently smiled, stroking the smooth surface of a small golden sword he kept hidden in his sleeve.

Arctic Dragon then changed his focus to Han Li and the other two external cultivators and said, “I’ve already spoken about this before with Junior Martial Brother Ouyang and Junior Martial Sister Bai, but you will be rewarded with a piece of Myriad Year Profound Jade as a token of your gratitude, regardless of whether or not we succeed.”

“Truly?” Even the bold and detached woman was unable to conceal her joy upon hearing him.

Arctic Dragon nodded, “It is something within my authority as the Grand Elder of the North Night PAlace.”

Joy appeared on the face of the monk as well.

Myriad Year Profound Jade was an extremely rare material that was found at no market and had no price. If one could find it, they would ordinarily infuse it with their magic power, immediately increasing its power by an entire fifth.

Even Han Li couldn't help but be moved by his generosity.

With such a heavy reward, the three would find it shameful if they didn’t do their utmost when the time came.

“Enough with that, let’s enter the Profound Jade Cave!” Arctic Dragon continued, “The glacial Qi within is extremely potent. Have your flames ready when you enter or you will be hard-pressed to defend yourselves. Fortunately, the cave has an area that can block the corrosion of the Profound Jade’s glacial Qi. We’ll be using that place to restore our magic power, else we won’t be able to stay inside for long.”

Soon after, the dwarf opened his mouth and spat out a bright blue fireball. It turned into a large firebird above his head, only to circle him once before diving at the dwarf’s body.

A bird’s cry sounded before the image of the large bird disappear. A layer of blue flames then erupted and enveloped him.

With his hands grasped in an incantation gesture, he began to float down into the crack.

Bai Mengxin and the others released their own glacial flames and flew into the crack as well.

Han Li glanced at the two golden gates the side, and to the cauldron floating above the crack. After some hesitation, something came to mind and he silently smiled, wrapping himself in a layer of Purple Apex Flames and following them below.

As soon as he entered, white glacial light brushed past him, producing an odd crackle as it brushed past the purple flames protecting him. They seemed to be at odds with one another, causing the flames to flicker.

Han Li trembled. Without any further thought, he clapped his hands together, summoning even more flames to protect him and solidify his defenses.

Now, he had the leisure to examine his surroundings.

The Profound Jade Cave was an underground cavern.

As the cave was created from a vein of Myriad Year Profound Jade, countless pieces of variously sized grains laid in the wall all around them. The extremely rare material was several times more potent than profound ice, well displayed by the glacial light that dropped down from it, condensing into a mist at the bottom. When Han Li dropped down, the light struck at his purple flames like the patter of dense rain.

In his alarm, he faintly felt that something was amiss. Seeing that the rest of the party wasn’t paying attention to him, he reached out to the glacial light out of instant and forcibly used his magic power to grasp a sliver of it into his hand and concentrating his purple flames around it.

Any ordinary glacial Qi wouldn’t have shown any peculiarities, but when Han Li looked at it with his Brightsight Spirit Eyes, he frowned, soon to betray astonishment on his face.

Under the Brightsight Spirit Eyes, Han Li was able to see traces of its true form. As the purple flames continuously warped around the glacial light, their mutually powerful cold seemed to oppose one another.

“What is this? This glacial Qi seems almost intelligent...” Han Li muttered with amazement.

The glacial Qi was attacking only of its own accord. If anyone were to control a large amount and concentrate it into an attack, he feared even his Purple Apex Flames wouldn’t be able to block it.

As the thoughts quickly churned in his head, he was suddenly reminded of something and quickly formed an incantation gesture, summoning a scarlet wisp from the purple flames in his hand.

When this flame wisp made contact with the white glacial light, it was instantly absorbed.

An odd expression appeared on his face while delight surged through his mind.

The Great Yin Trueflame was known to Silvermoon as one of the three true spirit flames. It was well deserving of its name. Despite being only a single wisp, its power far exceeded that of the Purple Apex Flames.

When he initially refined the wisp of Great Yin Trueflame, he was only able to temporarily merge it with a bit of his Purple Apex Flames. If he truly wished to fully convert the Purple Apex Flames into the Great Yin Trueflame, it would take far beyond the time of a dozen years. Were this not the case, he would’ve already done so.

After all, the Great Yin Trueflame already possessed a trace of intelligence. It was a higher existence compared to other kinds of glacial flames.

When Han Li saw that the thread of trueflame was able to restrain the cave’s glacial light, Han Li also felt a bit of relief.

Just as these thoughts appeared in his mind, he suddenly held his hands behind his back and flicked his finger, vanishing the scarlet flame from sight.

In the instant, Han Li was performing his experiment, Elder Ouyang seemed to sense something and looked upward at Han Li with a trace of surprise.

Han Li’s heart sank, but his expression remained calm. He nonchalantly asked, “Fellow Daoist, is there anything wrong?”

The Elder Ouyang examined Han Li and the cave walls to either side of him, discovering nothing out of the ordinary. He knew well that Han Li’s abilities were exceptional and thus gave a prompt and polite answer, “Its nothing. I was just wondering why you weren’t following us. The large restrictions to spiritual sense inside Spirit Void Hall make me rather uncomfortable.”

Han Li looked down to see the glacial light brushing past his flames and replied, “Hehe, The glacial Qi in this cave is rather odd!”

“Yes, the glacial Qi is by no means ordinary. The cave is something that has existed since ancient times. After existing for such a long time, the glacial Qi may have undergone a subtle change.” Elder Ouyang’s black flames were also under attack by the glacial Qi and heard the same sounds of rain as Han Li.

Han Li smiled and through to say something when he suddenly let out a yelp.

Elder Ouyang suddenly looked below and saw that the rest of the party already entered the depths of the cave. There was a hill of scattered rocks that spanned a kilometer wide. The glacial light lingering there was several times more concentrated than at the top.

At the edge of the hill was a fire-red stone room with several entrances opened around it, appearing to almost be a cave formation.

At the peak of the stone hill, there was a giant boulder with condensed glacial Qi surrounding it. It was ten meters wide and its surface roiled with icy gusts and sparkling light.

As he closely examined it, he discovered that the huge boulder’s surface had a thumb-sized piece of Profound Jade. It sparkled with light, clearly displaying that it was many times purer than the shards he found at the cave’s entrance.

Suppressing his astonishment, Han Li followed the others and landed on the ground. Arctic Dragon’s gaze was captured by the boulder as soon as he saw it and joy appeared on his face.

“Haha, that’s great! I originally worried about how I would gather the glacial Qi in the cave. I didn’t expect that there would be a natural point where it concentrated. This will save us much effort!”

Arctic Dragon bellowed and soon after, he raised his hand, producing a blue ice spike in his hand, striking the ball of white light.

Clang! A metallic ring sounded upon impact, followed by the ice spike shattering to dust.

“Not bad, not bad!” Arctic Dragon only seemed to grow happier.

“Ah yes, did you all see that stone room over there? It is formed from Puresun Essence Stone. It is the only area that is absent of glacial Qi. We can rest there first as I explain what actions are forbidden in the cave. Otherwise, you will attract deep trouble for yourself!”

When the old woman heard him, she tapped her cane on the ground and asked, “Deep trouble? What does Fellow Daoist Arctic Dragon mean?”